<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - activitypub</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/activitypub</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'activitypub' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-06-14 10:47 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>MLS over ActivityPub Draft</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://messaginglayersecurity.rocks/"&gt;Messaging Layer Security (MLS)&lt;/a&gt; is an IETF standard for end-to-end encrypted (E2EE) messaging. It lets people on laptops and phones communicate with each other in a secure way that no one in between can see.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
MLS is designed to use pluggable lower-level protocols. This specification defines an envelope format for distributing MLS messages through the network, and an Activity Streams 2.0 profile for the packets of application data stored inside the messages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This specification is ready for review from both ActivityPub developers and security analysts. It’s time to start making proof-of-concept implementations and testing interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: https://socialwebfoundation.org/2025/06/13/mls-over-activitypub-draft/&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mls-over-activitypub-draft</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mls-over-activitypub-draft</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-14 10:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>protocol</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>w3c</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gen Z Leading Tumblr Revival</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Gen Z, the site has found new life. As of 2025, Gen Z makes up 50% of Tumblr’s active monthly users and accounts for 60% of new sign-ups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't call it a comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User numbers spiked in January during the near-ban of TikTok and jumped again last year when Brazil temporarily banned X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep up with the momentum, Tumblr introduced Reddit-style Communities in December, letting users connect over shared interests like photography and video games. In January, it debuted Tumblr TV—a TikTok-like feature that serves as both a GIF search engine and a short-form video platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps Tumblr’s greatest strength is that it isn’t TikTok or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its users...that’s part of the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr's been through a rough ride, but at the core there's a lot of nice things to like about it. In previous posts, I talked about some opportunities for Tumblr as a result of &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr/"&gt;replatforming on top of WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and its expressed intent for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-still-working-fediverse-integration/"&gt;ActivityPub integration&lt;/a&gt;. In doing so, not only would it enable an intuitive front-end for publishing different kinds of posts, but it would also provide opportunities for self-hosting and a more federated and decentralized social platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to see where this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/gen-z-flocking-tumblr-millennials-musk-zuckerberg-safe-space-2025-4"&gt;Related post from Business Insider's Amanda Hoover&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/gen-z-tumblr-revival</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/gen-z-tumblr-revival</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-04-08 06:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>genz</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Static Sites to the Fediverse - Enhancements and Implementations</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Awesome post from my friend &lt;a href="https://maho.dev/"&gt;maho.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve introduced customizable templates for note generation. This enhancement allows the full content of a blog post to be included directly in ActivityPub notes, moving beyond mere link sharing—a practice often associated with bots—and leveraging the full potential of the Fediverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is cool. I'd like something better for my POSSE setup. Might give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bringing-static-sites-fediverse-enhancements-implementations-maho</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bringing-static-sites-fediverse-enhancements-implementations-maho</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-03-18 21:08 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Implementing ActivityPub in a Static Site (or Any Website) - Part 8</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Part 8 of &lt;a href="https://www.maho.dev/2024/02/a-guide-to-implement-activitypub-in-a-static-site-or-any-website/"&gt;&amp;quot;A guide to implement ActivityPub in a static site (or any website)&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.maho.dev/"&gt;maho.dev&lt;/a&gt; recently dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part goes over how to add replies and comments to your static site.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/guide-implementing-activitypub-static-site-pt-8</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/guide-implementing-activitypub-static-site-pt-8</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-02 18:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Agentic Fediverse&amp;quot; is the idea of a new kind of network federation, a complementary iteration on the concept of federation currently established with ActivityPub. It's an experiment and something that we in Muni Town are still trying to define more concretely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tenets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still working on defining the core tenets of the agentic fediverse, but here is what we have so far.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An agentic fediverse is...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fediverse of agents; agent-centric, as opposed to server-centric.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local-first; solve local problems for local people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessible by default; inaccessibility is a bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematically consensual; architected on the basis of informed consent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/agentic-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/agentic-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>munitown</category>
      <category>agents</category>
      <category>agentic</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Social Web - Hello, Social Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're A New Social, a new non-profit organization focused on building cross-protocol tools and services for the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our mission is to liberate people's networks from their platforms, enabling &lt;a href="https://www.augment.ink/bridges-the-last-network-effect/?ref=anew.social"&gt;The Last Network Effect&lt;/a&gt; and leveling the playing field across the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The first project we'll take on to accomplish this mission is &lt;a href="https://fed.brid.gy/?ref=anew.social"&gt;Bridgy Fed&lt;/a&gt;, a service that enables users of ActivityPub-based platforms like Mastodon, ATProto-based platforms like Bluesky, and websites to interact and engage across ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:39 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>anewsocial</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>atproto</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr adds Reddit-like ‘communities’</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr is introducing a new Community feature — in-app groups organized by topic or interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communities are similar to subreddits or Facebook groups and had previously been in beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given recent announcements like &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr/"&gt;Tumblr replatforming on top of WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin/"&gt;WordPress adding support for ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt;, I could see communities becoming not only an alternative to Reddit, but also Lemmy in the Fediverse.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-adding-reddit-like-communities</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-adding-reddit-like-communities</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-16 22:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>reddit</category>
      <category>communities</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>lemmy</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghost is federating over ActivityPub</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2024, Ghost is adopting ActivityPub and connecting with other federated platforms across the web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This means that, soon, Ghost publishers will be able to follow, like and interact with one another in the same way that you would normally do on a social network — but on your own website.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The difference, of course, is that you’ll also be able to follow, like, and interact with users on Mastodon, Threads, Flipboard, Buttondown, WriteFreely, Tumblr, WordPress, PeerTube, Pixelfed... or any other platform that has adopted ActivityPub, too. You don’t need to limit yourself to following people who happen to use the same platform as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few years the choice has been difficult. Either participate in closed networks at the mercy of algorithms, or set up an independent website at the expense of your growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email gave us private messaging technology that isn’t owned by a single company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ActivityPub is doing the same for social technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open web is coming back, and with it returns diversity. You can both publish independently and grow faster than ever before with followers from all over the world &amp;amp; the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't express how much I love this. Personally I don't use Ghost, but given platforms like WordPress and now Ghost are adding support for ActivityPub, it empowers people to build their own platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, this still doesn't address the challenges of building your own website, which as mentioned in the post are one of the appealing aspects of current closed networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still though, there is a vast number of creators, businesses, and company websites or blogs that can benefit from this today. When paired with RSS, it gives people choice and autonomy in how they create and consume content as I mentioned in a previous post, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom"&gt;Rediscovering the RSS protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ghost-activitypub-integration-announcement</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ghost-activitypub-integration-announcement</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 22:11 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ghost</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMentions</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenMentions is a project designed to use Webmentions and ActivityPub for topical content discovery. The site is organised along the lines of a hierarchy of topics going from broad to fine. This we call OpenTopic – the idea being that many sites could host the full collection of topics so that the loss of any one site is not the loss of all topics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The intention is that this site should own nothing and that topic hierarchies are organic and discoverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openmentions</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openmentions</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-16 20:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>webmentions</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>online</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goblin - Tumblr meets the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goblin band is an attempt to replicate the colletive creative energy that happens on tumblr and take it to the fediverse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repo&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/johnHackworth/goblin"&gt;https://github.com/johnHackworth/goblin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/goblin-tumblr-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/goblin-tumblr-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 16:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>firefish</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>federation</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 in social media: the case for the fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Good article from David Pierce. I'd add that many of these platforms (i.e. Mastodon, Lemmy, PeerTube, WordPress) have strong RSS support which offer another degree of freedom from opting out of signing up for any of the platforms but still being able to follow the people and topics you care about. Sure, the experience may not be as rich but it's yet another way for people to participate in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new kind of social internet is currently forming. Right now it might still look like “Twitter and Reddit, only different,” but that’s only the very beginning of what’s to come. Hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced we’ll be better off with a hundred different apps for Snapchat or Instagram or X instead of just one...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t make sense that we have a dozen usernames, a dozen profiles, a dozen sets of fans and friends. All that stuff should belong to me, and I should be able to access it and interact with it anywhere and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralizing social media can sound like a sort of kumbaya anti-capitalist manifesto: “It’s about openness and sharing, not capitalism, man!” In practice it’s the opposite: it’s a truly free market approach to social networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...in a fediverse-dominated world, the way to win is not to achieve excellent lock-in and network effects. The only way to win is to build the best product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...so far we’re mostly in the “popular app, but federated” phase of this transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everything in the fediverse is a one-to-one competitor to an existing platform...Some of these apps are very good! But nearly all of them are differentiated only in that they’re federated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s be super clear about this: the point of the fediverse is not that it’s federated...Making the “It’s federated!” argument is like making the “It’s better for privacy!” argument: it makes you feel good, and at best it’s a useful tiebreaker, but it doesn’t actually matter. All that matters is the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023 was the year “fediverse” became a buzzword, 2024 will be the year it becomes an industry. (Hopefully one with a better name, but I’ll get over that.) We’ve spent too long living our lives online in someone else’s spaces. What’s next will belong to all of us. All that’s left to do is start posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/2023-social-media-case-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/2023-social-media-case-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-19 09:26 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing ActivityPub adoption</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Exciting developments in the ActivityPub space. A few months ago, the &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin/"&gt;WordPress plugin&lt;/a&gt; was released. In the last few days, Threads recently started testing their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/13/24000120/threads-meta-activitypub-test-mastodon"&gt;ActivityPub integration&lt;/a&gt;. Not so new but new to me, I saw that &lt;a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/activitypub-plugin/266794"&gt;Discourse, the forum software, also has an ActivityPub plugin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/18/24006062/flipboard-fediverse-mastodon-activitypub-profiles-social"&gt;Flipboard&lt;/a&gt; is one of the latest names to express plans for ActivityPub integration. Not sure what the end result will look like when all these platforms are all interoping with each other but I'm excited to see platforms building on open protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/growing-activitypub-adoption-december-2023</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/growing-activitypub-adoption-december-2023</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-18 20:28 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engage a Wider Audience With ActivityPub on WordPress.com</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exciting times are here for all WordPress.com users! The revolutionary ActivityPub feature is now available across all WordPress.com plans, unlocking a world of engagement and interaction for your blog. Your blogs can now be part of the rapidly expanding fediverse, which enables you to connect with a broader audience and attract more followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't believe I missed these news but so exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/activitypub-plugin-available-hosted-wordpress</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/activitypub-plugin-available-hosted-wordpress</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-14 20:57 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress ActivityPub Plugin</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I can't believe I missed this announcement. This is great to see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the fediverse with ActivityPub, broadcasting your blog to a wider audience! Attract followers, deliver updates, and receive comments from a diverse user base of ActivityPub-compliant platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the ActivityPub plugin installed, your WordPress blog itself function as a federated profile, along with profiles for each author. For instance, if your website is example.com, then the blog-wide profile can be found at @example.com@example.com, and authors like Jane and Bob would have their individual profiles at @jane@example.com and @bobz@example.com, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-17 12:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>