<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - bureaulandmanagement</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/bureaulandmanagement</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'bureaulandmanagement' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-08-10 21:13 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>BLM Lands Marked for Potential Sale (OnX)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Sad to see what's happening with our public lands. Great to see folks staying vigilant and providing information of what's happening on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blm-lands-marked-for-potential-sale-onx</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blm-lands-marked-for-potential-sale-onx</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-10 21:13 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>onx</category>
      <category>bureaulandmanagement</category>
      <category>nature</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do not privatize federal land</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve long advocated selling off some federal land...Most of this “public land” is never used by the public. Selling some of it would actually make it more accessible and useful to real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about no. If privatization means, John and Jane Doe can purchase some land for their homestead is one thing. We've tried that before by the way - &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homestead_Acts"&gt;Homestead Act&lt;/a&gt;. In reality, it means some private equity firm or hedge fund buying the land, building expensive and shoddy cookit-cutter condos, and &lt;a href="https://www.nar.realtor/magazine/real-estate-news/commercial/build-to-rent-homes"&gt;selling you a subscription for a roof over your head&lt;/a&gt;. I say condos because it's hot and there's not a lot of water in Vegas, so keeping those brand new AI data centers cool might be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you haven't seen that area that Alex highlights in his post, it seems like a deserted landscape. And yes, the terrain can be rough, but actually, it's a beautiful landscape that is best left undisturbed.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/do-not-privatize-federal-land</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/do-not-privatize-federal-land</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-29 17:26 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bureaulandmanagement</category>
      <category>uspol</category>
      <category>land</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>