<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - genz</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/genz</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'genz' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-04-08 06:05 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Gen Z Leading Tumblr Revival</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Gen Z, the site has found new life. As of 2025, Gen Z makes up 50% of Tumblr’s active monthly users and accounts for 60% of new sign-ups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't call it a comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User numbers spiked in January during the near-ban of TikTok and jumped again last year when Brazil temporarily banned X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep up with the momentum, Tumblr introduced Reddit-style Communities in December, letting users connect over shared interests like photography and video games. In January, it debuted Tumblr TV—a TikTok-like feature that serves as both a GIF search engine and a short-form video platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps Tumblr’s greatest strength is that it isn’t TikTok or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its users...that’s part of the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr's been through a rough ride, but at the core there's a lot of nice things to like about it. In previous posts, I talked about some opportunities for Tumblr as a result of &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr/"&gt;replatforming on top of WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and its expressed intent for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-still-working-fediverse-integration/"&gt;ActivityPub integration&lt;/a&gt;. In doing so, not only would it enable an intuitive front-end for publishing different kinds of posts, but it would also provide opportunities for self-hosting and a more federated and decentralized social platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to see where this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/gen-z-flocking-tumblr-millennials-musk-zuckerberg-safe-space-2025-4"&gt;Related post from Business Insider's Amanda Hoover&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/gen-z-tumblr-revival</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/gen-z-tumblr-revival</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-04-08 06:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>genz</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>