<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - resource</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/resource</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'resource' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-06-06 22:18 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI Handbook: A Roadmap for Learning Resources</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document aims to serve as a handbook for learning the key concepts underlying modern artificial intelligence systems. Given the speed of recent development in AI, there really isn’t a good textbook-style source for getting up-to-speed on the latest-and-greatest innovations in LLMs or other generative models, yet there is an abundance of great explainer resources (blog posts, videos, etc.) for these topics scattered across the internet. My goal is to organize the “best” of these resources into a textbook-style presentation, which can serve as a roadmap for filling in the prerequisites towards individual AI-related learning goals. My hope is that this will be a “living document”, to be updated as new innovations and paradigms inevitably emerge, and ideally also a document that can benefit from community input and contribution. This guide is aimed at those with a technical background of some kind, who are interested in diving into AI either out of curiosity or for a potential career. I’ll assume that you have some experience with coding and high-school level math, but otherwise will provide pointers for filling in any other prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/genai-handbook-learning-resource-brown</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/genai-handbook-learning-resource-brown</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-06 22:18 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>generativeai</category>
      <category>genai</category>
      <category>handbook</category>
      <category>learning</category>
      <category>resource</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>