<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - Reviews</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews</link>
    <description>Book reviews by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>09/13/2025 14:03 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Serviceberry by Robin Wall Kimerrer</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Indigenous scientist and author of Braiding Sweetgrass Robin Wall Kimmerer harvests serviceberries alongside the birds, she considers the ethic of reciprocity that lies at the heart of the gift economy. How, she asks, can we learn from Indigenous wisdom and the plant world to reimagine what we value most? Our economy is rooted in scarcity, competition, and the hoarding of resources, and we have surrendered our values to a system that actively harms what we love. Meanwhile, the serviceberry’s relationship with the natural world is an embodiment of reciprocity, interconnectedness, and gratitude. The tree distributes its wealth—its abundance of sweet, juicy berries—to meet the needs of its natural community. And this distribution ensures its own survival. As Kimmerer explains, “Serviceberries show us another model, one based upon reciprocity, where wealth comes from the quality of your relationships, not from the illusion of self-sufficiency.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
As Elizabeth Gilbert writes, Robin Wall Kimmerer is “a great teacher, and her words are a hymn of love to the world.” The Serviceberry is an antidote to the broken relationships and misguided goals of our times, and a reminder that “hoarding won’t save us, all flourishing is mutual.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Robin Wall Kimmerer is donating her advance payments from this book as a reciprocal gift, back to the land, for land protection, restoration, and justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm happy my name is not Darren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started as an &lt;a href="https://emergencemagazine.org/essay/the-serviceberry/"&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; expanded into book form. I like how Robin uses her experience working with plants and nature and draws parallels to our society and way of life. We are not separate from nature and it has a lot of lessons we could learn from.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/serviceberry-robin-wall-kimerrer</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/serviceberry-robin-wall-kimerrer</guid>
      <pubDate>09/13/2025 14:03 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Agreements by Don Miguel Ruiz</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In The Four Agreements, don Miguel Ruiz reveals the source of self-limiting beliefs that rob us of joy and create needless suffering. Based on ancient Toltec wisdom, The Four Agreements offer a powerful code of conduct that can rapidly transform our lives to a new experience of freedom, true happiness, and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased the paperback version but ended up listening to the audiobook version while doing chores over the weekend (~2.5 hours). This book gets straight to the point. That point being, throughout our lives we enter into agreements with society that enforce beliefs and influence our behavior, happiness, and inner peace. By speaking with truth and love, not suffering from main character syndrome (not everything is about you), seeking to understand rather than make assumptions, and not striving for perfection but constant improvement, you can slowly create new agreements that are more in line with your higher self.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/four-agreements-ruiz</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/four-agreements-ruiz</guid>
      <pubDate>08/30/2025 19:08 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Experiments by Anne-Laure Le Cunff</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A transformative guide to rethinking our approach to goals, creativity, and life itself from a neuroscientist and entrepreneur, and the creator of the popular Ness Labs newsletter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life isn’t linear, and yet we constantly try to mold it around linear goals: four-year college degrees, ten-year career plans, thirty-year mortgages. What if instead we approached life as a giant playground for experimentation? Based on ancestral philosophy and the latest scientific research, Tiny Experiments provides a desperately needed reframing: Uncertainty can be a state of expanded possibility and a space for metamorphosis.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Neuroscientist and entrepreneur Anne-Laure Le Cunff reveals that all you need is an experimental mindset to turn challenges into self-discovery and doubt into opportunity. Readers will replace the old linear model of success with a circular model of growth in which goals are discovered, pursued, and adapted—not in a vacuum, but in conversation with the larger world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Throughout the book, you will ask hard questions and design simple yet meaningful experiments to find the answers. You will learn how to break free from the invisible cognitive scripts that shape your life, how to harness the power of imperfection, and how to make smarter decisions when the path forward is unclear.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is a guide to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover your true ambitions through conducting tiny personal experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dismantle harmful beliefs about success that have kept you stuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dare to make decisions true to your own aspirations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop trying to find your purpose and start living instead&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Tiny Experiments offers not just practical tools to make sure our most vital work gets done, but a guide to reawakening our curiosity and drive in a noisy, busy, disaffected world, so that we can discover and pursue our most authentic ambitions while making a meaningful contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this book and resonated with a lot of points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the ones that resonated the most with me include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outputs, not outcomes&lt;/strong&gt; - Focus on the output when setting goals. Create and focus on the now rather than being overwhelmed in trying to control the outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metacognition&lt;/strong&gt; - Pause and take time to evaluate your thoughts and experiences about what went well, what didn't, and evaluate what the next steps are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dance with disruption&lt;/strong&gt; - I really enjoyed the parable this chapter started with and puts things into perspective. Our lives and the world are constantly shifting. Rather than trying to control it or label it, surrender and enjoy the ride.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning in public&lt;/strong&gt; - Let curiosity lead you. You don't have to be an expert. Learning in public frees you up to explore new ideas and also build community along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also appreciated Anne-Laure narrating her own book and being honest and vulnerable this was not something she was comfortable with at first. Regardless, I really enjoyed the narration and as an active reader of the blog provided another way to connect with the author.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/tiny-experiments-le-cunff</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/tiny-experiments-le-cunff</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-30 14:04 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book: On the Taboo Against Knowing Who You Are by Alan Watts</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revelatory primer on what it means to be human, from &amp;quot;the perfect guide for a course correction in life&amp;quot; (Deepak Chopra)—and a mind-opening manual of initiation into the central mystery of existence. At the root of human conflict is our fundamental misunderstanding of who we are. The illusion that we are isolated beings, unconnected to the rest of the universe, has led us to view the “outside” world with hostility, and has fueled our misuse of technology and our violent and hostile subjugation of the natural world. To help us understand that the self is in fact the root and ground of the universe, Watts has crafted a revelatory primer on what it means to be human—and a mind-opening manual of initiation into the central mystery of existence. In  The Book, Alan Watts provides us with a much-needed answer to the problem of personal identity, distilling and adapting the Hindu philosophy of Vedanta. Amazon.com Review Modern Western culture and technology is inextricably tied to the belief in the existence of a self as a separate ego, separated from and in conflict with the rest of the world. In this classic book, Watts provides a lucid and simple presentation of an alternative view based on Hindu and Vedantic philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short read and great book. I felt in some of the chapters there was some filler, but the conclusions were great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon...&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/the-book-watts</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/the-book-watts</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-04-15 19:45 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep Going: 10 Ways to Stay Creative in Good Times and Bad by Austin Kleon</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is crazy. Creative work is hard. How do you keep going?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In my previous books — the New York Times bestsellers Steal Like An Artist and Show Your Work! — I showed readers how to steal their way to a more creative life and then share their creativity to get discovered. In Keep Going, I show you 10 ways to stay creative, focused, and true to yourself:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every day is Groundhog Day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a bliss station.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forget the noun, do the verb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make gifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ordinary + extra attention = the extraordinary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slay the art monsters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re allowed to change your mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When in doubt, tidy up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demons hate fresh air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant your garden.
&lt;br&gt;
Whether you’re burned out, starting out, starting over, or wildly successful, Keep Going will help you stay on the path to more creative work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid listicle book.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/keep-going-kleon</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/keep-going-kleon</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-03-24 19:45 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meditative Mind: The Varieties of Meditative Experience by Daniel Goleman</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meditative Mind is an essential traveler’s guide to the topography of the spirit for every spiritual seeker.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the beginning meditator, the book provides a comprehensive, accessible overview of the different kinds of meditation, from Hindu, Buddhist, Sufi, Jewish, and Christian to Transcendental, Tantric, Kundalini, Tibeta Buddhist, Zen, and those developed by Gurdjeff and Krishnamurti, and introduces the reader to the basic elements of their practice.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the experienced meditator, Goleman explores the distinct levels of consciousness developed as a result of long-term application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was a quick and easy read. Given Goleman has an academic background, I enjoyed that the book took that tone. The second part of the book which dives into the various meditation practices using published source material provided a quick introduction into each practice. If you're not interested in learning about the various practices, part three does a nice job summarizing them and essentially getting to the point that in one way or another, for the most part, they're all saying the same thing. The focus of the various practices is on concentration, mindfulness, and insight using meditation as a vehicle. The ultimate goal is using the insights from meditation to effect short and long-term changes in your daily life that get you closer to what is considered ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/meditative-mind-goleman</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/meditative-mind-goleman</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-24 20:42 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Priest by Timothy Leary</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in print after 20 years, this text from the earliest days of psychedelia chronicles the experiences on 16 acid trips taken before LSD was illegal. The trip guides or &amp;quot;high priests&amp;quot; included Aldous Huxley, Ram Dass, Ralph Meltzner, Huston Smith and a junkie from New York City named Willy. It tells of the goings-on and freaking out at the Millbrook mansion in New York State that became the Mecca of psychedelia during the 1960s, and of the many luminaries who made their pilgrimage there to trip with Leary and his group. Chapters include an I Ching reading and a chronicle of what happened during those &amp;quot;spacewalks&amp;quot; of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked this book up (in a town near Woodstock, NY of all places) not knowing what I was in for. I didn't really know much about Leary or his work. The cover and illustrations looked interesting and there were some familiar names like Aldous Huxley and Ram Dass, so that was enough to get me to buy it. This semi-autobiographical book covers a period of time in Leary's life when he had his first psychedelic experience all the way until the time he left / was kicked out of Harvard. During that time, Leary conducted a series of experiments using a variety of psychedelic substances like Psilocybin, LSD, and DMT. As stated in the back cover, each chapter covers a different experience with one of these substances setting the scene for that particular session and then diving into the experience which can be difficult to follow since the writing captures the thoughts during altered states. Some accounts were disturbing. Not exactly what was experienced during the session but events surrounding it (i.e. having one of these sessions early in his experiments at his house while his daughter was hosting a sleepover with her friends). Other accounts were laugh out loud funny. Two different sessions were the most memorable to me. The research program set up at the correctional facility and the other at the church. It was interesting to see his progression at the beginning of the book where he used these substances recreationally and towards the end he appears to develop more reverence or connect spirituality with them. Took me a while to get through the book but overall it was a fun read and first-hand account of this period of time in history.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/high-priest-leary</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/high-priest-leary</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-16 20:50 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Diaries of Adam and Eve by Mark Twain</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Diaries and Adam and Eve” by Mark Twain was originally published as two separate stories and were later combined at Twain’s request. “Extracts from Adam’s Diary” was published as a stand-alone book in 1904. In 1905, “Eve’s Diary” was published in the Christmas issue of “Harper’s Bazaar” and then as a book in 1906. With his signature wit and charm, Twain tells the separate stories of humanity’s biblical ancestors from the perspective of each in the form of diary entries. As one would expect from one of America’s greatest humorist, Adam and Eve’s diaries are funny and clever interpretations of these classic biblical tales. Adam is portrayed as lazy, cranky, and disinterested in the new, long-haired creature he suddenly finds with him in the Garden of Eden. Eve, in contrast, is enthusiastic, chatty, and brimming with curiosity about the enchanting and abundant life around them. The couple’s children, Cain and Abel, also make a brief appearance, though Adam is characteristically uninterested and Eve is left to the do all the hard work. Twain’s retelling of this classic and ancient myth is touching, funny, and an essential addition to the library of anyone who appreciates one of America’s best storytellers. This edition is printed on premium acid-free paper and includes the original illustration of F. Strothmann and Lester Ralph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a short and fun read. Throughout the beginning of Eve's diary, while in the Garden of Eden, I found myself laughing out loud. After the fall though, Eve's diary takes a more serious tone. At the end of her diary, I felt the sentiments Adam expressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam's diary had its moments as well and similar to Eve's, the end was touching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ADAM: Wheresoever she was, THERE was Eden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[NOTE.—I translated a portion of this diary some years ago, and a friend of mine printed a few copies in an incomplete form, but the public never got them. Since then I have deciphered some more of Adam’s hieroglyphics, and think he has now become sufficiently important as a public character to justify this publication.—M. T.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all these years, I see that I was mistaken about Eve in the beginning; it is better to live outside the Garden with her than inside it without her. At first I thought she talked too much; but now I should be sorry to have that voice fall silent and pass out of my life. Blessed be the chestnut that brought us near together and taught me to know the goodness of her heart and the sweetness of her spirit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/diaries-adam-eve-twain</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/diaries-adam-eve-twain</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-19 18:45 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Holographic Universe: The Revolutionary Theory of Reality by Michael Talbot</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone is familiar with holograms—three-dimensional images projected into space with the aid of a laser. Two of the world's most eminent thinkers believe that the universe itself may be a giant hologram, quite literally a kind of image or construct created, at least in part, by the human mind. University of London physicist David Bohm, a protégé of Einstein and one of the world's most respected quantum physicists, and Stanford neurophysiologist Karl Pribram, an architect of our modern understanding of the brain, have developed a remarkable new way of looking at the universe. Their theory explains not only many of the unsolved puzzles of physics but also such mysterious occurrences as telepathy, out-of-body and near-death experiences, &amp;quot;lucid&amp;quot; dreams, and even religious and mystical experiences such as feelings of cosmic unity and miraculous healings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts by using science and the understanding of physics at the time to establish the thesis that the universe is a hologram or simulation. Using this as the foundation, Talbot then explores various natural and supernatural phenomenon such as the placebo effect, stigmata, altered states of consciousness (meditation, hypnosis, lucid dreaming, astral projection, psychedelics), UFOs, near-death-experiences, and uses them as evidence of the latent abilities to shape reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't dived deep into any of the topics and claims made in this book. However, given this book is over 30 years old, personally I'm not aware of shocking new revelations about any of the topics mentioned and they still appear to be in large part considered fringe by the mainstream. Maybe UFOs is one where at the time of this writing there's been hearings at various levels in the U.S. government in recent years. Also, there were reports of UFO / UAV sightings in the New York and New Jersey area over the holidays in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is out there. I want to believe. 🛸&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/holographic-universe-talbot</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/holographic-universe-talbot</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-12 19:45 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Doors of Perception by Aldous Huxley</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most profound and influential explorations of mind-expanding psychedelic drugs ever written, here are two complete classic books—The Doors of Perception and Heaven and Hell—in which Aldous Huxley, author of Brave New World, reveals the mind's remote frontiers and the unmapped areas of human consciousness. This edition also features an additional essay, &amp;quot;Drugs That Shape Men's Minds,&amp;quot; now included for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version I read only covered the first part of this essay, The Doors of Perception. A large portion of this book covers Huxley's experiences during altered states of consciousness. The part I found most interesting was his commentary and comparisons between the society of the time's understanding of science, spirituality, and consciousness and those of ancient or native traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/doors-of-perception-huxley</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/doors-of-perception-huxley</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-12 19:35 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concentration &amp; Inner Awakening: According to Tibetan Buddhism by Fernand Schwarz</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of concentration is essential so that each of us can freely build our destiny. It allows us to get out of confusion and helps us to better control ourselves. Concentration exercises in daily life facilitate the development of our ability to overcome obstacles without repression or violence in order to obtain a more harmonious daily life. Concentration promotes the reappropriation of our memory and the rediscovery of our true identity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This little book invites us to discover in a simple way the itinerary of our consciousness according to the oral teachings of Tibetan Buddhism. This was the goal of the Lama Blo-bzang Don-yod when, in the 17th century to facilitate the learning of his disciples, he made a drawing representing the story of a character accompanied by three symbolic animals on a path.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This path shows us the difficulties that we must overcome through simple and accessible mental and physical practices that demand very little of our daily time. Indeed, the key to this method is to permanently do a short practice daily rather than long occasional workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book mainly concerns itself with the interpretation of a drawing inspired by an engraving done by Blo-Bzang Don-yod. While the drawing is packed with meaning and ideas, the book felt repetitive and dragged on in some parts. Although it's not a long or hard read at ~50 pages, it feels like it could've been condensed even further into less than 20 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/concentration-inner-awakening-tibetan-buddhism</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/concentration-inner-awakening-tibetan-buddhism</guid>
      <pubDate>11/18/2024 17:54 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soul Boom: Why We Need a Spiritual Revolution by Rainn Wilson</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this New York Times and Los Angeles Times bestseller, comedic actor, producer, and writer Rainn Wilson explores the problem-solving benefits that spirituality gives us to create solutions for an increasingly challenging world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The trauma that our struggling species has experienced in recent years—because of both the pandemic and societal tensions that threaten to overwhelm us—is not going away anytime soon. Existing political and economic systems are not enough to bring the change that the world needs. In this book, Rainn Wilson explores the possibility and hope for a spiritual revolution, a “Soul Boom,” to find a healing transformation on both a personal and global level.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For Wilson, this is a serious and essential pursuit, but he brings great humor and his own unique perspective to the conversation. He feels that, culturally, we’ve discounted spirituality—faith and the sacred—and we need profound healing and a unifying understanding of the world that the great spiritual traditions provide. Wilson’s approach to spirituality—the non-physical, eternal aspects of ourselves—is relatable and applies to people of all beliefs, even the skeptics. Filled with genuine insight—not to mention enlightening Kung Fu and Star Trek references—Soul Boom delves into ancient wisdom to seek out practical, transformative answers to life’s biggest questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this book, Rainn explores the impact of society's distancing from the spiritual and religion. Using examples from various world religions and personal annecdotes, he argues that despite the perceived differences, there is a core set of principles they all share. Using these core principles as the foundation, he makes the case for taking the &amp;quot;good parts&amp;quot; and bringing them into your own life as a means of reconnecting with the spiritial and the divine. Ultimately, through this reconnection, not only does it lead to more fulfilling personal experiences and relationships, but also a more conscientious society.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/soul-boom</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/soul-boom</guid>
      <pubDate>11/18/2024 16:59 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jung: A Very Short Introduction by Anthony Stevens</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though he was a prolific writer and original thinker of vast erudition, Jung lacked a gift for clear exposition and his ideas are less widely appreciated than they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In this concise introduction, Anthony Stevens explains clearly the basic concepts of Jungian psychology: the collective unconscious, complex, archetype, shadow, persona, anima, animus, and the individuation of the Self. He examines Jung's views on such disparate subjects as myth, religion, alchemy, 'synchronicity', and the psychology of gender differences, and he devotes separate chapters to the stages of life, Jung's theory of psychological types, the interpretation of dreams, the practice of Jungian analysis, and the unjust allegation that Jung was a Nazi sympathiser. Finally, he argues that Jung's visionary powers and profound spirituality have helped many to find an alternative set of values to the arid materialism prevailing in Western society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony Stevens tries to capture Jung's complex work and distill it into less than 200 pages. I found it to be a great insight into Jung's background, life, and main ideas. It also piqued my interest to read other works on specific topics introduced in this book. Before approaching the original source though, I might read analysis of the source instead as an introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/jung-very-short-introduction-stevens</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/jung-very-short-introduction-stevens</guid>
      <pubDate>09/27/2024 07:47 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Creative Act: A Way of Being by Rick Rubin</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the legendary music producer, a master at helping people connect with the wellsprings of their creativity, comes a beautifully crafted book many years in the making that offers that same deep wisdom to all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many famed music producers are known for a particular sound that has its day. Rick Rubin is known for something else: creating a space where artists of all different genres and traditions can home in on who they really are and what they really offer. He has made a practice of helping people transcend their self-imposed expectations in order to reconnect with a state of innocence from which the surprising becomes inevitable. Over the years, as he has thought deeply about where creativity comes from and where it doesn’t, he has learned that being an artist isn’t about your specific output, it’s about your relationship to the world. Creativity has a place in everyone’s life, and everyone can make that place larger. In fact, there are few more important responsibilities.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Creative Act is a beautiful and generous course of study that illuminates the path of the artist as a road we all can follow. It distills the wisdom gleaned from a lifetime’s work into a luminous reading experience that puts the power to create moments—and lifetimes—of exhilaration and transcendence within closer reach for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this book. My favorite sections were the beginning and end of the book. The middle section is good too but it's more about process.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/creative-act-way-of-being-rubin</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/creative-act-way-of-being-rubin</guid>
      <pubDate>09/27/2024 07:40 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Hail Mary by Andy Weir</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryland Grace is the sole survivor on a desperate, last-chance mission\u2014and if he fails, humanity and the earth itself will perish.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Except that right now, he doesn\u2019t know that. He can\u2019t even remember his own name, let alone the nature of his assignment or how to complete it..&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
All he knows is that he\u2019s been asleep for a very, very long time. And he\u2019s just been awakened to find himself millions of miles from home, with nothing but two corpses for company..&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
His crewmates dead, his memories fuzzily returning, Ryland realizes that an impossible task now confronts him. Hurtling through space on this tiny ship, it\u2019s up to him to puzzle out an impossible scientific mystery\u2014and conquer an extinction-level threat to our species..&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
And with the clock ticking down and the nearest human being light-years away, he\u2019s got to do it all alone..&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Or does he?.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An irresistible interstellar adventure as only Andy Weir could deliver, Project Hail Mary is a tale of discovery, speculation, and survival to rival The Martian\u2014while taking us to places it never dreamed of going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing book. I really enjoyed the various themes explored throughout the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/project-hail-mary</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/project-hail-mary</guid>
      <pubDate>08/01/2024 20:12 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple: Conquering the Crisis of Complexity by Alan Siegel and Irene Etzkorn</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, Alan Siegel and Irene Etzkorn have championed simplicity as a competitive advantage and a consumer right. Consulting with businesses and organizations around the world to streamline products, services, processes and communications, they have achieved dramatic results.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In Simple, the culmination of their work together, Siegel and Etzkorn show us how having empathy, striving for clarity, and distilling your message can reduce the distance between company and customer, hospital and patient, government and citizen-and increase your bottom line.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Examining the best and worst practices of an array of organizations big and small-including the IRS, Google, Philips, Trader Joe\u2019s, Chubb Insurance, and ING Direct, and many more-Siegel and Etzkorn recast simplicity as a mindset, a design aesthetic, and a writing technique.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In these illuminating pages you will discover, among other things:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why the Flip camera became roadkill in the wake of the iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What SIMPLE idea allowed the Cleveland Clinic to improve care and increase revenue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How OXO designed a measuring cup that sold a million units in its first 18 months on the market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where Target got the idea for their \u201cClearRX\u201d prescription system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How New York City simplified its unwieldy bureaucracy with three simple numbers
&lt;br&gt;
By exposing the overly complex things we encounter every day, SIMPLE reveals the reasons we allow confusion to persist, inspires us to seek clarity, and explores how social media is empowering consumers to demand simplicity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The next big idea in business is Simple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/simple-siegel-etzkorn</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/simple-siegel-etzkorn</guid>
      <pubDate>07/14/2024 13:19 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eat That Frog! by Brian Tracy</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieve work-life balance by conquering procrastination and get your most important work done, now with new chapters on technology and maintaining focus&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The fully revised and expanded edition of the global bestseller with over 3 million copies sold world-wide&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The saying goes: if the first thing you do each morning is eat a live frog, then you’re done with the toughest thing for the day. Eating that frog means tackling your most challenging task—and it’s also the one that can have the greatest positive impact on your life.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Productivity and time management coach Brian Tracy shows you how to organize each day so you can zero in on these critical tasks and accomplish them efficiently and effectively.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The 3 essentials of successful time management are decision, discipline, and determination, and Tracy shows you how to dial in these skills using 21 principles and techniques like:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
• Single handle every task&lt;br /&gt;
• Upgrade your key skills&lt;br /&gt;
• Identify your key constraints&lt;br /&gt;
• Put the pressure on yourself&lt;br /&gt;
• Slice and dice the task&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This life-changing manual will ensure that you get more of your important tasks done today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick read. I got through it in about two hours. Most of the advice are things that you may have heard of before. Not saying it's bad, but it's more of a reference manual / card. If short on time, you can probably just skip to the conclusion to get a gist of the key points from the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unwritten goals lead to confusion, vagueness, misdirection, and numerous mistakes. (p. 34 / 210)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of your top goals at work should be to get the highest possible return on your investment of your mental, emotional, and physical energy. (p. 40 / 210)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always work from a list. When something new comes up, add it to the list before you do it. (p.41 / 210)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is never enough time to do everything, but there is always enough time to do the most important thing. (p. 57 / 210)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is full of people who are waiting for someone to come along and motivate them to be the kind of people they wish they could be. The problem is that no one is coming to the rescue. (p. 116 / 210)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the table:&lt;/strong&gt; Decide exactly what you want. Clarity is essential. Write out your goals and objectives before you begin. (p. 164 &amp;amp; 165 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan every day in advance:&lt;/strong&gt; Think on paper. Every minute you spend on planning can save you five or ten minutes in execution. (p. 165 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply the 80/20 Rule to everything:&lt;/strong&gt; Twenty percent of your activities will acount for 80 percent of your results. Always concentrate your efforts on that top 20 percent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider the consequences:&lt;/strong&gt; Most of your important tasks and priorities are those that can have the most serious consequences, positive or negative, on your life or work. Focus on these above all else. (p. 165 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice creative procrastination:&lt;/strong&gt; Since you can't do everything, you must learn to deliberately put off those tasks that are too low value os that you have enough time to do the few tihngs that really count. (p. 165 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the ABCDE Method continually:&lt;/strong&gt; Before you begin work on a list of tasks, take a few moments to organize them by value and priority so you can be sure of working on your most important activiites. (p. 165 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on key result areas:&lt;/strong&gt; Identify those results that you absolutely, positively have to get to do your job well, and work on them all day long. (p. 166 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="8"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply the Law of Three:&lt;/strong&gt; Identify the three things you do in your work that account for 90 percent of your contribution, and focus on getting them done before anything else. You will then have more time for your family and personal life. (p. 166 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="9"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare thoroughly before you begin:&lt;/strong&gt; Hvae everything you need at hand before you start. Assemble all the papers, information, tools, work materials, and numbers you might require so that you can get started and keep going. (p. 166 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="10"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take it one barrel at a time:&lt;/strong&gt; You can accomplish the biggest and most complicated job if you just complete it one step at a time. (p. 166 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="11"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrade your key skills:&lt;/strong&gt; The more knowledgeable and skilled you become as your key tasks, the faster you start them and the sooner you get them done. Determine exactly what it is that you are very good at, and throw your whole heart into doing those specific things very, very well. (p. 166 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="12"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify your key contraints:&lt;/strong&gt; Determine the bottlenecks or choke points, internal or external, that set the speed at which you achieve your most important goals, and focus on alleviating them. (p. 167 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="13"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put the pressure on yourself:&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine that you have to leave town for a month, and work as if you had to get your major task completed before you left. (p. 167 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="14"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivate yourself into action:&lt;/strong&gt; Be your own cheerleader. Look for the good in every situation. Focus on the solution rather than the problem. Always be optimistic and constructive. (p. 167 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="15"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology is a terrible master:&lt;/strong&gt; Take back your time from enslaving technological additions. Learn to often turn devices off and leave them off. (p. 167 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="16"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology is a wonderful servant:&lt;/strong&gt; Use your technological tools to confront yourself with what is most important and protect yourself from what is least important. (p. 167 &amp;amp; 168 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="17"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus your attention:&lt;/strong&gt; Stop the interruptions and distractions that interfere with completing your most important tasks. (p. 168 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="18"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slice and dice the tasks:&lt;/strong&gt; Break large, complex tasks down into bite-sized pieces, and then do just one small part of the task to get started. (p. 168 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="19"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create large chunks of time:&lt;/strong&gt; Organize your days around large blocks of time so you can concentrate on extended periods on your most important tasks. (p. 168 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="20"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop a sense of urgency:&lt;/strong&gt; Make a habit of moving fast on your key tasks. Become known as a person who does things quickly and well. (p. 168 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ol start="21"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single handle every task:&lt;/strong&gt; Set clear priorities, start immediately on your most important task, and then work without stopping until the job is 100 percent complete. This is the real key to high performance and maximum personal productivity. (p. 168 / 210)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three key capabilities to develop habit of focus and concentration
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision - to develop the habit of task completion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discipline - yourself to practice the principles learned until they are automatic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determination - until the habit is locked in and becomes a permanent part of your personality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think on paper
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 1: Decide what you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 2: Write it down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 3: Set a deadline for your goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 4: Make a list of everything you can think of that you are going to have to do to achieve your goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 5: Organize the list into a plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 6: Take action on your plan immediately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 7: Resolve to do something every day that moves you toward your major goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different lists for different purposes
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a master list on which you write down everything you can think of that you want to do sometime in the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a monthly list that you make at the end of the month for the month ahead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a weekly list where you plan your entire week in advance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer items fro myour monthly and weekly lists onto your daily list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABCDE Method
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A - Something that is very important, something you MUST do. Has serious positive or negative consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B - Something you SHOULD do. Mild consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C - Something that WOULD BE NICE to do. No consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D - Something you can DELEGATE. Delegate anything to free up time for A tasks only YOU can do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E - Something you can ELIMINATE. Something that may have been important at one time but no longer relevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On optimist behaviors
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for the good in every situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek the valuable lesson in every setback or difficulty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for the solution to every problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think and talk continually about their goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On steps to mastery
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read in your field for at least one hour every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take every course and seminar available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to audio programs in your car&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NOTE: I'd add making things to this. You can take all the courses and read all the books, but if you don't put things to practice, mastery is limited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/eat-that-frog-tracy</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/eat-that-frog-tracy</guid>
      <pubDate>07/09/2024 21:05 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lurking: How a Person Became a User by Joanne McNeil</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Esquire’s Best Books to Elevate Your Reading List in 2020, , and a OneZero Best Tech Book of 2020. Named one of the 100 Notable books of 2020 by the End of the World Review.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A concise but wide-ranging personal history of the internet from—for the first time—the point of view of the user.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In a shockingly short amount of time, the internet has bound people around the world together and torn us apart and changed not just the way we communicate but who we are and who we can be. It has created a new, unprecedented cultural space that we are all a part of—even if we don’t participate, that is how we participate—but by which we’re continually surprised, betrayed, enriched, befuddled. We have churned through platforms and technologies and in turn been churned by them. And yet, the internet is us and always has been.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In Lurking, Joanne McNeil digs deep and identifies the primary (if sometimes contradictory) concerns of people online: searching, safety, privacy, identity, community, anonymity, and visibility. She charts what it is that brought people online and what keeps us here even as the social equations of digital life—what we’re made to trade, knowingly or otherwise, for the benefits of the internet—have shifted radically beneath us. It is a story we are accustomed to hearing as tales of entrepreneurs and visionaries and dynamic and powerful corporations, but there is a more profound, intimate story that hasn’t yet been told.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Long one of the most incisive, ferociously intelligent, and widely respected cultural critics online, McNeil here establishes a singular vision of who we are now, tells the stories of how we became us, and helps us start to figure out what we do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/lurking-how-person-becomes-user</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/lurking-how-person-becomes-user</guid>
      <pubDate>04/23/2024 22:03 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desert Oracle: Volume 1 by Ken Layne</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cult-y pocket-size field guide to the strange and intriguing secrets of the Mojave—its myths and legends, outcasts and oddballs, flora, fauna, and UFOs—becomes the definitive, oracular book of the desert.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the past five years, Desert Oracle has existed as a quasi-mythical, quarterly periodical available to the very determined only by subscription or at the odd desert-town gas station or the occasional hipster boutique, its canary-yellow-covered, forty-four-page issues handed from one curious desert zealot to the next, word spreading faster than the printers could keep up with. It became a radio show, a podcast, a live performance. Now, for the first time—and including both classic and new, never-before-seen revelations—Desert Oracle has been bound between two hard covers and is available to you.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Straight out of Joshua Tree, California, Desert Oracle is “The Voice of the Desert”: a field guide to the strange tales, singing sand dunes, sagebrush trails, artists and aliens, authors and oddballs, ghost towns and modern legends, musicians and mystics, scorpions and saguaros, out there in the sand. Desert Oracle is your companion at a roadside diner, around a campfire, in your tent or cabin (or high-rise apartment or suburban living room) as the wind and the coyotes howl outside at night.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
From journal entries of long-deceased adventurers to stray railroad ad copy, and musings on everything from desert flora, rumored cryptid sightings, and other paranormal phenomena, Ken Layne's Desert Oracle collects the weird and the wonderful of the American Southwest into a single, essential volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/desert-oracle-vol-1</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/desert-oracle-vol-1</guid>
      <pubDate>04/23/2024 22:03 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes From The Undergrond by Fyodor Dostoyevsky</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dostoevsky’s most revolutionary novel, Notes from Underground marks the dividing line between nineteenth- and twentieth-century fiction, and between the visions of self each century embodied. One of the most remarkable characters in literature, the unnamed narrator is a former official who has defiantly withdrawn into an underground existence. In full retreat from society, he scrawls a passionate, obsessive, self-contradictory narrative that serves as a devastating attack on social utopianism and an assertion of man’s essentially irrational nature.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Richard Pevear and Larissa Volokhonsky, whose Dostoevsky translations have become the standard, give us a brilliantly faithful edition of this classic novel, conveying all the tragedy and tormented comedy of the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actions&lt;/h2&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/notes-from-the-underground-dostoyevsky</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/reviews/notes-from-the-underground-dostoyevsky</guid>
      <pubDate>03/31/2024 19:31 -05:00</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>