<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - protocols</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/protocols</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'protocols' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-05-09 20:23 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of AI Agent Protocols</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;It'll be interesting to see once many of the exiting protocols begin to converge towards a standard. There's a ton of existing well-adopted protocol standards out there that when stitched together could create a compelling and native experience. I think eventually we'll get to a place where agents are native parts of the OSI stack and the world wide web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of large language models (LLMs) has led to the widespread deployment of LLM agents across diverse industries, including customer service, content generation, data analysis, and even healthcare. However, as more LLM agents are deployed, a major issue has emerged: &lt;strong&gt;there is no standard way for these agents to communicate with external tools or data sources. This lack of standardized protocols makes it difficult for agents to work together or scale effectively, and it limits their ability to tackle complex, real-world tasks. A unified communication protocol for LLM agents could change this. It would allow agents and tools to interact more smoothly, encourage collaboration, and triggering the formation of collective intelligence.&lt;/strong&gt; In this paper, we provide the first comprehensive analysis of existing agent protocols, proposing a systematic two-dimensional classification that differentiates context-oriented versus inter-agent protocols and general-purpose versus domain-specific protocols. Additionally, we conduct a comparative performance analysis of these protocols across key dimensions such as security, scalability, and latency. Finally, we explore the future landscape of agent protocols by identifying critical research directions and characteristics necessary for next-generation protocols. These characteristics include adaptability, privacy preservation, and group-based interaction, as well as trends toward layered architectures and collective intelligence infrastructures. We expect this work to serve as a practical reference for both researchers and engineers seeking to design, evaluate, or integrate robust communication infrastructures for intelligent agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/survey-ai-agent-protocols</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/survey-ai-agent-protocols</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 20:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>agents</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>research</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Agentic Fediverse&amp;quot; is the idea of a new kind of network federation, a complementary iteration on the concept of federation currently established with ActivityPub. It's an experiment and something that we in Muni Town are still trying to define more concretely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tenets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still working on defining the core tenets of the agentic fediverse, but here is what we have so far.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An agentic fediverse is...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fediverse of agents; agent-centric, as opposed to server-centric.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local-first; solve local problems for local people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessible by default; inaccessibility is a bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematically consensual; architected on the basis of informed consent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/agentic-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/agentic-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>munitown</category>
      <category>agents</category>
      <category>agentic</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Social Web - Hello, Social Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're A New Social, a new non-profit organization focused on building cross-protocol tools and services for the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our mission is to liberate people's networks from their platforms, enabling &lt;a href="https://www.augment.ink/bridges-the-last-network-effect/?ref=anew.social"&gt;The Last Network Effect&lt;/a&gt; and leveling the playing field across the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The first project we'll take on to accomplish this mission is &lt;a href="https://fed.brid.gy/?ref=anew.social"&gt;Bridgy Fed&lt;/a&gt;, a service that enables users of ActivityPub-based platforms like Mastodon, ATProto-based platforms like Bluesky, and websites to interact and engage across ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:39 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>anewsocial</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>atproto</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starter Packs with OPML and RSS</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
One of the things I like about Bluesky is the [Starter Pack feature](https://bsky.social/about/blog/06-26-2024-starter-packs). 

In a gist, a Starter Pack is a collection of feeds. 

Bluesky users can:

- Create starter packs
- Share starter packs
- Subscribe to starter packs

Unfortunately, Starter Packs are limited to Bluesky. 

Or are they? 

As mentioned, starter packs are a collection of feeds that others can create, share, and subscribe to. 

[Bluesky supports RSS](/responses/bluesky-rss-support/), which means you could organize the feeds using an OPML file that you can share with others and others can subscribe to. The benefits of this is, you can continue to keep up with activity on Bluesky from the feed reader of your choice without being required to have an account on Bluesky. 

More importantly, because RSS and OPML are open standards, you're not limited to building starter packs for Bluesky. You can create, share, and subscribe to starter packs for any platform that supports RSS. That includes blogs, podcasts, forums, YouTube, Mastodon, etc. [Manton seems to have something similar in mind](https://www.manton.org/2024/12/07/with-the-success.html) as a means of building on open standards that make it easy for Micro.blog to interop with various platforms. 

If you're interested in what that might look like in practice, check out my "starter packs" which you can subscribe to using your RSS reader of choice and the provided OPML files. 

- [Blogs](/collections/blogroll)
- [Podcasts](/collections/podroll)
- [YouTube](/collections/youtube)
- [Forums](/collections/forums)

I'm still working on similar collections for Mastodon and Bluesky but the same concept applies.  

Although these are just simple examples, it shows the importance of building on open standards and the open web. Doing so introduces more freedom for creators and communities. 

Here are other "starter packs" you might consider subscribing to. 

- [People and Blogs](https://www.thingelstad.com/2024/12/03/people-blogs-list.html)
- [Blogroll Club](https://blogroll.club/faq/)

If this is interesting to you, [Feedland](https://feedland.org/) might be a project worth checking out.  ]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-opml-starter-packs</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-opml-starter-packs</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-08 19:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>starterpacks</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>openstandards</category>
      <category>feedland</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon instance now supports OpenGraph creator tag</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In version 4.3, &lt;a href="https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2024/10/mastodon-4.3/#:%7E:text=Helping%20writers%20and%20journalists"&gt;Mastodon introduced OpenGraph creator tags&lt;/a&gt; to link to an author's Fediverse account from within a post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag"&gt;implemented it on my website&lt;/a&gt; a while back. However, because my instance wasn't using a version that supported it, it didn't show up on my instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since upgrading to 4.3.1, I can now see my posts making use of the creator tag feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c8be21fd-daa8-40ef-b923-fd6c302ab1f3" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Mastodon Post with Author Profile Link" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the original post, implementing it was relatively trivial. Another win for open protocols and standards.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/mastodon-instance-supports-opengraph-creator-tag</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/mastodon-instance-supports-opengraph-creator-tag</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 09:25 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>opengraph</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You should be using an RSS reader</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;Yes, you should!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the conduit through which I experience Molly's excellent work is totally enshittification-proof, and the more I use it, the easier it is for everyone to be less enshittified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
This conduit is anti-lock-in, it works for nearly the whole internet. It is surveillance-resistant, far more accessible than the web or any mobile app interface. It is my secret super-power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
It's RSS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
...But RSS isn't just good for the news! It's good for everything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Your RSS reader doesn't (necessarily) have an algorithm. By default, you'll get everything as it appears, in reverse-chronological order.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Now, you sign up to so many feeds that you're feeling overwhelmed and you want an algorithm to prioritize posts – or recommend content. Lots of RSS readers have some kind of algorithm and recommendation system...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
But you control the algorithm, you control the recommendations. And if a new RSS reader pops up with an algorithm you're dying to try, you can export all the feeds you follow with a single click, which will generate an OPML file. Then, with one click, you can import that OPML file into any other RSS reader in existence and all your feeds will be seamlessly migrated there. You can delete your old account, or you can even use different readers for different purposes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
RSS basically works like social media should work. Using RSS is a chance to visit a utopian future in which the platforms have no power, and all power is vested in publishers, who get to decide what to publish, and in readers, who have total control over what they read and how, without leaking any personal information through the simple act of reading.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
And here's the best part: every time you use RSS, you bring that world closer into being!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Unlike those largely useless, performative boycotts of widely used platforms, switching to RSS doesn't require that you give anything up. Not only does switching to RSS let you continue to follow all the newsletters, webpages and social media accounts you're following now, it makes doing so better: more private, more accessible, and less enshittified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Using RSS to follow the stuff that matters to you will have an immediate, profoundly beneficial impact on your own digital life – and it will appreciably, irreversibly nudge the whole internet towards a better state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article by &lt;a href="https://craphound.com/bio/"&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written at length on my website as to &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom"&gt;why I enjoy RSS&lt;/a&gt;. My use goes back to the days of Google Reader. Like many, once that was disbanded, my consumption pretty much shifted to social media for a few years. After growing dissatisfaction with the limitations and lack of control over my feed, I started my journey back to RSS readers eventually landing on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/subscribed-to-1042-feeds-newsblur"&gt;NewsBlur&lt;/a&gt; and elfeed as my readers of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this website, RSS plays an important role in a few areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS is how I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/website-feeds-opml/"&gt;Enable discovery of my own feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;Enable visitors to subscribe and get the latest content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps"&gt;Syndicate posts to Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented/"&gt;Enable feed discovery of websites I subscribe to&lt;/a&gt; through my:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;Blogroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;Podroll (podcasts)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/youtube/"&gt;YouTubeRoll?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/forums/"&gt;ForumRoll?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can you get started?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;a href="https://aboutfeeds.com/"&gt;about feeds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the many &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/we-love-rss"&gt;getting started guides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse through &lt;a href="https://blogroll.club/"&gt;blogrolls and feed catalogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24036427/rss-feed-reader-best"&gt;Explore various feed readers&lt;/a&gt; to find the one that works best for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/you-should-be-using-rss-reader-pluralistic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/you-should-be-using-rss-reader-pluralistic</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-10-18 08:54 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>pluralistic</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>freeweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky Welcomes Mike Masnick to Board of Directors</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Nice! I remember reading &lt;a href="https://knightcolumbia.org/content/protocols-not-platforms-a-technological-approach-to-free-speech"&gt;Protocols, Not Platforms&lt;/a&gt; many years ago and felt inspired to seek out a better web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mike-masnick-bluesky-board-of-directors</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mike-masnick-bluesky-board-of-directors</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-07 22:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>platforms</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>humanweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPML for website feeds</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;While thiking about implementing &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/well-known-feeds/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;.well-known&lt;/code&gt; for RSS feeds on my site&lt;/a&gt;, I had another idea. Since that uses OPML anyways, I remembered recently &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented//"&gt;doing something similar for my blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is the same, except instead of making my blogroll discoverable, I'm doing it for my feeds. At the end of the day, a blogroll is a collection of feeds, so it should just work for my own feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation ended up being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an OPML file for&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt; each of the feeds on by website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-xml"&gt; &amp;lt;opml version=&amp;quot;2.0&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Luis Quintanilla Feeds&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;ownerId&amp;gt;https://www.luisquintanilla.me&amp;lt;/ownerId&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;outline title=&amp;quot;Blog&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Blog&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;rss&amp;quot; htmlUrl=&amp;quot;/posts/1&amp;quot; xmlUrl=&amp;quot;/blog.rss&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;outline title=&amp;quot;Microblog&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Microblog&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;rss&amp;quot; htmlUrl=&amp;quot;/feed&amp;quot; xmlUrl=&amp;quot;/microblog.rss&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;outline title=&amp;quot;Responses&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Responses&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;rss&amp;quot; htmlUrl=&amp;quot;/feed/responses&amp;quot; xmlUrl=&amp;quot;/responses.rss&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;outline title=&amp;quot;Mastodon&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Mastodon&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;rss&amp;quot; htmlUrl=&amp;quot;/mastodon&amp;quot; xmlUrl=&amp;quot;/mastodon.rss&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;outline title=&amp;quot;Bluesky&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Bluesky&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;rss&amp;quot; htmlUrl=&amp;quot;/bluesky&amp;quot; xmlUrl=&amp;quot;/bluesky.rss&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
 	&amp;lt;outline title=&amp;quot;YouTube&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;YouTube&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;rss&amp;quot; htmlUrl=&amp;quot;/youtube&amp;quot; xmlUrl=&amp;quot;/bluesky.rss&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/opml&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a &lt;code&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; tag to the &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; element of my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;feeds&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Feeds&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/feed/index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/website-feeds-opml</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/website-feeds-opml</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-01 20:08 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>feeds</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>webstandards</category>
      <category>standards</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>404 Media Now Has a Full Text RSS Feed</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paid for the development of full text RSS feeds for Ghost-based publishers. Now we can offer them to our paid subscribers, and other Ghost sites can use the service too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our friends Anil Dash and Ernie Smith have recently written passionately and persuasively about the importance of RSS to the open web, and about how a technology that turns 25 years old this month remains both subversive and quite versatile. RSS-based distribution underpins a podcasting ecosystem that has allowed for shows to be distributed not just on Apple Podcasts but on Spotify, Google Podcasts, Pocket Casts, Overcast, and whatever other podcast player you might want to listen on. “Being able to say, ‘wherever you get your podcasts’ is a radical statement,” Dash wrote. “Because what it represents is the triumph of exactly the kind of technology that's supposed to be impossible: open, empowering tech that's not owned by any one company, that can't be controlled by any one company, and that allows people to have ownership over their work and their relationship with their audience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS has empowered podcasters, but that it needs a “creator economy rethink” for text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/404-media-full-text-rss</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/404-media-full-text-rss</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-26 21:16 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>404media</category>
      <category>ghost</category>
      <category>404</category>
      <category>media</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>technology</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JRE - Now available wherever you get your podcasts</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Since Joe Rogan went exclusive with Spotify, I maybe listened to a handful of episodes. The main reason for it is, I don't use Spotify to listen to podcasts. Periodically, I'd scroll through the feed to see if he had any intereting guests on. As part of his new contract, the podcast is now available on other platforms. That means you can listen &lt;a href="https://podbay.fm/p/the-joe-rogan-experience/about"&gt;wherever you get your podcasts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/jre-wherever-you-get-your-podcasts</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/jre-wherever-you-get-your-podcasts</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-26 18:29 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>jre</category>
      <category>joerogan</category>
      <category>audio</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private social media?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Brain dumping a bunch of half-formed thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, I've been thinking about different forms of sharing content. With the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/19/technology/personaltech/tiktok-twitter-facebook-social.html"&gt;shifts in social media towards smaller, more private communities&lt;/a&gt;, is it possible to get the best of feeds for sharing updates and information but in a smaller more intimate way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a few of the options I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://dayoneapp.com/guides/tips-and-tutorials/shared-journals/"&gt;Day One Shared Journals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made for an audience of one, but other can collaborate on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the interface, looking back at specific days and events that took place is easy to look back on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May be able to include different forms of media (i.e. audio, video, photos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No individual profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require everyone to use the same app / service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;E-mail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Newsletters, Mailing lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost everyone has an e-mail address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on standard protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Producers can use any app they'd like to compose e-mails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers can use any app they'd like to read e-mails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could use any app / client / service-provider they'd like. (Federated by default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content rendering may differ based on app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could add to the noise already present in your e-mail inbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No individual accounts / feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Messaging Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Discord, Matrix, IRC, Slack, Signal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing could be done via SMS (though this would limit the content you share).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could form various sub-groups to sub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require everyone to use the same app / service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May not have a way to view individual profiles or feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because conversations are not often grouped by topics, it might be difficult to find conversations, especially older conversations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Private blogs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com/go/tutorials/private-blog-wordpress-com/"&gt;Private WordPress Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://havenweb.org/"&gt;Haven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produces can use any tool / service to author and publish posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers can access via any browser of their choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May have to host your own service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers may have to create accounts and passwords for each of the private blogs they follow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fediverse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Mastodon, PixelFed, PeerTube&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familar social media interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More availability of apps and services that form part of the Fediverse make it easier for producers and consumers to use what makes the most sense for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited to the format supported by the app / service (i.e. Pixelfed is for images / video, PeerTube for video, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require you to host your own service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;P2P Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://scuttlebutt.nz/"&gt;ScuttleButt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could be made for an audience of one but shared with other peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentralized by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access individual feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similar to the Fediverse, being exposed to new protocols and technical terms may make onboarding and adoption challenging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require you to host your own service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocols haven't been widely adopted so users are limited in the apps / services they can use for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forums&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://discourse.nixos.org/"&gt;NixOS Forum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lemmy.world/"&gt;Lemmy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could create threads and conversations on various topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to search and tag content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone would have to host a server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might not work well for small groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a variation on the private blog. Except instead of having a website that displays the posts, you just have an RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://daverupert.com/2018/01/welcome-to-rss-club/"&gt;RSS-Only Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Producers can use any software they'd like to create and publish their RSS feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers can use any feed reader to access and read content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone could have their own feed, so effectively they'd be like profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to figure out how to produce and host the RSS feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can't really control who sees this since the feed is public. Maybe private feeds could help here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited interaction. Users can't comment or reply to items in a feed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this is not an exhaustive list of pros and cons, just a few that I thought of. I persoanlly would skew towards e-mail and messaging apps. The main reason at least with e-mail is that everyone is familiar with it and most likely won't have to create separate accounts on various silos to communicate and engage with others. With apps like &lt;a href="https://delta.chat/"&gt;DeltaChat&lt;/a&gt; you could actualy combine them and get the best of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/private-social-media</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/private-social-media</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-22 21:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>private</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>forums</category>
      <category>journal</category>
      <category>e-mail</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top five RSS readers for keeping up with your news feeds</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS readers allow you to collect the articles of specific sources in one app, making it a lot easier to find the content you’re interested in without crawling through a lot of noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever RSS feed reader you choose, it’s worth it to try at least one or two. This way, you can keep up with news from your favorite sources without depending on the chaos that is your email account or the random opinions from TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great overview of the various RSS feed readers out there.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/top-five-rss-feed-readers-verge</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/top-five-rss-feed-readers-verge</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-22 20:49 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>news</category>
      <category>feeds</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 - The year of Gemini?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;If 2023 was the year of AI and the Fediverse, is 2024 the year of Gemini?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been seeing a few posts about Gemini cross my feed reader which is more than I'm used to seeing. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2023/12/29/the-gopher-revival-is-upon-us/"&gt;The Gopher Revival Is Upon Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://zserge.com/posts/small-web/"&gt;Poor Man's Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gemini is weird in a fun way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since content is text-based, using terminal clients like &lt;a href="https://thelambdalab.xyz/elpher/"&gt;Elpher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/makew0rld/amfora"&gt;Amfora&lt;/a&gt; make it easy to browse pages (capsules) and blogs (gemlogs).&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/2024-year-of-gemini</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/2024-year-of-gemini</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-30 00:34 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>gemini</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>gopher</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing ActivityPub adoption</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Exciting developments in the ActivityPub space. A few months ago, the &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin/"&gt;WordPress plugin&lt;/a&gt; was released. In the last few days, Threads recently started testing their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/13/24000120/threads-meta-activitypub-test-mastodon"&gt;ActivityPub integration&lt;/a&gt;. Not so new but new to me, I saw that &lt;a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/activitypub-plugin/266794"&gt;Discourse, the forum software, also has an ActivityPub plugin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/18/24006062/flipboard-fediverse-mastodon-activitypub-profiles-social"&gt;Flipboard&lt;/a&gt; is one of the latest names to express plans for ActivityPub integration. Not sure what the end result will look like when all these platforms are all interoping with each other but I'm excited to see platforms building on open protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/growing-activitypub-adoption-december-2023</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/growing-activitypub-adoption-december-2023</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-18 20:28 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSS for new event notifications</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;After my post on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/rss-community-calendars"&gt;Shared calendars and RSS&lt;/a&gt; I kept thinking about what else you can get out of sharing a calendar using RSS. What I didn't see immediately is the main use case of RSS, though I did mention it as a drawback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main drawbacks I see are that I can't get notifications or see it in my calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, with RSS, I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; get notifications when a new event has been added to the calendar. With iCal for example, when a new event is added to the calendar, it'll automatically be populated in my calendar client. However, I won't get a notification that a new event has been added. Conversely, with RSS, I won't see it in my calendar client but I will get a notification in my RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When paired together though you could use RSS to get notified when a new event is added to the calendar and also be able to view it in your calendar client since it'll automatically be populated (assuming you're already subscribed to the shared calendar). That means managing two feeds, but the more I think about it, the RSS format makes some sense. The shared calendar could be the source of truth. When a new event is added to the calendar, the RSS feed can be updated. The &lt;code&gt;channel&lt;/code&gt;property has the link to the shared calendar you can subscribe to and the individual events have &lt;em&gt;.ics&lt;/em&gt; files embedded in the &lt;code&gt;enclosure&lt;/code&gt;. As a consumer, the new event notification will then appear in my RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/rss-community-calendars-new-events</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/rss-community-calendars-new-events</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-11-12 09:52 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>calendars</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shared calendars and RSS</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I just came across a new use for RSS - shared calendars. Well, not exactly sharing calendars in RSS format. While I have seen calendars in RSS format as I'll mention later in this post, I think there's enough downsides that make this impractical. However, for discoverability, there's some RSS patterns that shared calendars could benefit from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading a &lt;a href="https://doc.searls.com/2023/11/09/datepress/"&gt;recent post on Doc Searls' blog&lt;/a&gt; it got me thinking about using public calendars for sharing community events. By leveraging iCal or CalDav, this could be a good alternative to current solutions like Facebook Events or Meetup. It could also be a great way to foster interoperability. There's still the discoverability problem, but platforms like Meetup and Facebook Events could enable subscribing to shared public calendars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sent me down a search to see whether others were using shared calendars, similar to &lt;a href="https://bsquarebulletin.com/test-calendar/?r34icsym=202312"&gt;The Big Calendar&lt;/a&gt;. It was nice to see that Penn State has shared calendars for their various sports. That shouldn't be surprising. As a university, they already share their academic calendars. The part that I found surprising though was that RSS was one of the options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/rss-community-calendars.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Penn State Subscription Calendar Subscriptions" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloading the RSS feed enabled me to import it into my feed reader and view it there. I'd prefer if instead of downloading the RSS feed as a file, they just provided the link so I could copy and paste it into my feed reader. However, it's still nice that just like podcasts and YouTube feeds, I can now also see Penn State athletic events in my feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what the benefit of subscribing to this feed via RSS as opposed to the calendar itself has. The main drawbacks I see are that I can't get notifications or see it in my calendar. I also don't know if changes and updates to events also propagate to the RSS feed. That's why I'd prefer to just subscribe to the calendar directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to the broader topic of shared calendars and discoverability mentioned in the &lt;a href="https://bsquarebulletin.com/test-calendar/?r34icsym=202312"&gt;DataPress proposal&lt;/a&gt; for community calendars, you could imagine a solution similar to how websites can make their &lt;a href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2021/automatically-discoverable-rss-feeds/"&gt;RSS feeds discoverable&lt;/a&gt;. As a calendar and community maintainer, you could post the link to your shared calendars on your website. As a community member, you'd just need to point your calendar client to the respective website's domain (i.e. gopsusports.com) and your client would automatically import the shared calendars. This is how shared calendars work today. The difference is, you don't need the exact link to the calendar, you just need the website domain. The calendar client is what handles the discovery and import process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important thing to highlight, doing something like this isn't exclusive to communities. You could imagine businesses being able to implement similar practices to communicate their business hours and availability. Platforms like Yelp or Google could then just import the public calendar for that business and display the business hours on their platform. To schedule your next oil change, imagine looking at your auto service shop's shared calendar and sending a calendar invite for one of their open slots. This is no different to solutions like &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/business/scheduling-and-booking-app"&gt;Microsoft Bookings&lt;/a&gt;. The difference is, instead of using these platforms, you would do it from your preferred calendar client of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could also see this working for individuals as well. If you need to coordinate something with other people, instead of the constant back and forth to find availability, you can just share your public calendar and they can find a time that works for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the point of this longish post is that by building on simple components like calendars, iCal, CalDAV, and RSS, communities, businesses, and individuals could communicate and collaborate more effectively without being constrained to any single platform.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/rss-community-calendars</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/rss-community-calendars</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-11-11 13:34 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>calendars</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix 2.0: The Future of Matrix</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: If you want to play with a shiny new Matrix 2.0 client, head over to &lt;a href="https://element.io/blog/element-x-ignition/"&gt;Element X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/matrix-2-0</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/matrix-2-0</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-22 10:10 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>communication</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering the RSS protocol</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

RSS provides a standardized way of aggregating content giving content creators the freedom to choose how they publish content while giving consumers the freedom to choose how they consume that content. I've used RSS for a long time. One of my favorite RSS readers was Google Reader while it was still around and I believe [I'm not the only fan](https://www.ripgooglereader.com/). Since then, I've bounced around between different RSS feed readers not settling one until recently when I started using [NewsBlur](https://newsblur.com). As a result of finding an RSS feed reader I liked, I've also started to expand the content I follow via RSS feeds to social media, videos, podcasts, and software projects. In part, this has gotten me thinking about some of the benefits of protocols. The essay [Protocols, Not Platforms: A Technological Approach To Free Speech](https://knightcolumbia.org/content/protocols-not-platforms-a-technological-approach-to-free-speech) makes good points on some of these benefits. Though the focus of that article is on free speech, I prefer to think about the benefits in terms of user freedom.

## Creator freedom using RSS

RSS provides content creators with the freedom to choose how and where they publish content. As a content creator, depending on the type of content you produce you use different platforms to publish. For example, when I blog, I publish on this site, when I create videos, I publish to YouTube or livestream on Twitch and to further expand the reach of my content, I publish links on social media like Reddit or Twitter. In each case, I use different platforms to publish content. This might be okay because the audiences interested in the video content may not be interested in blog posts and vice versa. However, now the content is split across all these various platforms with their own accounts, interfaces, policies, and audiences. It also means, when I tell people where they can follow me, it usually involves an entire speech like: "Follow me on GitHub at [lqdev](https://github.com/lqdev/), Twitter at [ljquintanilla](https://twitter.com/ljquintanilla), my blog at [luisquintanilla.me](/posts/1)...". Of course, I don't always list out all the platforms I'm active on and it's highly dependent on the setting, but the more platforms I'm active on the longer that speech gets.

Fortunately, some of these platforms generate RSS feeds. On GitHub, RSS feeds are generated for releases, issues, and pull requests. For example, the ML.NET releases RSS feed can be accessed by appending *.atom* to the releases URL [https://github.com/dotnet/machinelearning/releases.atom](https://github.com/dotnet/machinelearning/releases.atom). Note that while Atom and RSS are not the same, they both offer a way to aggregate content. Similarly, YouTube provides the option to generate feeds for channels. For example, you can find the RSS feed to my YouTube channel at the following URL [https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCkA5fHdQ4cf3D1J19UNgV7A](https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCkA5fHdQ4cf3D1J19UNgV7A). On this blog, the RSS feed can be found at [/posts/feed.xml](/posts/feed.xml). For social media, the experience is a bit more limited since platforms like Twitter, Instagram, or Facebook don't generate RSS feeds which is unfortunate since they all have feeds of their own making them the perfect use case for RSS feeds. Platforms like Reddit provide RSS feeds to public subreddits and users by appending *.rss* at the end of the URL. For example, the RSS feed for the Zune subreddit can be found at [https://www.reddit.com/r/Zune.rss](https://www.reddit.com/r/Zune.rss). In each of these cases, though the content and platforms are different, the underlying protocol and format used is the same, RSS.

Therefore, a strategy to improve how I publish my content using RSS is, instead of sending users to the various platforms, I can provide links to the different RSS feeds for each of the platforms I'm active on in my personal site. Instead of having a long speech on the different platforms I'm active on, I can just say, "Go to my personal website at ...", and that's it! That becomes the gateway to the rest of my content. I can continue publishing on the different platforms because of the features they may provide me with for content creation and discovery, but only send users to a single place. For even more control over publishing, I can self-host videos or other content and create RSS feeds for it just like I do for my blog. In either case, users don't need to have an account in order to access and follow my content lowering the barrier to access content. This brings me to my next point of user freedom.

## User freedom using RSS

RSS provides users with the freedom to choose how they consume content. One way it does so is by being a standard protocol for aggregating content. Because there's an agreed upon set of standards, clients or RSS feed readers that consume this protocol at minimum only need to be able to read an RSS feed. Once a client can read the RSS feed, it's free to build on top of that leading to diversity and competition among the various clients. Diversity and competition is good for users because it provides choice. If I want a minimal feed reader, I can subscribe to RSS feeds using an e-mail client like [Outlook](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/subscribe-to-an-rss-feed-73c6e717-7815-4594-98e5-81fa369e951c) or [Thunderbird](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/how-subscribe-news-feeds-and-blogs). If I want more features, I can use something like NewsBlur. As an aside, one of the other things I like about NewsBlur is being provided with an e-mail address that I can use to subscribe to newsletters helping me both clear up my inbox and letting me access information in a single place. This shows how RSS readers don't have to stop at only reading RSS feeds and can build on top of the protocol while still performing their core functionality.

Another reason to use RSS is having a single place to consume almost all your content. As mentioned before, an RSS feed can aggregate content from a YouTube channel, subreddit, blog, newspaper, podcast, etc. RSS is agnostic in the sense it doesn't care what's in the feed so long as you're able to link to the content. Now, because RSS readers can read any RSS feed, it means you can follow almost all of your content from a single place so long as you're able to subscribe to the RSS feed. In fact, aside from some social media, the only other content I don't consume via RSS is podcasts. Not because I'm not able to since podcasts are usually aggregated using RSS feeds, but because I'm not able to play and sync them with other devices. Being able to consume content in a single place provides users with an incredible amount of freedom by not requiring the use of multiple apps, websites, or accounts.

One last way in which RSS gives user freedom to choose how they consume content is by giving them control of their feed. Various platforms like social media sites and YouTube generate feeds and recommend content using algorithms. These algorithms are sometimes useful by exposing you to new and diverse content. Other times, algorithms can create a bubble by reinforcing preferences and interests. In any case, there's little visibility or control into how the algorithms make choices and recommendations. RSS by default is ordered in chronological order. Therefore you know you're getting the newest content. Depending on the client, you might be able to sort content into folders in whichever way makes the most sense to you. You might also be able to choose how often the feeds you're subscribed to are checked for new content. If you don't want to get the latest updates every second, set it to update daily or weekly. If you want to get rid of the clutter and only see content from the previous day, you can automatically delete or mark older content as read. Note that all these capabilities are dependent on the client, but if this is important to you, you can choose a client that gives you these features making the possibilities endless. Finally, because you are actively choosing which feeds you subscribe to, you're not presented with content other people liked, retweeted, shared, or recommended. You only have access to the content you choose to subscribe to. If at any point you're no longer interested in the content, unsubscribe and you no longer see it on your feed.

## Conclusion

As I continue my rediscovery of RSS, I want to find ways to subscribe to content on platforms I'm already using via RSS. It's important to note that this is not an either or approach. You can subscribe to content from the various platforms using RSS to get updates in a single place and since RSS links to the original content, you can consume content on the platform itself helping content creators with more page views, likes, subscriptions, and other forms of engagement. Ultimately though, the choice is yours. A choice of how you publish and consume content. 
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom</guid>
      <pubDate>2021-04-05 19:30:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>rss</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>