<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - windowsphone</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/windowsphone</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'windowsphone' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-02-21 14:59 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 12 Mobile - Concept</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;Cool concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XhwFp6lMOcQ" title="Windows 12 Mobile Concept Video"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/XhwFp6lMOcQ/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Windows 12 Mobile Concept Video" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The likelihood of it happening is low, but there's a lot of really great opportunities here especially with &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/quick-thoughts-snapdragon-summit-2023"&gt;the new wave or ARM PCs coming&lt;/a&gt;. I don't know what the device form factor looks like, but I wouldn't mind carrying around a pocket PC - a true mobile computer. Already with the Windows Store, you have access to tons of apps. For the apps that aren't in the Store, there's the browser. That seemed to be good enough for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/vision-pros-most-important-app-safari"&gt;Apple's Vision Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Taking it a step further would the app gap matter as much if you have Copilot as your concierge orchestrating tasks for you using the various services? Better yet, what if these services had their own assistants / GPTs Copilot could talk to and coordinate on your behalf?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, I might just use &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openai-sora"&gt;OpenAI's Sora model&lt;/a&gt; to live vicariously through an AI-generated video depicting this alternate reality where Windows Phone exists...&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/windows-12-mobile-concept</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/windows-12-mobile-concept</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-21 14:59 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>windows</category>
      <category>mobile</category>
      <category>windowsphone</category>
      <category>pc</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conor McGregor pitching Zune and Windows Phone to Cristiano Ronaldo</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/amplify_video_thumb/1738661229822967808/img/nmYicHlHX6lR_pha.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Conor McGregor speaking to someone with Cristiano Ronaldo next to him" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was probably being said according to Copilot 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristiano, you need to listen to me, mate. You're wasting your time and money on those Apple products. They're overpriced, overrated, and outdated. They're nothing compared to the real champions of technology: Windows Phone and Zune. Trust me, I know what I'm talking about. I've used them both, and they're the best phone and MP3 player ever made. Let me tell you why. First of all, they had a sleek design, a smooth interface, and a unique tile system that was way ahead of its time. They were also compatible with Microsoft's ecosystem, which gave you access to Office, Xbox, and Bing. And don't get me started on the Zune Pass, which let you stream and download unlimited music for a low monthly fee. You can't beat that, mate. Second of all, they had no apps, no games, no support, and no market share. Wait, what? No, no, no, that's not a bad thing. That's a good thing. That means they were exclusive, elite, and original. They were not for the masses, they were for the class. They were not for the sheep, they were for the lions. They were not for the followers, they were for the leaders. They were not for the weak, they were for the strong. They were not for you, they were for me. And they can be for you too, if you have the courage, the vision, and the taste to switch to Windows Phone and Zune. I'm telling you, Cristiano, you're missing out on the best phone and MP3 player ever made. And I'm willing to prove it to you. I'll bet you a million euros that if you try them for a week, you'll never go back to your Apple products. What do you say? Are you man enough to take the challenge? Or are you too scared to face the truth? Come on, Cristiano, don't be a coward. Don't be a fool. Don't be a loser. Be a winner. Be a legend. Be a Windows Phone and Zune user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mcgregor-ronaldo-zune-windows-phone-meme</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mcgregor-ronaldo-zune-windows-phone-meme</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-23 20:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>windowsphone</category>
      <category>zune</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>copilot</category>
      <category>meme</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts Snapdragon Summit 2023 Addendum</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I wrote a post with some quick thoughts on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/quick-thoughts-snapdragon-summit-2023"&gt;why I'm excited for the new Snapdragon X Elite&lt;/a&gt; set of chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's something I missed which came to mind this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your Snapdragon X Elite powered computer is running Windows, and it also has calling and messaging capabilities like a phone, does that mean that you're now the proud owner of a &amp;quot;Windows Phone&amp;quot;? As a fan of Windows Phone, that sounds interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you might say, &amp;quot;Windows doesn't have all my apps&amp;quot;. Fair point but with Windows Subsystem for Android (WSA), maybe the app gap isn't much of a concern. More importantly, as I mentioned in the post, if the apps no longer become the main mode of interaction and instead are relegated to serve as background services to the AI interface, does it even matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the post, I also mentioned how I'd prefer my mobile computer runs Linux (and no, I don't mean AOSP). Even that is not a strict limitation, since I can run Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) inside Windows. So technically I can still have Linux on my mobile computer even if it's running Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see if 2024 becomes the Year of the Windows (or Linux) Phone.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/snapdragon-summit-2023-addendum</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/snapdragon-summit-2023-addendum</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-25 19:26 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>windows</category>
      <category>qualcomm</category>
      <category>windowsphone</category>
      <category>mobilecomputing</category>
      <category>arm</category>
      <category>hardware</category>
      <category>5g</category>
      <category>ai</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>