<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - work</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/work</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'work' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-03-07 21:14 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The surprising connection between after-hours work and decreased productivity</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick take: How do you spend your time at work and what is it costing you? Slack’s Workforce Index, based on survey responses from more than 10,000 desk workers around the globe, uncovers new findings on how to structure the workday to maximize productivity and strengthen employee well-being and satisfaction.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Key learnings include:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employees who log off at the end of the workday register 20% higher productivity scores than those who feel obligated to work after hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making time for breaks during the workday improves employee productivity and well-being, and yet half of all desk workers say they rarely or never take breaks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On average, desk workers say that the ideal amount of focus time is around four hours a day, and more than two hours a day in meetings is the tipping point at which a majority of workers feel overburdened by meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three out of every four desk workers report working in the 3 to 6pm timeframe, but of those, only one in four consider these hours highly productive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/surprising-connection-after-hours-work-productivity-slack</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/surprising-connection-after-hours-work-productivity-slack</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-07 21:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>slack</category>
      <category>productivity</category>
      <category>work</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>