<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - whitepaper</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/whitepaper</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'whitepaper' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-01-06 21:50 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Agents Whitepaper</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are fantastic at messy pattern recognition tasks. However, they often rely on tools - like books, Google Search, or a calculator - to supplement their prior knowledge before arriving at a conclusion. Just like humans, Generative AI models can be trained to use tools to access real-time information or suggest a real-world action. For example, a model can leverage a database retrieval tool to access specific information, like a customer's purchase history, so it can generate tailored shopping recommendations. Alternatively, based on a user's query, a model can make various API calls to send an email response to a colleague or complete a financial transaction on your behalf. To do so, the model must not only have access to a set of external tools, it needs the ability to plan and execute any task in a self- directed fashion. This combination of reasoning, logic, and access to external information that are all connected to a Generative AI model invokes the concept of an agent, or a program that extends beyond the standalone capabilities of a Generative AI model. This whitepaper dives into all these and associated aspects in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/kaggle-agents-whitepaper</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/kaggle-agents-whitepaper</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-06 21:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>agents</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>whitepaper</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>