<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - writing</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/writing</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'writing' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-02-10 17:02 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Why Blog If Nobody Reads It?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a hidden value in blogging... You do it not for the applause but because it needs doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You write because you think, because you observe, because you need to put it somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone reads it? Bonus. If not? The work still got done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💯💯💯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with many of the points in Andy's post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have analytics on my website, so I couldn't tell you who or how many people are visiting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone &lt;a href="https://malici.ous.computer/@shellsharks/statuses/01JKGDJCE0WZYAWRB816J8JFG2"&gt;links to content they found on my website and tags me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/cdn-issue-fixed-redirects-working"&gt;sends me an e-mail letting me know something on my website is broken&lt;/a&gt; is when I know there's at least one person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the content on here serves as a reminder of how I've solved problems for myself. The microposts and responses are observations that capture a moment in time. If the messages reach someone on the other end and either solve their problem or resonate with them, I'm happy that happens, but I see that as a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/why-blog-nobody-reads-andy</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/why-blog-nobody-reads-andy</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-10 17:02 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>expression</category>
      <category>creativity</category>
      <category>writing</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Affirmations for bloggers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The affirmations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I've seen and learned. Each of these will be expanded in its own section.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have things to write about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your perspective matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are good enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts don't have to be novel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will read it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are okay!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's okay to ask for things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get started quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can write on a schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgflip.com/1otri4.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Meme of man pointing at himself in the mirror" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ntietz-blogging-affirmations</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ntietz-blogging-affirmations</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-11 21:42 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Blogs</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts I jotted down on Mastodon:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs are newsletters that don’t require subscriptions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogrolls are lists of blogs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both require the lowest possible cognitive and economic overhead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That’s why they are coming back.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I know, they never left. But you get my point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/on-blogs-searls</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/on-blogs-searls</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-21 15:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogs</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>newsletters</category>
      <category>blogroll</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A blog post can be any length</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://github.com/lqdev/luisquintanilla.me/assets/11130940/d42cc57e-b882-4042-b2be-e68810105c3d" class="img-fluid" alt="A comment thread between Luis and Matt" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/26FLgGTPUDH6UGAbm/giphy.gif" class="img-fluid" alt="A GIF of a man dressed in black pointing up to blinking overhead text &amp;quot;THIS&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blog-posts-can-be-any-length-matt</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blog-posts-can-be-any-length-matt</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-07 22:37 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Gift - I want you to blog</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the gift I most want for my 40th is something everyone can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publish a post. About anything! It can be long or short, a photo or a video, maybe a quote or a link to something you found interesting. Don’t sweat it. Just blog. Share something you created, or amplify something you enjoyed. It doesn’t take much. The act of publishing will be a gift for you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it! No wrapping paper or bows. Just blogs and blogs and blogs, each unique and beautiful in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/i-want-you-to-blog-mullenweg</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/i-want-you-to-blog-mullenweg</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-03 00:16 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Year For Blogging To Pump Up The Volume</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of pontificating lately that the web is ripe for a blogging renaissance, wishing for it to be true. Much of it from people who don’t seem to notice that’s it’s already begun. Maybe they don’t anymore know quite where to look. Maybe the sorts of blogging they’re seeing isn’t what they mean. (To the blognoscenti, do things like “wordvomits” count?) If you haven’t seen it, either, that’s okay. All you have to do is choose to be a part of it. There’s never been a better time: those who managed to monopolize our attentions and keep too many of us chattering for a few hundred characters at a time to the benefit of advertisers are losing their relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not one for making personal resolutions, but let me suggest one on behalf of the blogosphere: this is the year we pump up the volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogging-pump-up-volume</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogging-pump-up-volume</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-02 18:36 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>movie</category>
      <category>radio</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plain text</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide provides an overview of plain text and how it can be used for a variety of tasks and advantages over rich text and custom text formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is plain text?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, plain text is text that isn't formatted and generally uses common characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benefits of plain text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplicity: Focus on the content rather than the formatting or medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portability: Any text editor can create and display plain text. That means you're not locked in to any particular tool or service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local-first: Because you can create plain text files using any phone or computer, it means your files belong to you and you have access to them any time regardless of network connectivity. While you can upload and sync your files with your preferred cloud storage provider for redundancy and backup, it's not a requirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longevity: Computers have been able to create and display plain text for decades. Since you don't need proprietary file formats or tools to create and consume plain text, it's likely many decades from now you'll be able to read plain text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional plain markup and text formats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write plain text on its own. However, you can format your plain text to provide additional visual cues, information, and context. Some popular plain formats and markup languages include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/worg/org-syntax.html"&gt;Org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.latex-project.org/"&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Editors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are a few popular plain text editors you can use to read and create plain text files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/"&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vim.org/"&gt;vi/vim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/"&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/9msmlrh6lzf3?hl=en-us&amp;amp;gl=US"&gt;Notepad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Note taking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to start taking notes using plain text is to open any text editor of choice and start capturing your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Productivity / Personal Knowledge Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extension to note taking is personal knowlege management and productivity. Whether it's scheduling appointments, journaling, tracking habits (exercise, reading, meditation), or managing to-do lists, you can use plain text for these tasks. Some tools and formats that can help with that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/"&gt;Emacs Org Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://todotxt.org/"&gt;todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While e-mail clients support HTML, in general e-mail communication is predomenantly text-based. Therefore, plain text is all you need. If you wanted to only use plain text, e-mail clients enable you to configure them to only support plain text. While your HTML e-mails may look weird, there are some advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://useplaintext.email/"&gt;use plaintext email guide&lt;/a&gt; can provide guidance as to how to get started using plaintext only for e-mails&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many apps for managing your personal finance. However, if you want to keep it simple, you can track your personal finances using plain text as well. Some tools that can help you do that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ledger-cli.org/"&gt;Ledger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Databases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you think of a database, you might think of a complicated system hosted in a server. While database systems are optimized for enterprise production workloads, at the end of the day, the purpose of a database is to store data. That means plain text can work for that too. Some tools that can help you here include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/recutils/"&gt;GNU Recutils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Blogging and building websites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more capable our computing devices have become, our software has suffered from inflation by becoming larger. However, larger doesn't mean the software is richer. If you're just trying to transmit information, you can upload your raw text files containing your blog posts or website to a server and they can be displayed in the browser. Examples of these sites include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://minim.blog/"&gt;minim.blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://250kb.club/"&gt;250kb club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://512kb.club/"&gt;512kb club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often you can build these websites with the help of static site generators such as. The &lt;a href="https://jamstack.org/generators/"&gt;Static Site Generators catalog&lt;/a&gt; provides more details on popular ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For hosting, you can do so for free using offerings like GitHub Pages. The &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/setting-up-a-github-pages-site-with-jekyll"&gt;Setting up a GitHub Pages site with Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; can help you get started there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://plaintext-productivity.net"&gt;Plaintext Productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://plaintextproject.online/articles.html"&gt;The Plain Text Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://doc.norang.ca/org-mode.html"&gt;Org Mode - Organize Your Life In Plain Text!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.markwk.com/plain-text-life.html"&gt;The Plain Text Life: Note Taking, Writing and Life Organization Using Plain Text Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://sive.rs/plaintext"&gt;Write plain text files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/plaintext</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/plaintext</guid>
      <pubDate>10/14/2023 12:56 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>plaintext</category>
      <category>productivity</category>
      <category>email</category>
      <category>notes</category>
      <category>personalknowledgemanagement</category>
      <category>pkm</category>
      <category>wiki</category>
      <category>calendar</category>
      <category>finance</category>
      <category>tools</category>
      <category>databases</category>
      <category>writing</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proofread articles using Microsoft Edge's Immersive Reader and read aloud</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
This will be a relatively short post but it's something I just discovered and thought I'd share. Before publishing a post, I try to proofread and review the article to make sure spelling, grammar, and flow all make sense. Part of that process involves reading the article aloud. I'll miss things from time to time but generally it works well. 

I've known about read aloud in general, but have often found voices to be robotic and sound unnatural when they encounter words outside their vocabulary. However, I recently tried out the read aloud feature in Microsoft Edge and was blown away at how natural the voice sounds and even how well it enunciates technical terms like product and programming API names. Here's what it looks like when reading one of the posts on my site.

![Microsoft Edge Immersive Reader read aloud reading blog post](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/134442715-e0af0c4a-a522-49a9-a0b1-ac658b284c68.png)

If you do any form of writing that can be displayed in Microsoft Edge, I highly encourage you to give read aloud a try. For more information, see [Use Immersive Reader in Microsoft Edge](https://support.microsoft.com/topic/use-immersive-reader-in-microsoft-edge-78a7a17d-52e1-47ee-b0ac-eff8539015e1).

Happy writing!]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/proofread-read-aloud</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/proofread-read-aloud</guid>
      <pubDate>2021-09-22 18:00:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>tools</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>