<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - community</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/community</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'community' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-08-18 18:36 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>FediUrbanism — Johanna Botari — FediCon 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this talk by &lt;a href="https://cosocial.ca/@johannab"&gt;@johannab&lt;/a&gt; on the concept of FediUrbanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://spectra.video/w/f7GBsBf3nAhF8WfTMWUEXm" title="Thumbnail of FediUrbanism Talk Recording"&gt;&lt;img src="https://spectra.video/lazy-static/previews/40a5e4bd-f8d7-438a-b35c-0c81e753ddbd.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thumbnail of FediUrbanism Talk Recording" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/fediurbanism-fedicon-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/fediurbanism-fedicon-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-18 18:36 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediurbanism</category>
      <category>fedicon2025</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>thirdspace</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IndieWeb Create Day - July 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Since it was a holiday weekend in the U.S. that kind of snuck up on me, I found myself with nothing planned on a Saturday. So I chose to spend it creating stuff for my website with the IndieWeb community during [IndieWeb Create Day](https://events.indieweb.org/2025/07/indieweb-create-day-3q2PTCbGioi9).

Over the last few months I've been overthinking my website redesign and while I've made several attempts at it, I've never been satisfied the outcome. I end up throwing away all the progress I've made and go back to the drawing board. 

Yesterday, I decided to not let perfect be the enemy of good and the approach I took was creating just a simpler piece of functionality outside of my website. How I integrate it into my website is a future me problem. But I want to work from a place of creativity and complete freedom to think of what could be rather than what is. 

With that in mind, I set out to sketch out how I want to create and render media (image, audio, video) posts. The approach I took used a combination of front-matter YAML and custom markdown media extensions. The front-matter YAML is something that I already use for my website and it's something that I want to continue using. However, in contrast to my current website, I like that the front-matter was kept simple and only includes a basic amount of information. The actual post content was handled by my custom markdown extension which leveraged YAML-like syntax to define media content. What's great about this is that it is composable so once I got one type of media working, the rest for the most part "just worked". I could even mix different media types within the same post with no additional work or code changes required. Once I had the skeleton, it was all about refactoring, documentation, adding finishing touches, and vibe-coding some CSS which Claude did a relatively good job with given the aesthetic I was going for. 

Overall, I'm happy with the end result. 

![A screenshot of a website post containing an image and audio player](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/indieweb-create-day-2025-07.png)

For more details, you can check out the [repo](https://github.com/lqdev/indieweb-create-day-2025-07).

At some point, I want to be able to integrate these media posts into my static site generator but for the time being, there are other kinds of posts such as reviews, RSVPs, and other [post types](https://indieweb.org/posts#Types_of_Posts) that I want to design and eventually also support on my website. I liked the approach I took this time around because it gave me the freedom to explore posibilities rather than constrain my creativity to what I've already built. So I think I'll keep doing the same for subsequent post types. 

At the end of the day, it was nice seeing everyone else's projects. My favorite one was Cy's recipe website. I want to be like them when I grow up 🙂.]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/indieweb-create-day-2025-07</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/indieweb-create-day-2025-07</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-07-06 20:09 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>iwc</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>website</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FediForum Day One Recap</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Just wrapped up a successful first day of FediForum.

The vibes and energy were high. Tons of great conversations and projects around the social web.

A few emerging themes I noticed:

- Identity
- Portability / Interoperability
- Feeds
- Commerce

Ian Forrester kicked us off with his Public Service &amp; The Fediverse keynote [(Slides)](https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HuQF_sI19zwByM793uvdl7BECneRmni_H9uOG-oFkdM/edit?slide=id.g420c517061_0_0#slide=id.g420c517061_0_0). 

One of the ideas that struck a chord of public service integrated into the fediverse. More specifically the interest that sparked in me was that publishing and social shouldn't be two separate things. Following the POSSE principle from the IndieWeb. You publish on your own site and then it's syndicated elsewhere. 

This was interesting enough for me I even hosted a session on the topic, I think it was called Tightening the Loop between CMS and the Fediverse. It was my first unconference, so I appreciated the way the agenda was built. Announce your topic, see whether there's interest, put it on the agenda, chat with fellow participants. Super easy.

## Identity &amp; Portability

These are such a huge topic but for the purpose of this post, I'm lumping them together.

[https://bounce-migrate.appspot.com/](https://bounce.so) is one of the projects aiming to make portability easy. What's so interesting is they're making it easy to migrate across protocols. So if you're in one network like ATProto (Bluesky), migrating to the Fediverse should be relatively seamless with https://bounce.so. 

Some great discussions that emerged on the topic as well include:

- **Reputation** - How do you build a web of trust?
- **Compartmentalization and Deduplication** - A single identity or multiple identities? When "following" someone, which of their feeds takes priority?

## Feeds

Talk of feeds was everywhere. I made a note to myself throughout the conference.

&gt; It's amazing how big the feeds theme is. Feed ownership, customization, and sharing. All powered by open protocols.

- [Bonfire releases 1.0](https://bonfirenetworks.org/posts/bonfire_social_rc/) - Congrats to the Bonfire team on this milestone. I haven't tried Bonfire myself, but the Circles feature caught my attention. It made me reminiscent of Google+.
- [Surf.Social is now in beta](https://https://surf.social) - As an avid user and curator of RSS feeds, I'd heard about Surf before but hadn't really looked into it. The beta release was announced at the conference and I quickly was able to sign up and download it. Kudos to the team on this milestone and thanks for being so responsive to my request to join the beta. I did almost no waiting in the waitlist. Once I have a chance to try it out and get familiar with it, I'll share some thoughts.
- [Channels](https://home.channel.org/) from the folks at [Newsmast Foundation](https://www.newsmastfoundation.org/) looks like an interesting way to curate and customize feeds. 
[Bring Your Own Timeline Algorithm](https://huggingface.co/spaces/mozilla-ai/byota) leverages semantic search to help you seamlessly leverage the power of algorithmic feeds but doing so under your control. Cool use of AI. 

There were a few unconference sessions on the topic as well. 

## Commerce

It was great to see folks talking about enabling creators to earn a living on open platforms and the social web. 

I believe [Bandwagon.fm](https://bandwagon.fm/home) showed of an implementation of a payments and subscription system built on top of [Emmisary](https://emissary.dev/), a social web toolkit.

## Additional Resources

Here's a list of other links and projects I was exposed to during the conference.

- [FediForum Advisory Board and Organizers](https://fediforum.org/people/)
- [An Internet of Many Autonomous Communities](https://blog.rudyfraser.com/an-internet-of-many-autonomous-communities/)
- [FediMeteo - Weather updates in your Fediverse Timeline](https://fedimeteo.com/)
- [Public Interest Technology Group (PITG)](https://pitg.network/)
- [Coalition for Content Provenance and Authenticity (C2PA)](https://c2pa.org/)
- [A New Social](https://www.anew.social/)
- [WeDistribute FediForum Live Coverage](https://wedistribute.org/2025/06/fediforum-june-2025/)
- [BBC Human Values](https://bbc.github.io/humanvalues/)
- [The Indie Beat Radio](https://theindiebeat.fm/)
- [Tie Yourself to a Federated Mastodon](https://pluralistic.net/2024/11/02/ulysses-pact/#tie-yourself-to-a-federated-mast)
- [The No Network Effect](https://snarfed.org/2013-04-13_the-no-network-effect)

As always, Cory Doctorow was great way to close out the first day. I even learned a new term, tron-pilled. Which means as a creator of a platform, you're on the side of the users.  

Looking forward to tomorrow's sessions!]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/fediforum-day-1-jun-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/fediforum-day-1-jun-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-05 17:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediforum</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources List for the Personal Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is to help guide and help those who are in every stage of their web-building journey on the personal web. This list is not meant to overwhelm you, but rather give you options and find tools, graphics, utilities, codes, and everything in between to help get you creating more on the independent web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/resource-list-personal-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/resource-list-personal-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-30 13:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>32bitcafe</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>retro</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>See you at FediForum June 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Super excited to be attending &lt;a href="https://fediforum.org/"&gt;FediForum&lt;/a&gt; in a few weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/fediforum-ticket.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Fediforum ticket showing name and event title" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/attending-fediforum-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/attending-fediforum-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-16 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediforum</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme web surfing</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This is what my browser looks like every time &lt;a href="https://shellsharks.com/"&gt;shellsharks&lt;/a&gt; drops one of their &lt;a href="https://shellsharks.com/scrolls/"&gt;scrolls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/too-many-browser-tabs.png" class="img-fluid" alt="A lot of open browser tabs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/too-many-browser-tabs-shellsharks</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/too-many-browser-tabs-shellsharks</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-10 18:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>surfing</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>blog</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bukmark Club</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BUKMARK.CLUB is a collection of websites from across the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/bukmark-club</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/bukmark-club</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 21:09 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bookmark</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>socialweb.network</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your gateway to decentralized social networking protocols, resources, and community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/socialweb-network</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/socialweb-network</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 20:49 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>decentralized</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redirect URLs working again</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the kind e-mail from &lt;a href="https://www.benji.dog/"&gt;benji.dog&lt;/a&gt;, I realized people couldn't subscribe to my RSS feeds using the links provided in the &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;/feed&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd noticed something weird had been going on for the past few days but since the rest of my site was working, I didn't pay attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I went in earlier today to fix the issue, I realized because of changes to &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/cdn/edgio-retirement-faq"&gt;Azure CDN&lt;/a&gt;, none of my redirects were working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My site kept working fine, but that's because the migration was autmatically done by Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What wasn't automatically migrated were my CDN rules which I'd set up to &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-rss-feed-links"&gt;simplify URLs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/own-your-rss-links"&gt;own my links&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/cdn-issue-fixed-redirects-working</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/cdn-issue-fixed-redirects-working</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-08 14:38 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>cdn</category>
      <category>azure</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>ownyourlinks</category>
      <category>cdn</category>
      <category>frontdoor</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attended my first IndieWeb Homebrew Website Club</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Last night I attended my &lt;a href="https://events.indieweb.org/2025/01/homebrew-website-club-pacific-V49lZfOizy1E"&gt;first IndieWeb Homebrew Website Club meeting&lt;/a&gt;. Although it was my first, everyone was very welcoming and it felt like I'd been a longtime participant. It was also great to put faces to the many websites I already follow as well as discover new people in the community. Looking forward to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/attended-first-indieweb-hwc</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/attended-first-indieweb-hwc</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-09 20:12 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starter Packs with OPML and RSS</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
One of the things I like about Bluesky is the [Starter Pack feature](https://bsky.social/about/blog/06-26-2024-starter-packs). 

In a gist, a Starter Pack is a collection of feeds. 

Bluesky users can:

- Create starter packs
- Share starter packs
- Subscribe to starter packs

Unfortunately, Starter Packs are limited to Bluesky. 

Or are they? 

As mentioned, starter packs are a collection of feeds that others can create, share, and subscribe to. 

[Bluesky supports RSS](/responses/bluesky-rss-support/), which means you could organize the feeds using an OPML file that you can share with others and others can subscribe to. The benefits of this is, you can continue to keep up with activity on Bluesky from the feed reader of your choice without being required to have an account on Bluesky. 

More importantly, because RSS and OPML are open standards, you're not limited to building starter packs for Bluesky. You can create, share, and subscribe to starter packs for any platform that supports RSS. That includes blogs, podcasts, forums, YouTube, Mastodon, etc. [Manton seems to have something similar in mind](https://www.manton.org/2024/12/07/with-the-success.html) as a means of building on open standards that make it easy for Micro.blog to interop with various platforms. 

If you're interested in what that might look like in practice, check out my "starter packs" which you can subscribe to using your RSS reader of choice and the provided OPML files. 

- [Blogs](/collections/blogroll)
- [Podcasts](/collections/podroll)
- [YouTube](/collections/youtube)
- [Forums](/collections/forums)

I'm still working on similar collections for Mastodon and Bluesky but the same concept applies.  

Although these are just simple examples, it shows the importance of building on open standards and the open web. Doing so introduces more freedom for creators and communities. 

Here are other "starter packs" you might consider subscribing to. 

- [People and Blogs](https://www.thingelstad.com/2024/12/03/people-blogs-list.html)
- [Blogroll Club](https://blogroll.club/faq/)

If this is interesting to you, [Feedland](https://feedland.org/) might be a project worth checking out.  ]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-opml-starter-packs</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-opml-starter-packs</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-08 19:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>starterpacks</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>openstandards</category>
      <category>feedland</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll Club - A blog directory</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;A Blog Directory is a cool project from &lt;a href="https://notes.jeddacp.com/"&gt;JC (Probably)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://louplummer.lol/"&gt;Lou Plummer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://blogroll.club/"&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogroll-club-blog-directory</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogroll-club-blog-directory</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-05 20:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The IndieWeb's Next Stage</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;🙋&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges I've found, even when using appliances like those from hosting providers like &lt;a href="https://www.linode.com/marketplace/apps/linode/wordpress/"&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; or tools like &lt;a href="https://yunohost.org/"&gt;YunoHost&lt;/a&gt; is connecting them to your domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, that's specific to your domain name provider and usually a manual process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases where that's easy, you're often overcharged for the convenience. Compared to &amp;quot;free&amp;quot; social media and publishing websites, it makes using your own domain a less desirable option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe advocating for a multi-staged approach like &lt;a href="https://indiewebify.me/"&gt;IndieWebify.Me&lt;/a&gt; could make the journey more approachable. More importantly, making it a journey, rather than a destination could help with meeting folks where they are and guide them closer towards their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the proposed list of goals seem like a great start towards helping people create their own place on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/indieweb-next-steps-durnell</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/indieweb-next-steps-durnell</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-25 21:54 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Services</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a site encouraging non-technical people and organisations to create their own online services such as websites, social networks, personal clouds, instant messaging etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/grow-your-own-services</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/grow-your-own-services</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 22:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>selfhosting</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>socialnetworks</category>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>online</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molly White's Blogroll</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;Bookmarking for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm already subscribed to many of these websites and publications. However, there's several new ones I found that I think will eventually make their rotation into my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/blogroll-molly-white</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/blogroll-molly-white</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-07 17:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Forums Page</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Following the patterns of a blogroll and podroll, I decided to post a &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/forums/"&gt;forums page&lt;/a&gt; to list various forums and communities I find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also created an &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/forums//index.opml"&gt;OPML file&lt;/a&gt; for it so you can subscribe to them in your RSS reader of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord is good for communities. For example on servers like Shudder there's watch parties and HuggingFace reading club gets together to discuss some of the latest papers. For events, this works really well because everyone can participate in real-time. However, I find that outside of events or general chat, it's difficult to follow the message stream. I like the forum format with topics / threads much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any forum recommendations, feel free to &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/contact"&gt;send them my way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-forums-page</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-forums-page</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-23 12:38 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>forums</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking for Discord server / community recommendations</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I finally decided to dust off my Discord. So far, I've joined several communities like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HuggingFace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LangChain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LlamaIndex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Racket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual ML.NET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shudder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ClubTwit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...and many others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've noticed that server / community discovery needs improvement, so I'm asking for your recommendations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General topics I'm interested in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.NET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F#&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fediverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lisp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Finance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retro Tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retro Gaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-mail me your recommendations at contact@lqdev.me or send me a Webmention!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/looking-for-discord-communities</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/looking-for-discord-communities</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-19 22:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>discord</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>recommendations</category>
      <category>lazyweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Online Local Chronicle</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way that every little place in America used to have a printed newspaper, every little place in America could have an online local chronicle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Broadly speaking, an online local chronicle is a collection of facts organized mostly in chronological order. The “pages” of the chronicle can be thought of as subsets of a community’s universal timeline of events. These online local chronicles could become the backbone of local news operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice project. Unfortunately, it's rare you get local news. I like publications / websites like &lt;a href="https://www.hobokengirl.com/"&gt;Hoboken Girl&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blockclubchicago.org/"&gt;Block Club Chicago&lt;/a&gt;. I wish there were more of them in more cities and towns. I know they're there in some forms like Facebook Groups. Even better, it'd be great to have the websites for these publications be the main source of truth that then syndicated their content to the various platforms out there.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/online-local-chronicle-searls</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/online-local-chronicle-searls</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-19 22:17 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>news</category>
      <category>local</category>
      <category>knowledgebase</category>
      <category>information</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky’s Stackable Approach to Moderation</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluesky was created to put users and communities in control of their social spaces online. The first generation of social media platforms connected the world, but ended up consolidating power in the hands of a few corporations and their leaders. Our online experience doesn’t have to depend on billionaires unilaterally making decisions over what we see. On an open social network like Bluesky, you can shape your experience for yourself.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Today, we’re excited to announce that we’re &lt;a href="https://github.com/bluesky-social/ozone"&gt;open-sourcing Ozone&lt;/a&gt;, our collaborative moderation tool. With Ozone, individuals and teams can work together to review and label content across the network. Later this week, we’re opening up the ability for you to run your own independent moderation services, seamlessly integrated into the Bluesky app. This means that you'll be able to create and subscribe to additional moderation services on top of what Bluesky requires, giving you unprecedented control over your social media experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bluesky-stackable-approach-moderation</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bluesky-stackable-approach-moderation</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-15 20:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>moderation</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>atprotocol</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky: An Open Social Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to announce that the Bluesky network is federating and opening up in a way that allows you to host your own data. What does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your data, such as your posts, likes, and follows, needs to be stored somewhere. With traditional social media, your data is stored by the social media company whose services you've signed up for. If you ever want to stop using that company's services, you can do that—but you would have to leave that social network and lose your existing connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't have to be this way! An alternative model is how the internet itself works. Anyone can put up a website on the internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think social media should work the same way. When you register on Bluesky, by default we'll suggest that Bluesky will store your data. But if you'd like to let another company store it, or even store it yourself, you can do that. You'll also be able to change your mind at any point, moving your data to another provider without losing any of your existing posts, likes, or follows. From your followers' perspective, your profile is always available at your handle—no matter where your information is actually stored, or how many times it has been moved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't spend a lot of time on Bluesky, but I love what they're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsky.social/about/blog/02-06-2024-join-bluesky"&gt;Made their service generally available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have over &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/bsky.app/post/3klzrudt4uk2z"&gt;5 million users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bluesky-rss-support/"&gt;Support RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can self-host your data. I'm excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other piece of this that's interesting is their feature which enables you to &lt;a href="https://bsky.social/about/blog/7-05-2023-namecheap"&gt;use your domain as a custom handle&lt;/a&gt;. Not only is your identity portable, but also your data. I'd be interested to see how this works in practice given you can already do some of this on the Fediverse on platforms like Mastodon. ... identity component to me is crucial. That's one of the challenges with Mastodon today. While you can move instances, your identity changes and while most of your data comes with you, there's tihngs that still dont transfer over. The other part that I'd be interested in seeing is whether or not they can be efficient in the storage of federated data. One of the challenges with Mastodon is, your server quickly fills up because of data from other instances (when you federate). &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/mastodon-4-1-0-release"&gt;It's gotten better&lt;/a&gt;, but this is an area I spend most of my time when maintaining my own self-hosted instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to tinker and self-host my own data. Maybe I'll also &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps"&gt;syndicate to Bluesky just like I do with Mastodon today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you can find me on Bluesky &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/bluesky"&gt;@lqdev.me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bluesky-open-social-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bluesky-open-social-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-22 21:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>