<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - signal</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/signal</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'signal' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-02-20 17:01 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Keep your phone number private with Signal usernames</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal’s mission and sole focus is private communication. For years, Signal has kept your messages private, your profile information (like your name and profile photo) private, your contacts private, and your groups private – among much else. Now we’re taking that one step further, by making your phone number on Signal more private.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Here’s how:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
New default: Your phone number will no longer be visible to everyone in Signal...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Connect without sharing your phone number...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Control who can find you on Signal by phone number...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Right now, these options are in beta, and will be rolling out to everyone in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/signal-usernames</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/signal-usernames</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-20 17:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>signal</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>osint</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s how WhatsApp plans to interoperate with other messaging apps</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp, like many other major tech platforms, will have to make some significant changes to comply with the European Union’s Digital Markets Act (DMA). One of those changes is interoperability with other messaging platforms...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift toward interoperability will first include text messages, images, voice messages, videos, and files sent from one person to another. In theory, this would allow users to chat with people on WhatsApp through third-party apps, like iMessage, Telegram, Google Messages, and Signal, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted by Wired, WhatsApp wants the messaging services it connects with to use the same Signal Protocol to encrypt messages. Meta is also open to apps using alternate encryption protocols so long as companies can prove “they reach the security standards that WhatsApp outlines in its guidance.” The third-party services will also have to sign a contract with Meta before they plug into WhatsApp, with more details about the agreement coming in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-whatsapp-plans-interoperate-other-messaging-services</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-whatsapp-plans-interoperate-other-messaging-services</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-06 20:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>whatsapp</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interoperability</category>
      <category>signal</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>