<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - newsletter</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/newsletter</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'newsletter' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-05-27 19:44 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>How do I keep up with AI?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
This question comes up a lot in conversations. The short answer? I don’t. There’s just too much happening, too fast, for anyone to stay on top of everything.

While I enjoy sharing links and recommendations, I realized that a blog post might be more helpful. It gives folks a single place they can bookmark, share, and come back to on their own time, rather than having to dig through message threads where things inevitably get lost.

That said, here are some sources I use to try and stay informed:

- **Newsletters** are great for curated content. They highlight the top stories and help filter through the noise.
- **Blogs** are often the primary sources behind those newsletters. They go deeper and often cover a broader set of topics that might not make it into curated roundups.
- **Podcasts** serve a similar role. In some cases, they provide curation like newsletters and deep dives like blogs in others. Best of all, you can tune in while on the go making it a hands-free activity.

For your convenience, if any of the sources (including podcasts) I list below have RSS feeds, I’ve included them in my [AI Starter Pack](/collections/starter-packs//ai), which you can [download and import into your favorite RSS reader](/collections/starter-packs//ai/index.opml) (as long as it supports OPML file imports).

If you have some sources to share, [send me an e-mail](/contact). I'd love to keep adding to this list! If they have a feed I can subscribe to, even better.

## Newsletters

- [AlphaSignal](https://alphasignal.ai/)
- [The Batch](https://www.deeplearning.ai/the-batch/)
- [Latent Space](https://www.latent.space/)
- [TLDR AI](https://tldr.tech/ai)

## Blogs

I pride myself on being able to track down an RSS feed on just about any website, even if it’s buried or not immediately visible. Unfortunately, I haven't found a feed URL for either OpenAI or Anthropic which is annoying. 

**OpenAI and Anthropic, if you could do everyone a favor and drop a link, that would be great.** 

UPDATE: Thanks to [@m2vh@mastodontech.de](https://toot.lqdev.tech/@m2vh@mastodontech.de) for sharing the OpenAI news feed. 

I know I could use one of those web-page-to-RSS converters, but I'd much rather have an official link directly from the source.

- [OpenAI](https://openai.com/news/)
- [Anthropic](https://www.anthropic.com/news)
- [Google AI Blog](https://blog.google/technology/ai/)
- [AWS Machine Learning Blog](https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/)
- [Microsoft Research](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/)
- [Google Research](https://research.google/blog/)
- [Simon Willison](https://simonwillison.net/)

## Podcasts

- [AI Daily Brief](https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/the-ai-daily-brief-formerly-th-5260567)
- [TWIML AI Podcast](https://twimlai.com/)
- [Practical AI](https://changelog.com/practicalai)

## Subscribing to feeds

Now that I’ve got you here...

Let’s talk about the best way to access all these feeds. My preferred and recommended approach is using a feed reader.

When subscribing to content on the open web, feed readers are your secret weapon.

RSS might seem like it’s dead (it’s not—yet). In fact, it’s the reason you often hear the phrase, “Wherever you get your podcasts.” But RSS goes beyond podcasts. It’s widely supported by blogs, newsletters, and even social platforms like the Fediverse (Mastodon, PeerTube, etc.) and BlueSky. It’s also how I’m able to compile my [starter packs](/collections/starter-packs/). 

I've written more about RSS in [Rediscovering the RSS Protocol](/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom), but the short version is this: when you build on open standards like RSS and OPML, you’re building on freedom. Freedom to use the tools that work best for you. Freedom to own your experience. And freedom to support a healthier, more independent web.
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-i-keep-up-with-ai</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-i-keep-up-with-ai</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-27 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>starterpack</category>
      <category>newsletter</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every - Daily Newsletter</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every is a daily newsletter founded in 2020. Every day, we publish a long-form essay to make you smarter about technology, productivity, and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/every-newsletter</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/every-newsletter</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 11:08 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>newsletter</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>productivity</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>essay</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Kings of Open Source AI (Oct 2023 Recap)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistral 7B, released at the tail end of Sept 2023, is both Apache 2.0 and smaller but better than Llama 2, and is now rumored to be raising $400m at $2.5b valuation from a16z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/new-kings-open-source-ai</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/new-kings-open-source-ai</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-11 19:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>newsletter</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>