<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - messaging</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/messaging</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'messaging' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-04-25 22:53 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Services</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a site encouraging non-technical people and organisations to create their own online services such as websites, social networks, personal clouds, instant messaging etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/grow-your-own-services</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/grow-your-own-services</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 22:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>selfhosting</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>socialnetworks</category>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>online</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beeper was just acquired by Automattic</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beeper, the upstart messaging app that attempts to corral all your messaging services into one inbox, is being acquired by Automattic, the giant that runs Wordpress.com, Tumblr, and a number of other hugely popular web properties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exciting especially given some of the recent developments in the EU. What's most interesting to me is how Beeper leverages open protocols like Matrix and for bridging capabilities where possible to provide secure messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more people moving to smaller spaces to communicate with their communities, being able to do so in a single place without everyone being on the same platform like in the early days of the internet is a welcome development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional coverage from the &lt;a href="https://blog.beeper.com/2024/04/09/beeper-is-now-available/"&gt;Beeper blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we’re announcing today…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more waitlist – Beeper is now available to everyone!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beeper has been acquired by Automattic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our new Android app is out of beta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re renaming Beeper Cloud → Beeper (sorry for the confusion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and &lt;a href="https://ma.tt/2024/04/beeper-texts/"&gt;Matt Mullenweg's blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the announcement went out that we’re combining the best technology from Beeper and Texts to create a great private, secure, and open source messaging client for people to have control of their communications. We’re going to use the Beeper brand, because it’s fun. This is not unlike how browsers have evolved, where solid tech and encryption on top of an open ecosystem has created untold value for humanity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A lot of people are asking about iMessage on Android… I have zero interest in fighting with Apple, I think instead it’s best to focus on messaging networks that want more engagement from power-user clients. This is an area I’m excited to work on when I return from my sabbatical next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/beeper-acquired-automattic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/beeper-acquired-automattic</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-09 22:06 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>beeper</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>matrix</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep your phone number private with Signal usernames</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal’s mission and sole focus is private communication. For years, Signal has kept your messages private, your profile information (like your name and profile photo) private, your contacts private, and your groups private – among much else. Now we’re taking that one step further, by making your phone number on Signal more private.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Here’s how:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
New default: Your phone number will no longer be visible to everyone in Signal...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Connect without sharing your phone number...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Control who can find you on Signal by phone number...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Right now, these options are in beta, and will be rolling out to everyone in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/signal-usernames</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/signal-usernames</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-20 17:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>signal</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>osint</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s how WhatsApp plans to interoperate with other messaging apps</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp, like many other major tech platforms, will have to make some significant changes to comply with the European Union’s Digital Markets Act (DMA). One of those changes is interoperability with other messaging platforms...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift toward interoperability will first include text messages, images, voice messages, videos, and files sent from one person to another. In theory, this would allow users to chat with people on WhatsApp through third-party apps, like iMessage, Telegram, Google Messages, and Signal, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted by Wired, WhatsApp wants the messaging services it connects with to use the same Signal Protocol to encrypt messages. Meta is also open to apps using alternate encryption protocols so long as companies can prove “they reach the security standards that WhatsApp outlines in its guidance.” The third-party services will also have to sign a contract with Meta before they plug into WhatsApp, with more details about the agreement coming in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-whatsapp-plans-interoperate-other-messaging-services</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-whatsapp-plans-interoperate-other-messaging-services</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-06 20:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>whatsapp</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interoperability</category>
      <category>signal</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private social media?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Brain dumping a bunch of half-formed thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, I've been thinking about different forms of sharing content. With the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/19/technology/personaltech/tiktok-twitter-facebook-social.html"&gt;shifts in social media towards smaller, more private communities&lt;/a&gt;, is it possible to get the best of feeds for sharing updates and information but in a smaller more intimate way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a few of the options I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://dayoneapp.com/guides/tips-and-tutorials/shared-journals/"&gt;Day One Shared Journals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made for an audience of one, but other can collaborate on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the interface, looking back at specific days and events that took place is easy to look back on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May be able to include different forms of media (i.e. audio, video, photos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No individual profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require everyone to use the same app / service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;E-mail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Newsletters, Mailing lists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost everyone has an e-mail address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on standard protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Producers can use any app they'd like to compose e-mails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers can use any app they'd like to read e-mails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could use any app / client / service-provider they'd like. (Federated by default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content rendering may differ based on app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could add to the noise already present in your e-mail inbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No individual accounts / feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Messaging Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Discord, Matrix, IRC, Slack, Signal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing could be done via SMS (though this would limit the content you share).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could form various sub-groups to sub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require everyone to use the same app / service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May not have a way to view individual profiles or feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because conversations are not often grouped by topics, it might be difficult to find conversations, especially older conversations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Private blogs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com/go/tutorials/private-blog-wordpress-com/"&gt;Private WordPress Blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://havenweb.org/"&gt;Haven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produces can use any tool / service to author and publish posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers can access via any browser of their choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May have to host your own service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers may have to create accounts and passwords for each of the private blogs they follow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fediverse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Mastodon, PixelFed, PeerTube&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familar social media interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More availability of apps and services that form part of the Fediverse make it easier for producers and consumers to use what makes the most sense for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited to the format supported by the app / service (i.e. Pixelfed is for images / video, PeerTube for video, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require you to host your own service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;P2P Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://scuttlebutt.nz/"&gt;ScuttleButt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could be made for an audience of one but shared with other peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentralized by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access individual feeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similar to the Fediverse, being exposed to new protocols and technical terms may make onboarding and adoption challenging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May require you to host your own service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocols haven't been widely adopted so users are limited in the apps / services they can use for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forums&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://discourse.nixos.org/"&gt;NixOS Forum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lemmy.world/"&gt;Lemmy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could create threads and conversations on various topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to search and tag content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone would have to host a server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might not work well for small groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a variation on the private blog. Except instead of having a website that displays the posts, you just have an RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: &lt;a href="https://daverupert.com/2018/01/welcome-to-rss-club/"&gt;RSS-Only Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Producers can use any software they'd like to create and publish their RSS feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consumers can use any feed reader to access and read content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone could have their own feed, so effectively they'd be like profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to figure out how to produce and host the RSS feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can't really control who sees this since the feed is public. Maybe private feeds could help here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited interaction. Users can't comment or reply to items in a feed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this is not an exhaustive list of pros and cons, just a few that I thought of. I persoanlly would skew towards e-mail and messaging apps. The main reason at least with e-mail is that everyone is familiar with it and most likely won't have to create separate accounts on various silos to communicate and engage with others. With apps like &lt;a href="https://delta.chat/"&gt;DeltaChat&lt;/a&gt; you could actualy combine them and get the best of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/private-social-media</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/private-social-media</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-22 21:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>private</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>forums</category>
      <category>journal</category>
      <category>e-mail</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texts Joins Automattic</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using an all-in-one messaging app is a real game-changer for productivity and keeping up with things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is obviously a tricky area to navigate, as in the past the networks have blocked third-party clients, but I think with the current anti-trust and regulatory environments this is actually something the big networks will appreciate: it maintains the same security as their clients, opens them up in a way consumers will love and is very user-centric, and because we’re committed to supporting all their features it can actually increase engagement and usage of their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can relate to the feeling of wanting to have one inbox expressed in the video. Coincidentally, I've been playing with &lt;a href="https://delta.chat/"&gt;Delta Chat&lt;/a&gt; and by building on top of e-mail, some of the issues with the siloed platforms are alleviated. Also, &lt;a href="https://www.emailisnotdead.com/"&gt;e-mail isn't dead&lt;/a&gt; and despite some of its shortcomings, it's still broadly used to sign up and sign into platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/texts-joins-automattic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/texts-joins-automattic</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-24 17:13 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interop</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automattic is acquiring Texts and betting big on the future of messaging</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I'm really liking the recent acquisitions from Automattic. I'm just starting to use Day One and really enjoy it. Pocket Casts is a fantastic podcast app, though I prefer to use AntennaPod. WordPress is also starting to make it easy to plug into the Fediverse using your blog. I'm excited for Texts and what that might offer in the current siloed messaging landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automattic, the company that runs WordPress.com, Tumblr, Pocket Casts, and a number of other popular web properties, just made a different kind of acquisition: it’s buying Texts, a universal messaging app, for $50 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texts is an app for all your messaging apps. You can use it to log in to WhatsApp, Instagram, LinkedIn, Signal, iMessage, and more and see and respond to all your messages in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...Mullenweg says he’s bullish on solutions like Matrix, which offers a decentralized and open-source messaging network, and other up-and-coming standards for messaging. He’s already thinking about how Texts might gently nudge people toward more open protocols over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mullenweg and Automattic see a big future for messaging, as more online interaction shifts away from public-first social networks and toward things like group chats. Hardly anyone has figured out how to build a meaningful and sustainable business from chat, but Mullenweg thinks it’s possible. And he thinks it starts with making your messaging a little less messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/automattic-acquires-texts-messaging</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/automattic-acquires-texts-messaging</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-24 09:16 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interop</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix 2.0: The Future of Matrix</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: If you want to play with a shiny new Matrix 2.0 client, head over to &lt;a href="https://element.io/blog/element-x-ignition/"&gt;Element X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/matrix-2-0</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/matrix-2-0</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-22 10:10 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>communication</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking trust in direct messages in the AI era</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a part of a series exploring our research in privacy, security, and cryptography. For the previous post, see &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/research-trends-in-privacy-security-and-cryptography"&gt;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/research-trends-in-privacy-security-and-cryptography&lt;/a&gt;. While AI has the potential to massively increase productivity, this power can be used equally well for malicious purposes, for example, to automate the creation of sophisticated scam messages. In this post, we explore threats AI can pose for online communication ecosystems and outline a high-level approach to mitigating these threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/rethinking-trust-dm-ai-era</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/rethinking-trust-dm-ai-era</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-06 00:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>cryptography</category>
      <category>communication</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>trust</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Synapse REALLY needs an Admin UI</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Spent the day playing sysadmin and removed about 50GB worth of data from my Matrix Synapse instance. Like Mastodon, most of that data wasn't even mine. Most of it comes is remote data from other users in large rooms. I really like Matrix and the ability to host my own messaging server that provides end-to-end encryption as well as federation with other instances. However, not having a straight-forward way of managing my server and cleaning up resources is painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if anyone is interested, here are some resources that have helped me in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/matrix-synapse-admin"&gt;Matrix Synapse Server Administration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/matrix-synapse-needs-admin-ui</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/matrix-synapse-needs-admin-ui</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-06-11 21:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>synapse</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>sysadmin</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Synapse Server Administration</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a guide for managing &lt;a href="https://github.com/matrix-org/synapse"&gt;Matrix Synapse&lt;/a&gt; servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize Python virtual environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;source env/bin/activate
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop server&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;synctl stop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upgrade Synapse package&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;pip install --upgrade matrix-synapse[postgres]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Restart server&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;synctl restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deactivate Python virtual environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;deactivate
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;curl http://localhost:8008/_synapse/admin/v1/server_version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clean up storage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Delete old media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to clean local meadia older than 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;curl -X POST -H &amp;quot;Authorization: Bearer access_token&amp;quot; http://localhost:8008/_synapse/admin/v1/media/delete?before_ts=$(date +%s000 --date &amp;quot;30 days ago&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start PSQL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;psql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connect to database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sql"&gt;\c synapse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean up unreferenced itemes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;VACUUM FULL;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Delete items in database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start PSQL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;psql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connect to database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sql"&gt;\c synapse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the following SQL script&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sql"&gt;DROP FUNCTION IF EXISTS synapse_clean_redacted_messages();
CREATE FUNCTION synapse_clean_redacted_messages()
    RETURNS void AS $$
    DECLARE
    BEGIN
        UPDATE events SET content = '{}' FROM redactions AS rdc
            WHERE events.event_id = rdc.redacts
            AND (events.type = 'm.room.encrypted' OR events.type = 'm.room.message');
    END;
$$ LANGUAGE 'plpgsql';

DROP FUNCTION IF EXISTS synapse_get_server_name();
CREATE FUNCTION synapse_get_server_name()
    RETURNS text AS $$
    DECLARE
        _someUser TEXT;
        _serverName TEXT;
    BEGIN
        select user_id from account_data limit 1 INTO _someUser;
        select regexp_replace(_someUser, '^.*:', ':') INTO _serverName;
        RETURN _serverName;
    END;
$$ LANGUAGE 'plpgsql';

DROP FUNCTION IF EXISTS synapse_get_unused_rooms();
CREATE FUNCTION synapse_get_unused_rooms()
    RETURNS TABLE(room_id TEXT) AS $$
    DECLARE
    BEGIN
        RETURN QUERY SELECT r.room_id FROM rooms AS r WHERE r.room_id NOT IN (
            SELECT DISTINCT(m.room_id) FROM room_memberships as m
                INNER JOIN current_state_events as c
                ON m.event_id = c.event_id
                AND m.room_id = c.room_id
                AND m.user_id = c.state_key
                WHERE c.type = 'm.room.member'
                AND m.membership = 'join'
                AND m.user_id LIKE concat('%', synapse_get_server_name())
        );
    END;
$$ LANGUAGE 'plpgsql';

DROP FUNCTION IF EXISTS synapse_clean_unused_rooms();
CREATE FUNCTION synapse_clean_unused_rooms()
    RETURNS void AS $$
    DECLARE
        _count INT;
    BEGIN
        CREATE TEMP TABLE synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp
            ON COMMIT DROP
            AS SELECT room_id FROM synapse_get_unused_rooms();

        SELECT COUNT(*) FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp INTO _count;
        RAISE NOTICE 'synapse_clean_unused_rooms() Cleaning up % unused rooms', _count;

        DELETE FROM event_forward_extremities AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_forward_extremities';

        DELETE FROM event_backward_extremities AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_backward_extremities';

        DELETE FROM event_edges AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_edges';

        DELETE FROM room_depth AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: room_depth';

        DELETE FROM events AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: events';

        DELETE FROM event_json AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_json';

        DELETE FROM state_events AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: state_events';

        DELETE FROM current_state_events AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: current_state_events';

        DELETE FROM room_memberships AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: room_memberships';

        DELETE FROM destination_rooms AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: destination_rooms';

        DELETE FROM event_failed_pull_attempts AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_failed_pull_attempts';

        DELETE FROM rooms AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: rooms';

        DELETE FROM room_aliases AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: room_aliases';

        DELETE FROM state_groups AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: state_groups';

        DELETE FROM state_groups_state AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: state_groups_state';

        DELETE FROM receipts_graph AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: receipts_graph';

        DELETE FROM receipts_linearized AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: receipts_linearized';

        DELETE FROM room_tags AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: room_tags';

        DELETE FROM room_tags_revisions AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: room_tags_revisions';

        DELETE FROM room_account_data AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: room_account_data';

        DELETE FROM event_push_actions AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_push_actions';

        DELETE FROM pusher_throttle AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: pusher_throttle';

        DELETE FROM event_reports AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_reports';

        DELETE FROM stream_ordering_to_exterm AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: stream_ordering_to_exterm';

        DELETE FROM event_auth AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: event_auth';

        DELETE FROM appservice_room_list AS x WHERE x.room_id IN (SELECT y.room_id FROM synapse_clean_unused_rooms__tmp AS y);
        RAISE NOTICE 'DONE: appservice_room_list';
    END;
$$ LANGUAGE 'plpgsql';

SELECT synapse_clean_redacted_messages();
SELECT synapse_clean_unused_rooms();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean up unreferenced tuples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sql"&gt;VACUUM FULL;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://matrix-org.github.io/synapse/latest/welcome_and_overview.html"&gt;Matrix Synapse Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://matrix-org.github.io/synapse/latest/upgrade.html"&gt;Upgrading Synapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://matrix-org.github.io/synapse/v1.38/admin_api/media_admin_api.html"&gt;Admin Media API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/xwiki-labs/synapse_scripts"&gt;Synapse Scripts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/matrix-synapse-admin</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/matrix-synapse-admin</guid>
      <pubDate>06/11/2023 21:13 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>how-to</category>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>self-host</category>
      <category>synapse</category>
      <category>sql</category>
      <category>python</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Jami username</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I got a reminder on the importance of backups last night. New Jami username is lqdev1. Fortunately I wasn't as active on there so not a big deal to lose my original username.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-jami-username</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-jami-username</guid>
      <pubDate>11/19/2021 10:37 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>jami</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>gnu</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Success! Matrix migration complete</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;It only took 6 hours but I was able to get it done with a little help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/mIZ9rPeMKefm0/giphy.gif" class="img-fluid" alt="Bender from Futurama happy dance" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/matrix-migration-complete</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/matrix-migration-complete</guid>
      <pubDate>10/09/2021 12:23 AM -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>element</category>
      <category>synapse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of Skype</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;For personal use, I tend to default to Skype for my video / audio call needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great to see there are some long-term plans for the app and it'll be around for a while more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.skype.com/en/blogs/2021-08-announcement-modern-skype/"&gt;The future of Skype: Fast, playful, delightful and buttery smooth​&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/skype-future-annoucement-09-2021</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/skype-future-annoucement-09-2021</guid>
      <pubDate>10/01/2021 4:20 PM -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>skype</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>microsoft</category>
      <category>roadmap</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>