<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - decentralization</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/decentralization</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'decentralization' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-05-10 20:47 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Distributed.Press Social Inbox 1.0</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I hadn't heard of &lt;a href="https://distributed.press/"&gt;Distributed Press&lt;/a&gt; and this is an older post (from 2023), but the idea is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypha and Sutty are thrilled to announce the release of the Social Inbox, a new feature of Distributed.Press that integrates a website’s comment section with federated social media platforms like Mastodon. With the Social Inbox enabled, websites obtain their own account on the Fediverse, allowing it to automatically send out new posts to followers at the time of publication. When other users reply to posts, you can approve them to be published to the site as comments. The Social Inbox allows readers to directly engage with your posts where they already are, and gives publishers the ability to incorporate public dialogue into their websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/announcing-distributed-press-social-inbox</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/announcing-distributed-press-social-inbox</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-10 20:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>dweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Links</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperlinks deserve more recognition in light of all the ways their value has been sidelined and denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, I present a link compilation in praise of links. It includes things I agree with entirely and things I don't, spanning from the 2020s to the early 2000s, to supply a tapestry of perspectives, context, and examples on the value and importance of links. Links may have their downsides, challenges, and vulnerabilities, but my hope is that this compilation will (re)invigorate your appreciation for linking as a technology and a social practice, all the better to understand what's at stake when links are discarded and devalued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/in-praise-of-links-osteophage</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/in-praise-of-links-osteophage</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 21:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe-Specing - From concepts to specification</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

Code generation is a common use case for AI. What about the design process that comes before implementation? Personally, I've found that AI excels not just at coding, but also helping formalize abstract ideas into concrete specifications. This post explores how I used AI-assisted design to transform a collection of loosely related concepts into a technical specification for a new system made up of those concepts.

## Specifications

Generally, I've had mixed success with vibe-coding (the practice of describing what you want in natural language and having AI generate the corresponding code). However, it's something that I'm constantly working on getting better at. Also, with tooling integrations like MCP, I can ground responses and supplement my prompts using external data.

What I find myself being more successful with is using AI to explore ideas and then formalizing those ideas into a specification. Even in the case of vibe-coding, what you're doing with your prompts is building a specification in real-time. 

I'd like to think that eventually I'll get to the vibe-coding part but before diving straight into the code, I'd like to spend time in the design phase. Personally, this is also the part that I find the most fun because you can throw wild things at the wall. It's not until you implement them that you actually validate whether some of those wild ideas are practical. But I find the design phase a ton of fun.

The result of my latest vibe-specing adventure is what I'm calling the [InterPlanetary Knowledge System (IPKS)](https://github.com/lqdev/IPKS).

## From concept to specification

Lately, I've been thinking a lot about knowledge. Some concepts that have been in my head are those of **non-linear publishing** (creating content that can be accessed in any order with multiple entry points, like wikis or hypertext) and **distributed cognition** (the idea that human knowledge and cognitive processes extend beyond the individual mind to include interactions with other people, tools, and environments).
Related to those concepts, I've also been thinking about how **digital gardens** (personal knowledge bases that blend note-taking, blogging, and knowledge management in a non-linear format) and **Zettelkasten** (a method of note-taking where ideas are captured as atomic notes with unique identifiers and explicit connections) are ways to capture and organize knowledge.

One other thing that I'm amazed by is the powerful concept of a **hyperlink** and how it makes the web open, decentralized, and interoperable. When paired with the **semantic web** (an extension of the web that provides a common framework for data to be shared across applications and enterprises), you have yourself a decentralized knowledgebase containing a lot of the world's knowledge.

At some point, IPFS (InterPlanetary File System, a protocol designed to create a permanent and decentralized method of storing and sharing files) joined this pool of concepts I had in my head.

These were all interesting concepts individually, but I knew there were connections but couldn't cohesively bring them together. That's where AI-assisted specification design came in.

Below is a summary of the collaborative design interaction with Claude Sonnet 3.7 (with web search) that eventually led to the generation of the IPKS specifications. I haven't combed through them in great detail, but what they're proposing seems plausible. 

Overall, I'm fascinated by this interaction. Whether or not IPKS ever becomes a reality, the process of using AI to transform abstract concepts into concrete specifications seems like a valuable and fun design approach that I'll continue to refine and include as part of my vibe-coding sessions. 

---

## Initial Exploration: IPFS and Knowledge Management

Our conversation began with exploring IPFS (InterPlanetary File System) and its fundamental capabilities as a content-addressed, distributed file system. We recognized that while IPFS excels at storing and retrieving files in a decentralized manner, it needed extensions to support knowledge representation, trust, and semantics.

Key insights from this stage:
- IPFS provides an excellent foundation with content addressing through CIDs
- Content addressing enables verification but doesn't inherently provide meaning
- Moving from document-centric to idea-centric systems requires additional layers

## Knowledge Management Concepts

We explored established knowledge management approaches, particularly:

### Zettelkasten
The Zettelkasten method contributed these important principles:
- Atomic units of knowledge (one idea per note)
- Explicit connections between ideas
- Unique identifiers for each knowledge unit
- Emergent structure through relationship networks

### Digital Gardens
The Digital Garden concept provided these insights:
- Knowledge in various stages of development
- Non-linear organization prioritizing connections
- Evolution of ideas over time
- Public visibility of work-in-progress thinking

These personal knowledge management approaches helped us envision how similar principles could work at scale in a distributed system.

## The "K" in IPKS

When we proposed replacing "IPFS" with "IPKS" (changing File → Knowledge), we recognized the need to define what makes knowledge different from files. This led to identifying several key requirements:

1. **Semantic meaning** - Knowledge needs explicit relationships and context
2. **Provenance and trust** - Knowledge requires verifiable sources and expertise
3. **Evolution** - Knowledge changes over time while maintaining continuity
4. **Governance** - Knowledge exists in various trust and privacy contexts

These requirements shaped the layered architecture of the specifications.

## Distributed Cognition and Non-Linear Publishing

Our discussions about distributed cognition highlighted how thinking processes extend beyond individual minds to include:
- Interactions with other people
- Cultural artifacts and tools
- Physical and digital environments
- Social and technological systems

This concept directly influenced the IPKS design by emphasizing:
- Knowledge as a collective, distributed resource
- The need for attribution and expertise verification
- The value of connecting knowledge across boundaries
- The role of tools in extending human cognition

Similarly, non-linear publishing concepts shaped how we approached knowledge relationships and navigation in IPKS, moving away from sequential formats toward interconnected networks of information.

## Web3 Technologies Integration

Our exploration of complementary technologies led to incorporating:

### Decentralized Identifiers (DIDs)
DIDs provided the framework for:
- Self-sovereign identity for knowledge contributors
- Cryptographic verification of authorship
- Persistent identification across systems
- Privacy-preserving selective disclosure

### Verifiable Credentials (VCs)
Verifiable Credentials offered mechanisms for:
- Expertise validation without central authorities
- Domain-specific qualification verification
- Credential-based access control
- Trust frameworks for knowledge contributors

### Semantic Web (RDF/OWL)
Semantic Web standards influenced:
- Relationship types between knowledge nodes
- Ontologies for domain knowledge representation
- Query patterns for knowledge discovery
- Interoperability with existing knowledge systems

## Business Context: Supply Chain Example

Our conversation about supply chain management provided a concrete use case that helped ground the specifications in practical application. This example demonstrated how IPKS could address real-world challenges:

- **Material Provenance**: Using DIDs and verifiable credentials to establish trusted material sources
- **Cross-Organization Collaboration**: Enabling knowledge sharing while respecting organizational boundaries
- **Regulatory Compliance**: Creating verifiable documentation of compliance requirements
- **Expertise Validation**: Ensuring contributors have appropriate qualifications for their roles
- **Selective Disclosure**: Balancing transparency with competitive confidentiality

This business context helped shape the Access Control &amp; Privacy specification in particular, highlighting the need for nuanced governance models.

## Technical Implementation Considerations

As we moved from abstract concepts to specifications, several technical considerations emerged:

1. **Building on IPLD**: Recognizing that InterPlanetary Linked Data (IPLD) already provided foundational components for structured, linked data in content-addressed systems

2. **Modular Specification Design**: Choosing to create multiple specifications rather than a monolithic standard to enable incremental implementation and adoption

3. **Backward Compatibility**: Ensuring IPKS could work with existing IPFS/IPLD infrastructure

4. **Extensibility**: Designing for future enhancements like AI integration, advanced semantic capabilities, and cross-domain knowledge mapping

## The Path Forward

The IPKS specifications represent a synthesis of our conceptual exploration, grounded in:
- Established knowledge management practices
- Decentralized web technologies
- Real-world business requirements
- Technical feasibility considerations

Moving from concept to implementation will require:
1. Reference implementations of the core specifications
2. Developer tools and libraries to simplify adoption
3. Domain-specific extensions for particular use cases
4. Community building around open standards

By building on the combined strengths of IPFS, DIDs, VCs, and semantic web technologies, IPKS creates a framework for distributed knowledge that balances openness with trust, flexibility with verification, and collaboration with governance.
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/vibe-specing-prompt-to-spec</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/vibe-specing-prompt-to-spec</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-06 20:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>dweb</category>
      <category>standards</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>protocol</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Element Desktop on Windows ARM64 Devices</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In a previous post, I talked about my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/running-linux-gui-apps-windows-wsl-amazing"&gt;workaround for running Element Desktop on my ARM64 Windows device&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm happy that I no longer need that workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/element-hq/element-desktop"&gt;Element Desktop&lt;/a&gt; enabled support for &lt;a href="https://github.com/element-hq/element-desktop/pull/624"&gt;ARM64 on Windows&lt;/a&gt; and shipped it as part of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/element-hq/element-desktop/releases/tag/v1.11.95"&gt;1.11.95 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you could go to the &lt;a href="https://element.io/download"&gt;downloads website&lt;/a&gt; and get the installer from there, you can now also get it via &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/windows/package-manager/winget/"&gt;WinGet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built on the work of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/tree/master/manifests/e/Element/Element"&gt;existing community manifest&lt;/a&gt; in the winget-pkgs repo and via a &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/pull/244768"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; updated the latest 1.11.96 version to include the ARM64 installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I didn't create the manifest from scratch, I thought it was really easy to contribute a new installer. I'll leave the details of my process for another post though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing Element Desktop via WinGet is relativaly straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you already have the WinGet tool installed, all you have to do is run the following commmand in the terminal and you're all set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell"&gt;winget install Element.Element -a arm64
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/install-element-desktop-windows-arm64</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/install-element-desktop-windows-arm64</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-04-07 08:38 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>arm64</category>
      <category>windows</category>
      <category>element</category>
      <category>winget</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky Welcomes Mike Masnick to Board of Directors</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Nice! I remember reading &lt;a href="https://knightcolumbia.org/content/protocols-not-platforms-a-technological-approach-to-free-speech"&gt;Protocols, Not Platforms&lt;/a&gt; many years ago and felt inspired to seek out a better web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mike-masnick-bluesky-board-of-directors</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mike-masnick-bluesky-board-of-directors</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-07 22:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>platforms</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>humanweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goblin - Tumblr meets the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goblin band is an attempt to replicate the colletive creative energy that happens on tumblr and take it to the fediverse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repo&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/johnHackworth/goblin"&gt;https://github.com/johnHackworth/goblin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/goblin-tumblr-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/goblin-tumblr-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 16:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>firefish</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>federation</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spritely and Veilid: Exciting Projects Building the Peer-to-Peer Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is a surge in federated social media sites, like Bluesky and Mastodon, some technologists are hoping to take things further than this model of decentralization with fully peer-to-peer applications. Two leading projects, Spritely and Veilid, hint at what this could look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spritely is a framework for building distributed apps that don’t even have to know that they’re distributed. The project is spearheaded by Christine Lemmer-Webber, who was one of the co-authors of the ActivityPub spec that drives the fediverse. She is taking the lessons learned from that work, combining them with security and privacy minded object capabilities models, and mixing it all up into a model for peer to peer computation that could pave the way for a generation of new decentralized tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Veilid project was released at DEFCON 31 in August and has a number of promising features that could lead to it being a fundamental tool in future decentralized systems. Described as a cross between TOR and Interplanetary File System (IPFS), Veilid is a framework and protocol that offers two complementary tools. The first is private routing, which, much like TOR, can construct an encrypted private tunnel over the public internet allowing two devices to communicate with each other without anyone else on the network knowing who is talking to whom...The second tool that Veilid offers is a Distributed Hash Table (DHT), which lets anyone look up a bit of data associated with a specific key, wherever that data lives on the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public interest in decentralized tools and services is growing, as people realize that there are downsides to centralized control over the platforms that connect us all. The past year has seen interest in networks like the fediverse and Bluesky explode and there’s no reason to expect that to change. Projects like Spritely and Veilid are pushing the boundaries of how we might build apps and services in the future. The things that they are making possible may well form the foundation of social communication on the internet in the next decade, making our lives online more free, secure, and resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://spritely.institute/"&gt;Spritely Institute Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://veilid.com/"&gt;Veilid Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/spritely-veilid-p2p-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/spritely-veilid-p2p-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-19 11:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>p2p</category>
      <category>veilid</category>
      <category>spritely</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texts Joins Automattic</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using an all-in-one messaging app is a real game-changer for productivity and keeping up with things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is obviously a tricky area to navigate, as in the past the networks have blocked third-party clients, but I think with the current anti-trust and regulatory environments this is actually something the big networks will appreciate: it maintains the same security as their clients, opens them up in a way consumers will love and is very user-centric, and because we’re committed to supporting all their features it can actually increase engagement and usage of their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can relate to the feeling of wanting to have one inbox expressed in the video. Coincidentally, I've been playing with &lt;a href="https://delta.chat/"&gt;Delta Chat&lt;/a&gt; and by building on top of e-mail, some of the issues with the siloed platforms are alleviated. Also, &lt;a href="https://www.emailisnotdead.com/"&gt;e-mail isn't dead&lt;/a&gt; and despite some of its shortcomings, it's still broadly used to sign up and sign into platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/texts-joins-automattic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/texts-joins-automattic</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-24 17:13 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interop</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automattic is acquiring Texts and betting big on the future of messaging</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I'm really liking the recent acquisitions from Automattic. I'm just starting to use Day One and really enjoy it. Pocket Casts is a fantastic podcast app, though I prefer to use AntennaPod. WordPress is also starting to make it easy to plug into the Fediverse using your blog. I'm excited for Texts and what that might offer in the current siloed messaging landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automattic, the company that runs WordPress.com, Tumblr, Pocket Casts, and a number of other popular web properties, just made a different kind of acquisition: it’s buying Texts, a universal messaging app, for $50 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texts is an app for all your messaging apps. You can use it to log in to WhatsApp, Instagram, LinkedIn, Signal, iMessage, and more and see and respond to all your messages in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...Mullenweg says he’s bullish on solutions like Matrix, which offers a decentralized and open-source messaging network, and other up-and-coming standards for messaging. He’s already thinking about how Texts might gently nudge people toward more open protocols over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mullenweg and Automattic see a big future for messaging, as more online interaction shifts away from public-first social networks and toward things like group chats. Hardly anyone has figured out how to build a meaningful and sustainable business from chat, but Mullenweg thinks it’s possible. And he thinks it starts with making your messaging a little less messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/automattic-acquires-texts-messaging</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/automattic-acquires-texts-messaging</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-24 09:16 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interop</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgraded to Mastodon 4.2.0</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Good thing I'd upgraded to 4.1.7 just a few weeks ago, so getting to 4.2.0 was relatively easy. The &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/mastodon-server-upgrades/"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; where I'm tracking updates makes it easy to quickly remember the general process. I haven't tried all of the new features, but it's nice to see there's a new onboarding flow to the Web UI which should make it easier to get started for new folks.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/upgraded-mastodon-4-2-0</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/upgraded-mastodon-4-2-0</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-24 20:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>sysadmin</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix 2.0: The Future of Matrix</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: If you want to play with a shiny new Matrix 2.0 client, head over to &lt;a href="https://element.io/blog/element-x-ignition/"&gt;Element X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/matrix-2-0</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/matrix-2-0</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-22 10:10 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>communication</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress ActivityPub Plugin</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I can't believe I missed this announcement. This is great to see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the fediverse with ActivityPub, broadcasting your blog to a wider audience! Attract followers, deliver updates, and receive comments from a diverse user base of ActivityPub-compliant platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the ActivityPub plugin installed, your WordPress blog itself function as a federated profile, along with profiles for each author. For instance, if your website is example.com, then the blog-wide profile can be found at @example.com@example.com, and authors like Jane and Bob would have their individual profiles at @jane@example.com and @bobz@example.com, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-17 12:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fediverse beyond Mastodon</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;It's been great to see many old and new friends joining Mastodon and considering alternatives to online communities over the past few weeks. Selfishly my feed had been quiet since I started using it and self-hosting back in 2018 so it's nice to see more activity. As folks have started to settle in and get a better understanding of Mastodon, I'd like to point out that Mastodon is only one of many apps and services on the &lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/"&gt;Fediverse&lt;/a&gt;. Now I won't try to explain the Fediverse but in general, it's the collection of applications and services that interoperate in a federated manner, Mastodon being one of them. If in general you like Mastodon and are looking for alternatives to services like Instagram, YouTube, SoundCloud, the Fediverse has a few options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram ➡️ &lt;a href="https://pixelfed.org/"&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube ➡️ &lt;a href="https://joinpeertube.org/"&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SoundCloud ➡️ &lt;a href="https://funkwhale.audio/"&gt;Funkwhale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitch ➡️ &lt;a href="https://owncast.online/"&gt;Owncast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create an account for each of these services using different instances, just like Mastodon. You also have the option of self-hosting which I find amazing. However, because for the most part these services implement the ActivityPub protocol, it means federation extends beyond Mastodon. You can follow people on PixelFed, PeerTube, and many of these other services using your Mastodon account which means you don't have to create accounts for those services just to follow people. While I don't have experience with all of these services, I recommend checking them out. I especially like what Pixelfed, PeerTube and Owncast are doing but those are the main ones I have experience with.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/fediverse-beyond-mastodon</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/fediverse-beyond-mastodon</guid>
      <pubDate>2022-11-20 19:28 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>owncast</category>
      <category>peertube</category>
      <category>pixelfed</category>
      <category>funkwhale</category>
      <category>alternatives</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In light of recent developments on Twitter, I see more people looking for alternative platforms. Personally, I don't think anything beats the level of customization and control you get from using your own website and RSS for sharing ideas and publishing content. However, it's great to see so many new friends in the Fediverse on platforms like &lt;a href="https://joinmastodon.org/"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;. I won't go into what the Fediverse is but you can check out the &lt;a href="https://joinfediverse.wiki/What_is_the_Fediverse%3F"&gt;Fediverse wiki&lt;/a&gt; for more info. In many ways the Fediverse will feel familiar, yet foreign. Many people have shared tips on getting started, but I'll share some of the ones I've personally used to organically curate my feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use hashtags. Similar to Twitter, hashtags are a good way of finding people and content related to the topic of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow &lt;a href="https://mstdn.social/@feditips"&gt;feditips&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://mastodon.online/@FediFollows"&gt;FediFollows&lt;/a&gt;. As the names suggest, they provide good tips and suggest interesting accounts to follow in the Fediverse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an alternative if you're not ready to create an account, you can use RSS. I'm a big &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom/"&gt;fan of RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Appending &lt;code&gt;.rss&lt;/code&gt; to any account on platforms like Mastodon (for example &lt;a href="https://mastodon.online/@FediFollows.rss"&gt;https://mastodon.online/@FediFollows.rss&lt;/a&gt;) provides you with the RSS feed of an account's posts letting you subscribe to their content through your favorite RSS feed reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to say hi at &lt;a href="https://toot.lqdev.tech/@lqdev"&gt;toot.lqdev.tech/@lqdev&lt;/a&gt;. See you in the Fediverse!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/welcome-to-fediverse-tips</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/welcome-to-fediverse-tips</guid>
      <pubDate>04/27/2022 13:04 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>twitter</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>