<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - postcast</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/postcast</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'postcast' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-11-19 09:56 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Digital minimalism: A moral duty?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I saw a reference to this paper yesterday and added it to my Read-It-Later list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a link to the original paper: &lt;a href="https://philpapers.org/archive/AYLITA.pdf"&gt;https://philpapers.org/archive/AYLITA.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chances are, I wasnt going to get to it until way later with the backlog of other things I want to read later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucky for me, that was the subject of the latest Deep Questions episode. Cal does a nice job breaking down the main arguments of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KK9ktzbBDPE" title="A thumbnail of Deep Questions Podcast Episode on Digital Minimalism"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/KK9ktzbBDPE/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="A thumbnail of Deep Questions Podcast Episode on Digital Minimalism" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main takeaway for me was, technology is a great tool. However, when it robs you of your rational decision making abilities and pushes you to compulsive behaviors that move you away from the habits and practices that fuel your growth, it's a problem. For example, lets say you want to build a habit of reading or working out. Unfortunately, when you &lt;INSERT TIME SUCKING DISTRACTION OF CHOICE&gt;, time, attention, and energy that would've otherwise been spent on those habits is now diverted towards the distraction. That is irrational and goes against your desire to grow, yet making the rational choice is where most of us struggle. Although the paper focuses on our digital lives, I can see other ways similar arguments can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also included the audio version as well: &lt;a href="https://www.buzzsprout.com/1121972/episodes/16124495-ep-327-would-kant-use-tiktok"&gt;https://www.buzzsprout.com/1121972/episodes/16124495-ep-327-would-kant-use-tiktok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/digital-minimalism-moral-duty-deep-questions</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/digital-minimalism-moral-duty-deep-questions</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 09:56 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>digitalminimalism</category>
      <category>postcast</category>
      <category>deepquestions</category>
      <category>philosophy</category>
      <category>calnewport</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NotebookLlama: An Open Source version of NotebookLM</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;This is cool! Already looking at how I can repurpose this sample for a project I have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/notebook-llama-oss-notebook-lm</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/notebook-llama-oss-notebook-lm</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-01 09:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>sample</category>
      <category>postcast</category>
      <category>texttospeech</category>
      <category>programming</category>
      <category>sample</category>
      <category>tutorial</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing the surface area of blogging</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS is kind of an invisible technology. People call RSS dead because you can’t see it. There’s no feed, no login, no analytics. RSS feels subsurface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to think of it - all the interesting bits of blogging are invisible. The discussion has moved to Twitter, or discords, or DMs. Trackbacks aren’t a thing anymore. So when you see someone blogging all you see is the blog post. The branching replies and conversations are either invisible or hard to track down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I believe we’re living in a golden age of RSS. Blogging is booming. My feed reader has 280 feeds in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we increase the surface area of RSS and blogging?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there’s something quietly radical about making your feed reader open by default. It increases the surface area of RSS so others can discover content more easily. It makes blogging more visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about RSS and OPML is that’s a very extensible spec. The file format is flexible, you can define your own schema and fields. This might open up new kinds of publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/increasing-surface-area-blogging-critchlow</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/increasing-surface-area-blogging-critchlow</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-08-24 21:25 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>postcast</category>
      <category>feeds</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>openstandards</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>