<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - ubuntu</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/ubuntu</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'ubuntu' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-06-06 22:14 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Omakub - An Omakase Developer Setup for Ubuntu 24.04</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Cool project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn a fresh Ubuntu installation into a fully-configured, beautiful, and modern web development system by running a single command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omakub is an opinionated take on what Linux can be at its best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omakub includes a curated set of applications and tools that one might discover through hours of watching YouTube, reading blogs, or just stumbling around Linux internet. All so someone coming straight from a platform like Windows or the Mac can immediately start enjoying a ready-made system, without having to do any configuration and curation legwork at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/omakub-ubuntu-developer-desktop</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/omakub-ubuntu-developer-desktop</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-06 22:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>developer</category>
      <category>ubuntu</category>
      <category>desktop</category>
      <category>37signals</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assorted links - Ubuntu 22.04 LTS, Bitwarden, DALLE-2, Emacs</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Here's a few links I found in the interwebs today that I thought were worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ubuntu 22.04 LTS Released&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my personal computing needs, Manjaro has been my default Linux distro. However, for hosting and cloud VMs I go back and forth between Debian and Ubuntu depending on which better supports the software I'm running. Canonical announced the release of the latest Ubuntu LTS version 22.04. Check out their &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/ubuntu-22-04-lts-released"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for more details on what's new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Self-hosting Bitwarden on DigitalOcean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to password managers, other than KeePass, my favorite it &lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/"&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt;. It's open-source, built on .NET, has excellent features that get even better with the low-cost paid version, but most importantly provides you the option of self-hosting. If you're looking to self-host Bitwarden on DigitalOcean, make sure to check out the &lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/blog/digitalocean-marketplace/"&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; they just published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How DALLE-2 Actually Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, OpenAI announced the release of &lt;a href="https://openai.com/dall-e-2/"&gt;DALLE-2&lt;/a&gt;. Open AI describes DALLE-2 as, &amp;quot;...a new AI system that can create realistic images and art from a description in natural language.&amp;quot; If you want to understand the details of how it works, you could read the 27 page research paper &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2204.06125.pdf"&gt;Hierarchical Text-Conditional
Image Generation with CLIP Latents&lt;/a&gt;. AssemblyAI just published an approachable guide into the inner workings of DALLE-2. If you're interested in that, check out their &lt;a href="https://www.assemblyai.com/blog/how-dall-e-2-actually-works/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Emacs Configuration Generator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my early days of using Emacs, I often found it difficult to customize it to my needs. Not only did I not know what was possible, but it also caused some anxiety because I didn't feel confident enough making major tweaks. If you're getting started with Emacs and aren't sure how to configure it, this neat &lt;a href="https://emacs.amodernist.com/"&gt;utility&lt;/a&gt; helps you generate a config file for Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PostgresML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're building machine learning applications, one of the main things you'll need is data. This data can reside in databases such as MySQL, SQL Server, and Postgres. Algorithms are applied to this data downstream using libraries written in languages like Python, R, and .NET. This not only means potentially moving the data from the database to another process but also using another library to train models. According to the project description on GitHub, &amp;quot;PostgresML is an end-to-end machine learning system. It enables you to train models and make online predictions using only SQL, without your data ever leaving your favorite database.&amp;quot; If that's something you're interested in, check out the project on &lt;a href="https://github.com/postgresml/postgresml"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/2022-04-21-assorted-links</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/2022-04-21-assorted-links</guid>
      <pubDate>04/21/2022 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>links</category>
      <category>assortedlinks</category>
      <category>ubuntu</category>
      <category>bitwarden</category>
      <category>dalle</category>
      <category>openai</category>
      <category>emacs</category>
      <category>linkblog</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HP ProBook 430 G1 Ubuntu BIOS Upgrade</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
I recently got an HP ProBook 430 G1 which came preinstalled with Windows 10. I have several Windows 10 devices, but needed a Linux system while on the go. I had given my HP Chromebook a try using Crouton. This worked okay. However, I was limited by the specs of the Chromebook and wanted something with more power for development purposes. Therefore, I erased Windows 10 on the ProBook and installed Ubuntu. The PC worked well. My only problem with it was that I found my battery meter was inaccurate and would reach a percentage in the 60’s before suddenly dropping to zero and shutting down. This was not something I could have, especially during the middle of a work session where I might lose some/all of my work.

Immediately, I assumed it had something to do with drivers/BIOS being out of date. To my surprise, BIOS updates were only available for Windows. Fortunately, through some research I was able to find a solution that allowed me to update my BIOS and fix my battery problems.

## Prerequisites:

1. Make sure PC is connected to the charger
2. 4GB USB Drive

## Procedure:

1. Format USB drive. (FAT32 required)
2. Create folder inside USB drive called Hewlett-Packard\BIOS\New
3. Download latest BIOS .exe file from HP Support website
4. Unzip .exe file. While 7Zip is not required, I found this to work well.
5. Copy .bin file to Hewlett-Packard\BIOS\New folder
6. Copy entire BIOSUpdate folder to Hewlett-Packard folder.
7. Restart PC
8. Continuously press F10 to enter BIOS Setup
9. Select Update System BIOS menu option
10. Select Update BIOS Using Local Media option
11. Select Accept

At this point, the installation process will take effect and the PC will restart itself at which point the your BIOS should be up to date.
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/hp-probook-430g1-ubuntu-bios-upgrade</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/hp-probook-430g1-ubuntu-bios-upgrade</guid>
      <pubDate>2017-12-09 12:57:12 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>sysadmin</category>
      <category>ubuntu</category>
      <category>bios</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up A New Ubuntu PC</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
# Users

This assumes that you are currently the root user.

Enter the adduser to command to create a new user.

```bash
adduser &lt;username&gt;
```

Immediately, you will be prompted for a password. Enter the password and continue the process. 

## Adding Root Privileges

This is only applicable when granting root priviliges to the newly created user. 

Enter the usermod command to add the new user to the sudo (root) group

```bash
usermod -aG sudo &lt;username&gt;
```

The user should now have root priviliges. 

To test that it worked log in as that user and try to run a command with sudo

```bash
su - &lt;username&gt;
sudo ls -la /root
```

# Emacs

By default, Ubuntu usually comes preloaded or has the default 24.x version of Emacs. I often like to use Emacs along with org-mode and to take full advantage, especially as it pertains to working with source code I have found version 25.x is much better suited for the task. While there are many ways to go about it, installing it via package manager appears to be the easiest. 

## Add repository to PPA

```bash
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:kelleyk/emacs
```

## Update the packages

```bash
sudo apt update
```

## Install Emacs. 
### Text-Only Interface

```bash
sudo apt-get install emacs25-nox
```

### GUI Interface

```bash
sudo apt-get install emacs25
```

## Backup files

Sometimes Emacs keeps a backup file by default. This can cause a lot of clutter in the current directory where work is being performed. There is a way to disable this.

Navigate to `~/.emacs.d/` and edit the `init.el` file and add the following line.

```lisp
(setq make-backup-files nil)
```

# Java

Make sure that your packages and repositories are up to date

```bash
sudo apt-get update
```

## OpenJDK

```bash
sudo apt-get install default-jdk
```

## Oracle JDK
### Add PPA Repository
```bash
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:webupd8team/java
sudo apt-get update
```

### Install the installer

```bash
sudo apt-get install oracle-java8-installer
```


#### Sources
[Users](https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-create-a-sudo-user-on-ubuntu-quickstart)  
[Emacs](http://ubuntuhandbook.org/index.php/2017/04/install-emacs-25-ppa-ubuntu-16-04-14-04/)  
[Java](https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-java-with-apt-get-on-ubuntu-16-04)
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/setting-up-new-ubuntu-pc</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/setting-up-new-ubuntu-pc</guid>
      <pubDate>2017-12-09 12:49:19 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>linux</category>
      <category>ubuntu</category>
      <category>java</category>
      <category>sysadmin</category>
      <category>emacs</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>