<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - streaming</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/streaming</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'streaming' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-02-28 21:51 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Tubi’s new redesign wants to push you down the rabbit hole</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tubi says its new ‘turple’-forward brand identity is all about encouraging viewers to fall down rabbit holes to find exciting shows and movies to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've often found &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds"&gt;good content to watch on Tubi&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, they're not the latest blockbusters but there are decades worth of movies out there. Just like today, not all movies that come out are good but there's still tons of great content. Sometimes, there's even &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/dread-central-overlook-motel"&gt;overlooked gems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tubi-redesign-down-the-rabbit-hole</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tubi-redesign-down-the-rabbit-hole</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-28 21:51 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>movies</category>
      <category>tubi</category>
      <category>streaming</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My streaming fatigue got so bad I started collecting DVDs</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending years reassuring myself that I don’t need physical copies of movies because of streaming, DVDs have officially reentered my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walmart...Thrift stores, flea markets, the library, and even my local mall’s FYE have also become places I frequent to get my hands on oft-ignored discs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense to subscribe to all these services if you’re into the exclusive content on each one and have the patience to sift through their massive libraries. However, all I’ve been watching lately is the junk on Discovery Plus, simply because I’m too tired to find anything else — especially when the extremely specific shows and movies I want to watch keep switching services or just aren’t available. One of the most devastating examples of this was when both The Office and Parks and Recreation moved from Netflix to Peacock, disrupting the casual binge-watching sessions that I would default to when I was done with work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the past year, nearly every streaming service has raised its prices, including Netflix, Disney Plus, Hulu, Paramount Plus, Discovery Plus, and Apple TV Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying DVDs are flawless: there’s a reason no one wants them anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, it’s still nice to have something that you physically own and don’t even need an internet connection to use. So when Best Buy confirmed it would stop selling DVDs this year and rumors emerged that Walmart would do the same, I was pretty disappointed. I can’t imagine Walmart without its bin of DVDs, nor can I even see Best Buy without its already-shrunken selection of movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2024, and I’m not ready to say goodbye to DVDs — in fact, I’m just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article from Emma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I've been doing the same. Just a few weekends ago, I got something like 8-10 DVDs for ~$25 at my local thrift store. That haul included 3 seasons of The Sopranos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With streaming services taking back control of their content and putting it on their own platforms, I don't want to have to keep signing up for a new service just to watch the shows and movies I enjoy. Also, that's assuming you can find the content to begin with (i.e. Westworld).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parks and Recreation, The Office, and Breaking Bad were some of the first shows I started collecting and have slowly been building up my collection. To save on space, I've ditched the cases and have the DVDs organized in a CD case. I've not only limited myself to DVDs but have also started collecting CDs as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I want variety, I just use one of the free streaming services like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justwatch.com/us/provider/freevee"&gt;Freevee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pluto.tv/"&gt;Pluto TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://tubitv.com/"&gt;Tubi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are ads but at least I'm not paying for it and I know that's part of the deal. There are a ton of good older (and sometimes original) TV shows and movies on those platforms to keep me entertained. The most recent ones being Stargate and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/vampires-kiss-movie"&gt;Vampire's Kiss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-26 15:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>streaming</category>
      <category>media</category>
      <category>dvds</category>
      <category>movies</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>physicalmedia</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to watch Twitch streams using VLC</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

Twitch has become a tool for various creators to connect with audiences. Originally, streams were centered around gaming but now there is a wide variety of creators that include musicians, software developers, and craftspeople. One of my favorites is [Brainfeeder](https://www.twitch.tv/brainfeeder). I myself try (and often fail) to build software projects on stream. If you're interested in hanging out and talking machine learning, .NET and all things tech, feel free to join me at [https://twitch.tv/lqdev1](https://twitch.tv/lqdev1).

Watching Twitch streams on the desktop via the browser can take a toll on compute resources. A more efficient solution to this problem is to use VLC. VLC is a free, open-source, cross-platform media player that supports various protocols. While it was possible to watch Twitch streams using VLC before, it often required additional software such as [Streamlink](https://github.com/streamlink/streamlink). More recent versions make this requirement redundant. In this post, I'll show how to use VLC to watch Twitch streams.

![Twitch iOS App on iPhoneX - Caspar Camille Rubin](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/103722126-4883f780-4f9d-11eb-8cc8-304d1a249ef9.png)

## Prerequisites

- VLC (version **3.11.0 or higher**)

## Watch Twitch Stream

&gt; **Update 11/12/2021**  
&gt; It's been a while since I've gotten the original steps to work, so feel free to skip them. You can still watch Twitch streams on VLC using Streamlink. To use Streamlink:
&gt; 1. Download and install [Streamlink](https://streamlink.github.io/install.html)
&gt; 1. Open the terminal and run:
&gt;    
&gt;    ```
&gt;    streamlink https://twitch.tv/&lt;username&gt; best
&gt;    ````
&gt;
&gt; For more information, see the [Streamlink Command-Line Interface documentation](https://streamlink.github.io/cli.html)

1. Open VLC
2. From the menu, Select **Media &gt; Open Network Stream**
3. Paste the URL to the stream you want to watch in the text box (i.e. https://twitch.tv/lqdev1)

At this point, the stream should start playing.

### CLI

Alternatively on Unix (Mac / Linux) systems, you can use the CLI. To watch a stream, open a terminal and enter the following command:

```bash
vlc https://twitch.tv/&lt;username&gt;
```

Make sure to replace the username with the streamer you want to watch.

After a few seconds, VLC loads and starts playing the stream.

## Performance comparison

Below is a comparison of the same stream playing on the browser vs VLC. These test were performed on a Surface Laptop 1 running Windows 10. By no means should you take this as a definitive performance comparison as there are many variables that may affect performance. However, it's a nice way to visualize each of the methods.

### Browser

In the browser scenario, I only had a single tab playing the Twitch stream on Microsoft Edge (chromium).

![Browser task manager](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/103723087-43c04300-4f9f-11eb-9969-df40541693bd.png)

### VLC

![VLC task manager](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/103721933-e1fed980-4f9c-11eb-92f3-0147f2c09134.png)

As it can be seen from this image, there's about a 4x decrease in CPU resource consumption when using VLC.

## Conclusion

In this post I showed how you can use VLC to watch Twitch streams. One of the drawbacks is, you can't see the channels you follow and who's online. You also can't browse streams like you would on the Twitch web client. You also don't have access to chat, which is half the fun on many streams. However, if you're only interested in the content, VLC is an excellent and less resource-hungry way of watching Twitch streams. See you on Twitch!
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-to-watch-twitch-using-vlc</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-to-watch-twitch-using-vlc</guid>
      <pubDate>2021-01-05 21:14:39 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>streaming</category>
      <category>hacks</category>
      <category>video</category>
      <category>IT</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>