<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - memory</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/memory</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'memory' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-08-13 22:29 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Playing around with the Ivy Cliq+ 2</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s7d1.scene7.com/is/image/canon/4519C001_ivy-cliq-plus2-instant-camera-printer-plus-app-rose-gold_primary?fmt=webp-alpha&amp;amp;wid=800" class="img-fluid" alt="Image of Canon Ivy Cliq+ 2 camera and photo printer" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my hands on an &lt;a href="https://www.usa.canon.com/shop/p/ivy-cliq-2-instant-camera-printer-app"&gt;Ivy Cliq+ 2&lt;/a&gt; earlier today and am really liking it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really cool that it's both a point-and-shoot camera as well as a photo printer. The camera comes in handy if you want to capture something in the moment and print it out immediately. The printer is great for pictures you've taken on your phone or some other device. Even better, you can create collages, apply filters, and do all sorts of adjustments to images before printing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there's one thing I didn't like is that in order to set it up, it needed access to my exact location. Trying approximate location wasn't enough. It connects over Bluetooth, so you'd think that should be enough to pair. Not sure what it needs my EXACT location for.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/ivy-cliq-2-camera-photo-printer</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/ivy-cliq-2-camera-photo-printer</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-13 22:29 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>analog</category>
      <category>camera</category>
      <category>photos</category>
      <category>journal</category>
      <category>memory</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory and new controls for ChatGPT</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re testing memory with ChatGPT. Remembering things you discuss across all chats saves you from having to repeat information and makes future conversations more helpful.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You're in control of ChatGPT's memory. You can explicitly tell it to remember something, ask it what it remembers, and tell it to forget conversationally or through settings. You can also turn it off entirely.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We are rolling out to a small portion of ChatGPT free and Plus users this week to learn how useful it is. We will share plans for broader roll out soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openai-chatgpt-memory</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openai-chatgpt-memory</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-13 21:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>openai</category>
      <category>chatgpt</category>
      <category>memory</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>llm</category>
      <category>gpt</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>