<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - online</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/online</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'online' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-04-25 23:11 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>We Need To Rewild The Internet</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has become an extractive and fragile monoculture. But we can revitalize it using lessons learned by ecologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our online spaces are not ecosystems, though tech firms love that word. They’re plantations; highly concentrated and controlled environments...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We all know this. We see it each time we reach for our phones. But what most people have missed is how this concentration reaches deep into the internet’s infrastructure — the pipes and protocols, cables and networks, search engines and browsers. These structures determine how we build and use the internet, now and in the future.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
They’ve concentrated into a series of near-planetary duopolies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Two kinds of everything may be enough to fill a fictional ark and repopulate a ruined world, but can’t run an open, global “network of networks” where everyone has the same chance to innovate and compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet made the tech giants possible. Their services have scaled globally, via its open, interoperable core. But for the past decade, they’ve also worked to enclose the varied, competing and often open-source or collectively provided services the internet is built on into their proprietary domains. Although this improves their operational efficiency, it also ensures that the flourishing conditions of their own emergence aren’t repeated by potential competitors. For tech giants, the long period of open internet evolution is over. Their internet is not an ecosystem. It’s a zoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up close, internet concentration seems too intricate to untangle; from far away, it seems too difficult to deal with. But what if we thought of the internet not as a doomsday “hyperobject,” but as a damaged and struggling ecosystem facing destruction? What if we looked at it not with helpless horror at the eldritch encroachment of its current controllers, but with compassion, constructiveness and hope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewilding “aims to restore healthy ecosystems by creating wild, biodiverse spaces,” according to the International Union for Conservation of Nature. More ambitious and risk-tolerant than traditional conservation, it targets entire ecosystems to make space for complex food webs and the emergence of unexpected interspecies relations. It’s less interested in saving specific endangered species. Individual species are just ecosystem components, and focusing on components loses sight of the whole. Ecosystems flourish through multiple points of contact between their many elements, just like computer networks. And like in computer networks, ecosystem interactions are multifaceted and generative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever we do, the internet isn’t returning to old-school then-common interfaces like FTP and Gopher, or organizations operating their own mail servers again instead of off-the-shelf solutions like G-Suite. But some of what we need is already here, especially on the web. Look at the resurgence of RSS feeds, email newsletters and blogs, as we discover (yet again) that relying on one app to host global conversations creates a single point of failure and control. New systems are growing, like the Fediverse with its federated islands, or Bluesky with algorithmic choice and composable moderation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We don’t know what the future holds. Our job is to keep open as much opportunity as we can, trusting that those who come later will use it. Instead of setting purity tests for which kind of internet is most like the original, we can test changes against the values of the original design. Do new standards protect the network’s “generality,” i.e. its ability to support multiple uses, or is functionality limited to optimize efficiency for the biggest tech firms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...our internet took off because it was designed as a general-purpose network, built to connect anyone.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our internet was built to be complex and unbiddable, to do things we cannot yet imagine.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Internet infrastructure is a degraded ecosystem, but it’s also a built environment, like a city. Its unpredictability makes it generative, worthwhile and deeply human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to stop thinking of internet infrastructure as too hard to fix. It’s the underlying system we use for nearly everything we do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Rewilding the internet connects and grows what people are doing across regulation, standards-setting and new ways of organizing and building infrastructure, to tell a shared story of where we want to go. It’s a shared vision with many strategies. The instruments we need to shift away from extractive technological monocultures are at hand or ready to be built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/rewild-the-internet-farrell-berjon</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/rewild-the-internet-farrell-berjon</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 23:11 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>online</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Used To Be Fun</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to write some kind of Important Thinkpiece™ on the glory days of the early internet, but every time I sit down to do it, I find another, better piece that someone else has already written. So for now, here’s a collection of articles that to some degree answer the question “Why have a personal website?” with “Because it’s fun, and the internet used to be fun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great catalog of posts about the personal web. Courtesy of &lt;a href="https://kwon.nyc/"&gt;Rachel Kwon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/internet-used-to-be-fun-kwon</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/internet-used-to-be-fun-kwon</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 22:56 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>online</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>blogs</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Services</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a site encouraging non-technical people and organisations to create their own online services such as websites, social networks, personal clouds, instant messaging etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/grow-your-own-services</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/grow-your-own-services</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 22:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>selfhosting</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>cloud</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>socialnetworks</category>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>online</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMentions</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenMentions is a project designed to use Webmentions and ActivityPub for topical content discovery. The site is organised along the lines of a hierarchy of topics going from broad to fine. This we call OpenTopic – the idea being that many sites could host the full collection of topics so that the loss of any one site is not the loss of all topics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The intention is that this site should own nothing and that topic hierarchies are organic and discoverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openmentions</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openmentions</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-16 20:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>webmentions</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>online</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarkesworld - Sci-fi and Fantasy Magazine</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarkesworld is a monthly science fiction and fantasy magazine first published in October 2006. Each issue contains interviews, thought-provoking articles, and between six and eight works of original fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/clarkesworld-sci-fi-fantasy-magazine</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/clarkesworld-sci-fi-fantasy-magazine</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 15:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>magazine</category>
      <category>scifi</category>
      <category>fantasy</category>
      <category>online</category>
      <category>fiction</category>
      <category>nonfiction</category>
      <category>art</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gravatar - Your digital profile beyond blog comments</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I had known about &lt;a href="https://gravatar.com/"&gt;Gravatar&lt;/a&gt; since its early days. I was under the (incorrect) impression that it could only be used to comment on blogs. I thought when you created an account, you added your name, e-mail, and image as part of your profile. Then, when you wanted to comment on blogs, instead of creating individual accounts or profiles, you could just reuse your Gravatar profile. That's partially true. However, I'm happy to report I was wrong and there's so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While commenting on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blog-posts-can-be-any-length-matt"&gt;Matt Mullenweg's Birthday Gift post&lt;/a&gt;, I didn't use a Gravatar profile. This prompted Matt to kindly respond via e-mail and suggest I check out Gravatar. I put it off for a few days. Eventually, I decided to check it out and I'm glad I did. Thanks &lt;a href="https://ma.tt"&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The signup process was simple. All I had to do was enter my e-mail address. This immediately sent me a confirmation e-mail which I then used to proceed with onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's where things got interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add all the things I was already aware of (name, e-mail, photo). However, you can also do much more than that! You can add your own verified accounts, links, contact information, and payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of this writing these options include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounts
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X / Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TikTok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tumblr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fediverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vimeo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TripIt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foursquare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact info
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E-mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone number (home, work, mobile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Payments
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PayPal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venmo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Litecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dogecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethereum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XRP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cardano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to those integrations, you can also provide as many of your own custom links as you'd like. In my case, I've chosen to link to my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. The options are endless though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have a &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/"&gt;Linktree&lt;/a&gt; profile so I can't objectively say how Gravatar compares to those offerings. At their core though, Gravatar and Linktree seem to address similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not yet committed to having your own place on the internet (website/blog) or if you're looking for a way to organize your digital identity in single place, Gravatar is an excellent option. I'd encourage you to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find my Gravatar profile at &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/gravatar"&gt;lqdev.me/gravatar&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/gravatar-digital-profile-beyond-blog-comments</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/gravatar-digital-profile-beyond-blog-comments</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 11:18 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>profile</category>
      <category>online</category>
      <category>gravatar</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>comments</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>identity</category>
      <category>linktree</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>bloggin</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>