<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - All Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/feed</link>
    <description>All content updates from Luis Quintanilla's website</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-08-12 08:41</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering for Slow Internet</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this webapp really need to be 20 MB? What all is being loaded that could be deferred until it is needed, or included in an “optional” add-on bundle? Is there a possibility of a “lite” version, for bandwidth-constrained users?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Antarctica is an edge case, this article illustrates some of the motivations behind my &lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/text"&gt;text-first website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By trimming the excess not only do you get to the core of the app or website, but it also loads faster.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/engineering-for-slow-internet</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/engineering-for-slow-internet</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-12 08:41</pubDate>
      <category>slowweb</category>
      <category>performance</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>computing</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Self-Hosted</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of Free Software network services and web applications which can be hosted on your own server(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/awesome-self-hosted</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/awesome-self-hosted</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-11 23:24</pubDate>
      <category>selfhosting</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>FOSS</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop saving everything</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your read-it-later list isn’t getting cleared weekly, perhaps it’s time to delete the lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save from a mindset of abundance, rather than scarcity, and process the things you’ve saved each week (or month, at the most). If you are worried that something you deleted truly would have changed your life, just stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STOP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t read it all, do it all, be it all. Trust that those potentially life-changing ideas will come around again, when you are ready for them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good reminder. Lately I've been sending a lot of notes to myself with stuff to read but just haven't had the time to get to it. That said, the act of sending myself those notes is low friction that I don't feel FOMO when I don't get to read the articles and consume the media.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/stop-saving-everything</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/stop-saving-everything</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-11 23:00</pubDate>
      <category>pkm</category>
      <category>productivity</category>
      <category>notetaking</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New text-first site and search are live</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Just iterated on another version of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major change is that there's now a text-first version of the website for minimal and resource-constrained environments over at &lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/text"&gt;/text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also added search functionality, which you can find at &lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/search"&gt;/search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/new-text-first-site-and-search-are-live</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/new-text-first-site-and-search-are-live</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-11 20:57 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>plaintext</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>website</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>URL Town</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;Love to see projects like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;url.town doesn’t have any overly lofty ambitions; we’re just building our own directory of really nice websites. We’re not trying to fully recreate the original Yahoo! or DMOZ directories. We’re not aiming for some astronomical number of links. This is just one space on the web, tied to a community that loves to share neat things with one another. Quality matters much more than quantity. There’s no need to share everything just for the shake of sharing it; it’s much better to share things that are useful or interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/url-town</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/url-town</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-10 23:26</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>directory</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test mobile post</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Testing date fix on mobile notes&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/test-mobile-post</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/test-mobile-post</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-10 21:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>test</category>
      <category>mobile</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BLM Lands Marked for Potential Sale (OnX)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Sad to see what's happening with our public lands. Great to see folks staying vigilant and providing information of what's happening on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/blm-lands-marked-for-potential-sale-onx</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/blm-lands-marked-for-potential-sale-onx</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-10 21:13</pubDate>
      <category>onx</category>
      <category>bureaulandmanagement</category>
      <category>nature</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claude Code Emacs Integration</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claude Code IDE for Emacs provides native integration with Claude Code CLI through the Model Context Protocol (MCP). Unlike simple terminal wrappers, this package creates a bidirectional bridge between Claude and Emacs, enabling Claude to understand and leverage Emacs’ powerful features—from LSP and project management to custom Elisp functions. This transforms Claude into a true Emacs-aware AI assistant that works within your existing workflow and can interact with your entire Emacs ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/claude-code-emacs-integration</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/claude-code-emacs-integration</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-10 20:17</pubDate>
      <category>emacs</category>
      <category>anthropic</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>claudecode</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world from the new site</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Posting from my brand new redesigned website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was working on it for about a month so I plan on doing a longer writeup on what has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still a few things that are broken, but for the most part, I'm happy with the progress and the changes that need to be made are incremental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a ton of cleanup as well but again. That is not a blocker to publishing the site.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/hello-world-new-site-2025-08</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/hello-world-new-site-2025-08</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-06 17:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>note</category>
      <category>website</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IndieWeb Create Day - July 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Since it was a holiday weekend in the U.S. that kind of snuck up on me, I found myself with nothing planned on a Saturday. So I chose to spend it creating stuff for my website with the IndieWeb community during [IndieWeb Create Day](https://events.indieweb.org/2025/07/indieweb-create-day-3q2PTCbGioi9).

Over the last few months I've been overthinking my website redesign and while I've made several attempts at it, I've never been satisfied the outcome. I end up throwing away all the progress I've made and go back to the drawing board. 

Yesterday, I decided to not let perfect be the enemy of good and the approach I took was creating just a simpler piece of functionality outside of my website. How I integrate it into my website is a future me problem. But I want to work from a place of creativity and complete freedom to think of what could be rather than what is. 

With that in mind, I set out to sketch out how I want to create and render media (image, audio, video) posts. The approach I took used a combination of front-matter YAML and custom markdown media extensions. The front-matter YAML is something that I already use for my website and it's something that I want to continue using. However, in contrast to my current website, I like that the front-matter was kept simple and only includes a basic amount of information. The actual post content was handled by my custom markdown extension which leveraged YAML-like syntax to define media content. What's great about this is that it is composable so once I got one type of media working, the rest for the most part "just worked". I could even mix different media types within the same post with no additional work or code changes required. Once I had the skeleton, it was all about refactoring, documentation, adding finishing touches, and vibe-coding some CSS which Claude did a relatively good job with given the aesthetic I was going for. 

Overall, I'm happy with the end result. 

![A screenshot of a website post containing an image and audio player](/assets/images/feed/indieweb-create-day-2025-07.png)

For more details, you can check out the [repo](https://github.com/lqdev/indieweb-create-day-2025-07).

At some point, I want to be able to integrate these media posts into my static site generator but for the time being, there are other kinds of posts such as reviews, RSVPs, and other [post types](https://indieweb.org/posts#Types_of_Posts) that I want to design and eventually also support on my website. I liked the approach I took this time around because it gave me the freedom to explore posibilities rather than constrain my creativity to what I've already built. So I think I'll keep doing the same for subsequent post types. 

At the end of the day, it was nice seeing everyone else's projects. My favorite one was Cy's recipe website. I want to be like them when I grow up 🙂.]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/posts/indieweb-create-day-2025-07</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/posts/indieweb-create-day-2025-07</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-07-06 20:09</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>iwc</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>website</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week of July 6, 2025 - Post Summary</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/2025-06-29-weekly-post-summary/"&gt;Week of June 29, 2025 - Post Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-june-2025"&gt;Crate Finds - June 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-may-2025"&gt;Crate Finds - May 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/post-statistics-june-2025"&gt;Website Post Statistics - June 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/do-not-privatize-federal-land"&gt;Do not privatize federal land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/tumblr-wordpress-fediverse-integration-pause"&gt;Tumblr’s move to WordPress and fediverse integration is ‘on hold’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/2025-07-06-weekly-post-summary</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/2025-07-06-weekly-post-summary</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-07-06 14:48 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>weeklysummary</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crate Finds - June 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Playlist from June 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claudia, Wilhelm R And Me by Roberto Musci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journey in Satchidananda by Alice Coltrane and Pharoah Sanders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little Sunflower by Dorothy Ashby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/6ZhcCrMutGjgL80C22iN1u" width="100%" height="352" frameBorder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-june-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-june-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-07-01 20:00</pubDate>
      <category>cratefinds</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>playlist</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Website Post Statistics - June 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I haven't published much this past month. Notes and responses are significantly down from last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I'm happy that so far I've published seven long-form blog posts, which is how many I published all of last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't spent as much time bookmarking and resharing content. Partially due to the fact that I'm still working on the redesign. So far &lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/posts/vibe-specing-prompt-to-spec/"&gt;vibe-specing&lt;/a&gt; the redesign hasn't yielded good enough results. Maybe I need to break down my problem further. That experience on its own might make a good blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the challenge with the redesign is that I'm trying to find a balance between standardizing my front-matter YAML schemas so that I can simplify my code and just have a single function handle the parsing of the front-matter, while at the same time enabling custom rendering depending on the post type. I think in the end what I'll end up doing is having different schemas per post type and maybe refactoring some of my code to remove redundancies.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/post-statistics-june-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/post-statistics-june-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-07-01 20:00</pubDate>
      <category>githubactions</category>
      <category>cicd</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>stats</category>
      <category>github</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr’s move to WordPress and fediverse integration is ‘on hold’</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;That's unfortunate. Having Tumblr as your frontend for posting and curating feeds, with WordPress as the backend and integrated with decentralized networks like the Fediverse for distribution would've been amazing. It sounds like Tumblr is still strategic to Automattic and as more people move away from the centralized social platforms and towards their own corners of the internet, having these differente building blocks in place will be even more important.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/tumblr-wordpress-fediverse-integration-pause</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/tumblr-wordpress-fediverse-integration-pause</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-30 20:21</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crate Finds - May 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Better late than never. Here's the May 2025 drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorites from last month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prayer to the Stars by Vianney Lopez, Sam Bottner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diarabi by Viex Farka Toure, Khruangbin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything &amp;amp; Nothing, OHMA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bloom, Deya Dova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dance of the Seven Sisters, Deya Dova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisdom Eye by Alice Coltrane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Meditation by Shabaka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/0ETG3ZcVXCPqgHN4xFQ8qN" width="100%" height="352" frameBorder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-may-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-may-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-29 18:00</pubDate>
      <category>cratefinds</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>playlist</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do not privatize federal land</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve long advocated selling off some federal land...Most of this “public land” is never used by the public. Selling some of it would actually make it more accessible and useful to real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about no. If privatization means, John and Jane Doe can purchase some land for their homestead is one thing. We've tried that before by the way - &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homestead_Acts"&gt;Homestead Act&lt;/a&gt;. In reality, it means some private equity firm or hedge fund buying the land, building expensive and shoddy cookit-cutter condos, and &lt;a href="https://www.nar.realtor/magazine/real-estate-news/commercial/build-to-rent-homes"&gt;selling you a subscription for a roof over your head&lt;/a&gt;. I say condos because it's hot and there's not a lot of water in Vegas, so keeping those brand new AI data centers cool might be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you haven't seen that area that Alex highlights in his post, it seems like a deserted landscape. And yes, the terrain can be rough, but actually, it's a beautiful landscape that is best left undisturbed.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/do-not-privatize-federal-land</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/do-not-privatize-federal-land</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-29 17:26</pubDate>
      <category>bureaulandmanagement</category>
      <category>uspol</category>
      <category>land</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week of June 29, 2025 - Post Summary</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/crate-finds-may-2025"&gt;Crate Finds - May 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/do-not-privatize-federal-land"&gt;Do not privatize federal land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/2025-06-29-weekly-post-summary</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/2025-06-29-weekly-post-summary</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-29 14:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>weeklysummary</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Adapting Language Models (SEAL)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs) are powerful but static; they lack mechanisms to adapt their weights in response to new tasks, knowledge, or examples. &lt;strong&gt;We introduce Self-Adapting LLMs (SEAL) 🦭, a framework that enables LLMs to self-adapt by generating their own finetuning data and update directives.&lt;/strong&gt; Given a new input, the model produces a self-edit — a generation that may restructure the information in different ways, specify optimization hyperparameters, or invoke tools for data augmentation and gradient-based updates. Through supervised finetuning (SFT), these self-edits result in persistent weight updates, enabling lasting adaptation. To train the model to produce effective self-edits, we use a reinforcement learning loop, using the downstream performance of the updated model as the reward signal. Unlike prior approaches that rely on separate adaptation modules or auxiliary networks, SEAL directly uses the model's generation to parameterize and control its own adaptation process. Experiments on knowledge incorporation and few-shot generalization show that SEAL is a promising step toward language models capable of self-directed adaptation in response to new data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate SEAL in two domains: (1) &lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Incorporation&lt;/strong&gt;, where the model integrates new factual information by generating logical implications as synthetic data, and (2) &lt;strong&gt;Few-Shot Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, where the model autonomously selects data augmentations and training hyperparameters to adapt to new abstract reasoning tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Continual-Intelligence"&gt;Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.10943"&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/self-adapting-language-models-seal</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/self-adapting-language-models-seal</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-16 20:33</pubDate>
      <category>agent</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>llm</category>
      <category>mit</category>
      <category>research</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How we built our multi-agent research system - Anthropic</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Great article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR: These are largely engineering problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey of this multi-agent system from prototype to production taught us critical lessons about system architecture, tool design, and prompt engineering. A multi-agent system consists of multiple agents (&lt;strong&gt;LLMs autonomously using tools in a loop&lt;/strong&gt;) working together. Our Research feature involves an agent that plans a research process based on user queries, and then uses tools to create parallel agents that search for information simultaneously. Systems with multiple agents introduce new challenges in agent coordination, evaluation, and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benefits of a multi-agent system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of search is compression: distilling insights from a vast corpus. &lt;strong&gt;Subagents facilitate compression by operating in parallel&lt;/strong&gt; with their own context windows, exploring different aspects of the question simultaneously before condensing the most important tokens for the lead research agent. Each subagent also provides &lt;strong&gt;separation of concerns&lt;/strong&gt;—distinct tools, prompts, and exploration trajectories—which reduces path dependency and enables thorough, independent investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once intelligence reaches a threshold, multi-agent systems become a vital way to scale performance. For instance, although individual humans have become more intelligent in the last 100,000 years, human societies have become exponentially more capable in the information age because of our collective intelligence and ability to coordinate. Even generally-intelligent agents face limits when operating as individuals; &lt;strong&gt;groups of agents can accomplish far more&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our internal evaluations show that multi-agent research systems excel especially for breadth-first queries that involve pursuing multiple independent directions simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-agent systems work mainly because they help spend enough tokens to solve the problem...Multi-agent architectures effectively scale token usage for tasks that exceed the limits of single agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve found that multi-agent systems excel at valuable tasks that involve heavy parallelization, information that exceeds single context windows, and interfacing with numerous complex tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Architecture overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Research system uses a multi-agent architecture with an orchestrator-worker pattern, where a lead agent coordinates the process while delegating to specialized subagents that operate in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional approaches using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) use static retrieval. That is, they fetch some set of chunks that are most similar to an input query and use these chunks to generate a response. In contrast, our architecture uses a &lt;strong&gt;multi-step search that dynamically finds relevant information, adapts to new findings, and analyzes results to formulate high-quality answers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prompt engineering and evaluations for research agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think like your agents.&lt;/strong&gt; To iterate on prompts, you must understand their effects. To help us do this, we built simulations using our Console with the exact prompts and tools from our system, then watched agents work step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teach the orchestrator how to delegate.&lt;/strong&gt; In our system, the lead agent decomposes queries into subtasks and describes them to subagents. Each subagent needs an &lt;strong&gt;objective&lt;/strong&gt;, an &lt;strong&gt;output format&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;guidance on the tools and sources to use&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;clear task boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;. Without detailed task descriptions, agents duplicate work, leave gaps, or fail to find necessary information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scale effort to query complexity.&lt;/strong&gt; Agents struggle to judge appropriate effort for different tasks, so we embedded scaling rules in the prompts...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tool design and selection are critical.&lt;/strong&gt; Agent-tool interfaces are as critical as human-computer interfaces. Using the right tool is efficient—often, it’s strictly necessary...Bad tool descriptions can send agents down completely wrong paths, so each tool needs a distinct purpose and a clear description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let agents improve themselves.&lt;/strong&gt;...When given a prompt and a failure mode, they are able to diagnose why the agent is failing and suggest improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start wide, then narrow down.&lt;/strong&gt; Search strategy should mirror expert human research: explore the landscape before drilling into specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guide the thinking process.&lt;/strong&gt;...Our testing showed that extended thinking improved instruction-following, reasoning, and efficiency. Subagents also plan, then use interleaved thinking after tool results to evaluate quality, identify gaps, and refine their next query. This makes subagents more effective in adapting to any task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel tool calling transforms speed and performance.&lt;/strong&gt;...For speed, we introduced two kinds of parallelization: (1) the lead agent spins up 3-5 subagents in parallel rather than serially; (2) the subagents use 3+ tools in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our prompting strategy focuses on instilling &lt;strong&gt;good heuristics rather than rigid rules&lt;/strong&gt;. We studied how skilled humans approach research tasks and encoded these strategies in our prompts—strategies like &lt;strong&gt;decomposing difficult questions into smaller tasks&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;carefully evaluating the quality of sources&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;adjusting search approaches based on new information&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;recognizing when to focus on depth (investigating one topic in detail) vs. breadth (exploring many topics in parallel)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Effective evaluation of agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...evaluating multi-agent systems presents unique challenges...Because we don’t always know what the right steps are, we usually can't just check if agents followed the “correct” steps we prescribed in advance. Instead, we need flexible evaluation methods that judge whether agents achieved the right outcomes while also following a reasonable process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start evaluating immediately with small samples.&lt;/strong&gt;...it’s best to start with small-scale testing right away with a few examples, rather than delaying until you can build more thorough evals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LLM-as-judge evaluation scales when done well.&lt;/strong&gt;...We used an LLM judge that evaluated each output against criteria in a rubric: &lt;strong&gt;factual accuracy&lt;/strong&gt; (do claims match sources?), &lt;strong&gt;citation accuracy&lt;/strong&gt; (do the cited sources match the claims?), &lt;strong&gt;completeness&lt;/strong&gt; (are all requested aspects covered?), &lt;strong&gt;source quality&lt;/strong&gt; (did it use primary sources over lower-quality secondary sources?), and &lt;strong&gt;tool efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; (did it use the right tools a reasonable number of times?)...[we] found that a single LLM call with a single prompt outputting scores from 0.0-1.0 and a pass-fail grade was the most consistent and aligned with human judgements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human evaluation catches what automation misses.&lt;/strong&gt;...Adding source quality heuristics to our prompts helped resolve this issue. Even in a world of automated evaluations, manual testing remains essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the best prompts for these agents are not just strict instructions, but &lt;strong&gt;frameworks for collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; that define the &lt;strong&gt;division of labor&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;problem-solving approaches&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;effort budgets&lt;/strong&gt;. Getting this right relies on &lt;strong&gt;careful prompting and tool design&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;solid heuristics&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;observability&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;tight feedback loops&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Production reliability and engineering challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agents are stateful and errors compound.&lt;/strong&gt;...Agents can run for long periods of time, maintaining state across many tool calls. This means we need to &lt;strong&gt;durably execute code and handle errors along the way&lt;/strong&gt;. Without effective mitigations, minor system failures can be catastrophic for agents. When errors occur, we can't just restart from the beginning...We combine the adaptability of AI agents built on Claude with deterministic safeguards like retry logic and regular checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging benefits from new approaches&lt;/strong&gt;...Adding full production tracing let us diagnose why agents failed and fix issues systematically. Beyond standard observability, we monitor agent decision patterns and interaction structures—all without monitoring the contents of individual conversations, to maintain user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployment needs careful coordination&lt;/strong&gt;...we use rainbow deployments to avoid disrupting running agents, by gradually shifting traffic from old to new versions while keeping both running simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synchronous execution creates bottlenecks.&lt;/strong&gt; Currently, our lead agents execute subagents synchronously, waiting for each set of subagents to complete before proceeding. This simplifies coordination, but creates bottlenecks in the information flow between agents. Asynchronous execution would enable additional parallelism: agents working concurrently and creating new subagents when needed. But this asynchronicity adds challenges in result coordination, state consistency, and error propagation across the subagents. As models can handle longer and more complex research tasks, we expect the performance gains will justify the complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the reasons described in this post, the gap between prototype and production is often wider than anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-agent research systems can operate reliably at scale with &lt;strong&gt;careful engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;comprehensive testing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;detail-oriented prompt and tool design&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;robust operational practices&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;tight collaboration between research, product, and engineering teams&lt;/strong&gt; who have a strong understanding of current agent capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/anthropic-how-we-built-multi-agent-system</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/responses/anthropic-how-we-built-multi-agent-system</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-16 17:39</pubDate>
      <category>agent</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>anthropic</category>
      <category>engineering</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thee Sacred Souls 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Some pictures from the Thee Sacred Souls concert I attended a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught them in New York when the tour started, so it was nice to catch them at the end of the tour as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, they were great performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/assets/images/feed/thee-sacred-souls-2025-1.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="A stage with Thee Sacred Souls band performing" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.luisquintanilla.me/assets/images/feed/thee-sacred-souls-2025-2.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thee Sacred Souls members on stage embracing" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/thee-sacred-souls-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.luisquintanilla.me/notes/thee-sacred-souls-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-14 12:30</pubDate>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>concert</category>
      <category>theesacredsouls</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>