<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - antennapod</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/antennapod</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'antennapod' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-01-05 21:04 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Reading Habit with Audiobooks, LibriVox, and AntennaPod</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Last year, I was able to complete my goal of reading 12 books or roughly one book per month. I kept track of some of the books I read in my [library page](/reviews).

I enjoyed most of the books I read. However, despite hitting my goal and averaging a book a month, I didn't build up a habit which is what I would've preferred. Many of the books I read last year, I read them during long periods of uninterrupted time, such as cross-country flights. The topic of goal setting and measuring the right thing could be an entire post, but I'll leave that for another time. 

Taking the learnings from last year, this year, I'll try to focus on building a reading habit rather than reading a set number of books. While I'd still like to finish at least one book per month, that's a metric I'll use to track general progress rather than making it the goal. Unless I'm reading something like War and Peace, I'd expect that by establishing a consistent cadence, I should be able to get through at least one book every month. Also, I'm only accounting for uninterrupted reading time blocks. Using audiobooks, I can continue building my reading habit while working out or doing chores. Kind of like having TV playing in the background. 

There is no shortage of audiobooks out there. Audible is one of the easiest ways to access audiobooks and they have a large selection to choose from. Personally, I don't use Audible. I don't like paying for a separate subscription, getting credits to "buy" books that I don't really own and can only listen through the Audible app. Instead, I use Spotify. I get [15 hours of access to audiobooks per month](https://support.spotify.com/us/article/audiobooks-access-plan/) as part of my subscription. While I still don't own the books and can only listen on the Spotify app, at least I'm not paying a separate subscription. Also, the 15 hour limit at this time is more than enough for me. 

The library is another amazing option. No subscription fees and you get access to your local library's entire digital catalog. Using the [Libby app](https://www.overdrive.com/apps/libby), you can borrow books and start listening for free. Selection though may be an issue here since you are limited to what's available through your local library. Pro-tip, universities and employers sometimes have libraries, so as an alumnus or employee, you can expand the number of books available to you by registering multiple libraries on the Libby app. Regardless of which library you choose though, you still have to go through the Libby app. 

The dream setup for me is, having direct access to the audiobook files so I can listen to them whenever and wherever I'd like. Similar to podcasts. Thanks to LibriVox and AntennaPod, that setup is possible. 

In case you're interested in setting up something similar, in this post, I'll briefly explain what LibriVox and AntennaPod are and show how you can use them to start listening to free audiobooks on your phone. 

## What is LibriVox?

[LibriVox](https://librivox.org/) is a website that provides a collection of free audiobooks from the public domain. Thanks to a vibrant community of volunteers, you can enjoy classics such as:

- [The Divine Comedy](https://librivox.org/the-divine-comedy-by-dante-alighieri/)
- [The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes](https://librivox.org/the-adventures-of-sherlock-holmes/)
- [Discourses of Epictetus](https://librivox.org/discourses-of-epictetus-by-epictetus/)
- [Roughing It](https://librivox.org/roughing-it/)
- [And many others...](https://librivox.org/search?primary_key=0&amp;search_category=title&amp;search_page=1&amp;search_form=get_results&amp;search_order=catalog_date)

It's important to note that the catalog is limited to public domain works. That means you won't have access to the latest self-help, business, or current events books. However, there are still thousands of books to keep you busy for an entire lifetime and the list is constantly growining since there are new works introduced into the public domain every year. 

Here's [a few notable literary works that entered the public domain in 2025](https://blog.archive.org/2025/01/01/welcome-to-the-public-domain-in-2025/) as well as the complete list of [literary works from 1929](https://archive.org/details/internetarchivebooks?tab=collection&amp;query=date%3A1929).

## What is Antennapod?

[AntennaPod](https://antennapod.org/) is an open-source podcast player for Android. 

The app has a ton of great features, such as [Podcast Index](https://podcastindex.org/) support, subscribe via RSS directly,  OPML import and export, chapters, adjustable playback speed, and for the past few years, a personalized yearly summary which is computed locally on your device [(here's my summary from 2024)](/notes/antennapod-echo-2024).

You can get AntennaPod from the Play Store or [F-Droid](https://f-droid.org/en/packages/de.danoeh.antennapod/)

## Keep track of new releases

LibriVox provides [several feeds](https://librivox.org/pages/librivox-feeds/). 

Since podcast distribution is primarly done through RSS and you can subscribe to podcasts directly using RSS feeds in AntennaPod, we can use the app to stay up to date with new audiobook releases. 

To subscribe to the LibriVox New Release feed:

1. Copy the LibriVox New Releases RSS feed URL to your clipboard: [https://librivox.org/rss/latest_releases](https://librivox.org/rss/latest_releases)
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.

    ![AntennaPod Add Podcast Dialog](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/add-podcast-antennapod.png)

1. Paste the LibriVox New Releases RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

At this point, you should see the feed listed in your AntennaPod subscriptions. 

By subscribing the LibriVox New Release feed, AntennaPod treats the feed as a podcast, and each new release entry or audiobook is like a podcast episode. 

For more information on subscribing to podcasts, see the [AntennaPod documentation](https://antennapod.org/documentation/getting-started/subscribe). 

## Add books to Antennapod

Subscribing to the new releases feed only notifies you when new books are added, you can't listen to or download the books. To do that, you'll need to subscribe to the RSS feed of the book you want to listen to in AntennaPod.

### From New Releases Feed

1. In AntennaPod's Subscription screen, select **LibriVox's New Releases**.
1. From the list of new releases, select the book you want to listen to. For example, "Room of One's Own" by Virginia Woolf.

    ![AntennaPod New Releases Feed](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-librivox-new-releases.png)

1. In the audiobook's screen, select **Visit Website**. This will take you to the LibriVox audiobook's page in the browser.

    ![AntennaPod Audiobook Screen](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-room-of-ones-own.png)

1. In the LibriVox audiobook page, select the book's RSS Feed.

    ![A Room of One's Own by Virginia Woolf LibriVox book page](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/librivox-room-ones-own.png)

1. Copy the book's feed URL to your clipboard.
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.
1. Paste the book's RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

### Any other books

The process works the same for other books but you'll have to use LibriVox as the entrypoint to browse books.

1. In your browser, navigate to LibriVox. 
1. Go to the audiobook page. For example, this is the page for [Walden](https://librivox.org/walden-by-henry-david-thoreau).
1. In the audiobook page, select the book's RSS Feed. For Walden, it's [https://librivox.org/rss/549](https://librivox.org/rss/549).
1. Copy the book's feed URL to your clipboard.
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.
1. Paste the book's RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

## Conclusion 

Although AntennaPod wasn't designed for audiobook listening, thanks to the flexibility of RSS feeds and the thankless work of the LibriVox community, you can easily listen to audiobooks for free on your mobile device. I plan on testing out this setup and seeing whether it helps keep my reading habit on track.]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/listen-audiobooks-librivox-antennapod</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/listen-audiobooks-librivox-antennapod</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-05 21:04 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>book</category>
      <category>audiobook</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>librivox</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>publicdomain</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antennapod Echo 2024</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;That's a lot of podcasts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-2024-1.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Antennapod Echo Podcast Hours Listened" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-2024-2.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Antennapod Echo Podcast Addict" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2024</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-11 20:52 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcasts</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>stats</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One more blog post for 2023?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Update from &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/weblogging-rewind-2023/"&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;. 2023 is still not over. I think I can squeeze out at least one more post for the year 🙂.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blog post counts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Note counts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;36&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/one-more-post-2023</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/one-more-post-2023</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-24 14:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>weblogging</category>
      <category>quantifiedself</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>stats</category>
      <category>analytics</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>fsharp</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>analytics</category>
      <category>pkm</category>
      <category>personalknowledgemanagement</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(We)blogging Rewind 2023 Continued</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I posted aggregate statistics about this website in the post &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/weblogging-rewind-2023/"&gt;(We)blogging Rewind 2023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it'd be cool to see which domains I referenced most in my responses. Here's the breakdown of the top 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;github.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;huggingface.co&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;arxiv.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;openai.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;www.theverge.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No surprise here given that AI was one of the top tags in my responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated script is here &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/resources/snippets/lqdev-me-website-post-metrics"&gt;stats.fsx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/weblogging-rewind-2023-continued</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/weblogging-rewind-2023-continued</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-24 09:39 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>weblogging</category>
      <category>quantifiedself</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>stats</category>
      <category>analytics</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>fsharp</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>analytics</category>
      <category>pkm</category>
      <category>personalknowledgemanagement</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(We)blogging Rewind 2023</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/spotify-wrapped-2023"&gt;Spotify Wrapped&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2023"&gt;Antennapod Echo&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to look back at my activity on this website for 2023. Here is the &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/resources/snippets/lqdev-me-website-post-metrics"&gt;snippet&lt;/a&gt; I used to generate these metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Posts by Year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog posts are my more formal, long-form content. This year, I published less blog posts than last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of that includes me getting in my head about what these posts &amp;quot;should be&amp;quot;. Historically, they have been detailed technical posts related to a project I've worked on like &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/receive-webmentions-fsharp-az-functions-fsadvent"&gt;Accept Webmentions using F#, Azure Functions, and RSS&lt;/a&gt;. I haven't stopped experimenting and tinkering, but because they aren't end-to-end solutions, I don't think of them as &amp;quot;blog post worthy&amp;quot;. That doesn't mean though that learnings and growth haven't come from them. In more recent blog posts like &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/ai-1999-1899"&gt;AI like it's 1999 or 1899&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/quick-thoughts-snapdragon-summit-2023"&gt;Quick thoughts about Snapdragon Summit 2023&lt;/a&gt;, I've started experimenting more with just posting. In 2024, I want to be more flexible in my posting and not worry too much about whether the blog posts are &amp;quot;good enough&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Microblog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site also contains a microblog feed, one for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; and another for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed/responses"&gt;responses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes tend to be original content that although can include links to external content, they are short-form and informal versions of blog posts. This post is an example of a note. This year, I posted less notes than last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, when these notes start to get long, I turn them into blog posts. &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/quick-thoughts-snapdragon-summit-2023"&gt;Quick thoughts about Snapdragon Summit 2023&lt;/a&gt; is an example of that. However, I haven't set a criteria for what makes a note &amp;quot;long&amp;quot;. This post for example I think is getting to the &amp;quot;blog post&amp;quot; length. I can't tell you why though, it's just &amp;quot;vibes&amp;quot;. One of the benefits of starting with notes types of posts is that the frame of mind is more informal which lets me just write and post without thinking too much about what the post &amp;quot;should be&amp;quot;. In 2024, I want to continue using notes as the starting point for these types of posts. Maybe later in the future, I just merge them both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Responses&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responses are reactions to content created / published by someone else. These can include bookmarks, replies, likes (star), and reposts (reshare). This year, I posted significantly more responses than last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;216&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;146&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm very happy with this, especially my bookmark use explained later. Not only am I happy because I'm actually making use of my website and the work I put in previous years that enabled me to publish all types of content but also because these responses create a log of my interactions with the internet over the years I can look back at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responses by Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking deeper into my responses and breaking them down by type, bookmarks take up the top spot with more than half of my responses being bookmarks. That makes sense since I'm usually bookmarking articles, papers, and other content I come across on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bookmark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;151&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reshare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;48&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reply&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;star&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start off with bookmarks. Bookmark style reponses on my website have slowly become my default capture system. Now, not everything I read and come across makes it onto my bookmarks. I'm experimenting with the first pass which I might just turn into another post. Generally, the things that are interesting or thought provoking, I post. Bookmark posts generally include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post title - Gives me a readable way to see what the post is about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source link - Provides a direct link to the source material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags - Enable me to index and organize related topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quotes / Notes - Provide highlights and things I thought were interesting about the post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all these pieces come together, they provide me with distilled bits of information that are organized in a way that enable quick retrieval and action when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on to other posts. Since the post type is effectively just metadata, the line between reshare, star, and reply is often blurry. It's not as blurry with replies because I use that to draft replies / comments to other posts and content on the internet. My &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tracy-durnell-20-blogging-anniversary"&gt;Tracy Durnell 20th anniversary of blogging&lt;/a&gt; post is an example of a reply. In these examples, the replies were directed at someone. However, for star and reshare, I'm still trying to understand where they fit in my flow. Today other than visually expressing the post type, the role these post types serve is webmentions. However, I'm not sure how many websites I create these post types for actually use webmentions. Maybe some analysis worth doing for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Responses by Tag (Top 5)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI and LLMs took the top spots which I think in general aligns with what was top of mind for everyone in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;104&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;llm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;42&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;untagged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;opensource&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much commentary here. Tags have helped me organize related content on my website. I do think that I get too high level with my tags and could do a better job of being more specific. Ultimately, there's no limit to the number of tags I can use so why not be liberal with it. The only self-imposed limitation I've placed on myself is the first 3 tags should be the most important because they're the ones that show up when my articles are automatically cross-posted to Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I'm happy with my activity and heavy use of my own website this year. I plan to make even more use of the bookmark type of posts in 2024 and plan on posting more whether that's as a note or blog post, just posting is something I want to work towards.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/weblogging-rewind-2023</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/weblogging-rewind-2023</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-23 02:28 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>weblogging</category>
      <category>quantifiedself</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>stats</category>
      <category>analytics</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>fsharp</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>analytics</category>
      <category>pkm</category>
      <category>personalknowledgemanagement</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antennapod Echo (Wrapped) 2023</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This was a nice surprise to see when I opened up Antennapod the other day. Using my listening statistics, it was able to compile a yearly summary for me (locally).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-wrapped-1.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Antennapod Echo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-wrapped-2.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Antennapod Echo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like I have a lot of catching up to do on the backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-wrapped-3.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Antennapod Echo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-wrapped-4.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Antennapod Echo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-wrapped-5.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Antennapod Echo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2023</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2023</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-12 21:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcasts</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>stats</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>