<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - creativity</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/creativity</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'creativity' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-09-12 07:55 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet's Hidden Creative Renaissance</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Great post from &lt;a href="https://blogtherapy.substack.com/about"&gt;Alexandra&lt;/a&gt;. Tons of great resources to explore as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...recently the indie web has been experiencing a revival, as more netizens look for connection outside the walled gardens created by tech giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kinds of posts and projects you’ll find are creative, personal, experimental, and sometimes so intimate you feel like you’re intruding. However, they’re not the kind of content that usually goes viral on TikTok. That’s beside the point. The focus isn’t on personal branding, growth or monetization, or “content” creation, but on freedom from those things. Instead of polished, 10-second snippets optimized for mass-appeal, engagement, and profit, these are largely slow-cooked projects made just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against a backdrop of accelerating enshittification and living chronically online — especially since the COVID pandemic — there’s growing interest in the slower, more intentional and connected experience the indie web promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In different corners of the mainstream internet, younger users are talking about reclaiming their attention spans, trading in their smartphones, writing essays for fun, journaling, discovering long reads, reading fiction, and picking up hobbies like crocheting or scrapbooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discoverability can be a challenge...But what seems like a bug can really be a feature of the small web experience: the point is to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the greater context of the global internet, the small web will never completely replace big platforms or serve every need, nor should it. Social media is still the main source of news in many parts of the world, offering valuable tools for community-building, commerce, even activism. For their part, most indie web creators are happy to exist outside of the mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/internet-hidden-creative-rennaissance-indieweb</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/internet-hidden-creative-rennaissance-indieweb</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 07:55 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>creativity</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Algorithm - J. Cole has a blog?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a place for me to share. I been wanting a lil blog for years. Somewhere to post random shit I fuck with where the audience is way smaller than it is on the social media platforms. Finally pulled the trigger, bare with us as we still developing this page and the layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into this while reading the post &lt;a href="https://herbertlui.net/blogging-for-smaller-audiences-and-deeper-connections/"&gt;Blogging for smaller audiences and deeper connections&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://herbertlui.net/"&gt;Herbert Lui&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at &lt;a href="https://www.inevitable.live/algorithm"&gt;other posts&lt;/a&gt;, it looks like he or at least someone is actively posting.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/inevitable-jcole-blog</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/inevitable-jcole-blog</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-25 21:34 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>creativity</category>
      <category>art</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Blog If Nobody Reads It?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a hidden value in blogging... You do it not for the applause but because it needs doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You write because you think, because you observe, because you need to put it somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone reads it? Bonus. If not? The work still got done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💯💯💯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with many of the points in Andy's post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have analytics on my website, so I couldn't tell you who or how many people are visiting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone &lt;a href="https://malici.ous.computer/@shellsharks/statuses/01JKGDJCE0WZYAWRB816J8JFG2"&gt;links to content they found on my website and tags me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/cdn-issue-fixed-redirects-working"&gt;sends me an e-mail letting me know something on my website is broken&lt;/a&gt; is when I know there's at least one person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the content on here serves as a reminder of how I've solved problems for myself. The microposts and responses are observations that capture a moment in time. If the messages reach someone on the other end and either solve their problem or resonate with them, I'm happy that happens, but I see that as a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/why-blog-nobody-reads-andy</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/why-blog-nobody-reads-andy</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-10 17:02 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>expression</category>
      <category>creativity</category>
      <category>writing</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>