<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - question</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/question</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'question' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-03-11 17:57 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>When should I check in stranger's luggage?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I was sitting at the airport waiting to board my flight and over the PA system, the usual &amp;quot;see something, say something&amp;quot; security announcements were going off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I've heard these many times before, this time for some reason there's one that caught my attention and got me thinking. I don't remember the exact words, but basically the gist of it said something like, &amp;quot;If anyone asks you to check in baggage other than your own, do not accept it&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I barely even want to deal with my own bags. Why would I want to deal with someone else's bag?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying to visualize scenarios where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone would come up to you and ask you to check in THEIR luggage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You would accept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe in scenarios where you're traveling with friends or family? In the case of family, maybe someone doesn't have a carry-on and if there's an extra bag that's small enough to be considered carry-on they'll &amp;quot;claim&amp;quot; it as their carry-on to not pay the extra fees. Still though, that's not checking it in. I'm just having a hard time seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting this out there ahead of time - no, stranger, I will not check in your bag.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/checking-in-strangers-luggage</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/checking-in-strangers-luggage</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-11 17:57 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>question</category>
      <category>airport</category>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>fun</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>