<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - timemanagement</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/timemanagement</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'timemanagement' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2023-12-09 10:08 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>To Everyone Who Asks For ‘Just A Little’ Of Your Time: Here’s What It Costs To Say Yes</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makers...need to have large blocks of uninterrupted, unscheduled time to do what they do. To create and think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep a maker’s schedule because I believe that anything else is anathema to deep work or creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca writes that if all the geniuses in history were to get together, none would be able explain our baffling relationship with time. He says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No person would give up even an inch of their estate, and the slightest dispute with a neighbor can mean hell to pay; yet we easily let others encroach on our lives—worse, we often pave the way for those who will take it over. No person hands out their money to passers-by, but to how many do each of us hand out our lives! We’re tight-fisted with property and money, yet think too little of wasting time, the one thing about which we should all be the toughest misers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time? Time is our most irreplaceable asset—we cannot buy more of it. We cannot get a second of it back. We can only hope to waste as little as possible. Yet somehow we treat it as most renewable of all resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/what-it-cost-to-say-yes-holiday</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/what-it-cost-to-say-yes-holiday</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-09 10:08 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>productivity</category>
      <category>timemanagement</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>