<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - podcast</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/podcast</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'podcast' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-09-12 22:20 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Ray Dalio on Diary of a CEO</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;If you get past the doom and gloom, this is a nice conversation with Ray Dalio on systems, team building, and mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=49RT6SQ8n0Y" title="Ray Dalio on Diary of a CEO"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/49RT6SQ8n0Y/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Ray Dalio on Diary of a CEO" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ray-dalio-diary-of-a-ceo-podcast-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ray-dalio-diary-of-a-ceo-podcast-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 22:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>diaryofaceo</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do I keep up with AI?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
This question comes up a lot in conversations. The short answer? I don’t. There’s just too much happening, too fast, for anyone to stay on top of everything.

While I enjoy sharing links and recommendations, I realized that a blog post might be more helpful. It gives folks a single place they can bookmark, share, and come back to on their own time, rather than having to dig through message threads where things inevitably get lost.

That said, here are some sources I use to try and stay informed:

- **Newsletters** are great for curated content. They highlight the top stories and help filter through the noise.
- **Blogs** are often the primary sources behind those newsletters. They go deeper and often cover a broader set of topics that might not make it into curated roundups.
- **Podcasts** serve a similar role. In some cases, they provide curation like newsletters and deep dives like blogs in others. Best of all, you can tune in while on the go making it a hands-free activity.

For your convenience, if any of the sources (including podcasts) I list below have RSS feeds, I’ve included them in my [AI Starter Pack](/collections/starter-packs//ai), which you can [download and import into your favorite RSS reader](/collections/starter-packs//ai/index.opml) (as long as it supports OPML file imports).

If you have some sources to share, [send me an e-mail](/contact). I'd love to keep adding to this list! If they have a feed I can subscribe to, even better.

## Newsletters

- [AlphaSignal](https://alphasignal.ai/)
- [The Batch](https://www.deeplearning.ai/the-batch/)
- [Latent Space](https://www.latent.space/)
- [TLDR AI](https://tldr.tech/ai)

## Blogs

I pride myself on being able to track down an RSS feed on just about any website, even if it’s buried or not immediately visible. Unfortunately, I haven't found a feed URL for either OpenAI or Anthropic which is annoying. 

**OpenAI and Anthropic, if you could do everyone a favor and drop a link, that would be great.** 

UPDATE: Thanks to [@m2vh@mastodontech.de](https://toot.lqdev.tech/@m2vh@mastodontech.de) for sharing the OpenAI news feed. 

I know I could use one of those web-page-to-RSS converters, but I'd much rather have an official link directly from the source.

- [OpenAI](https://openai.com/news/)
- [Anthropic](https://www.anthropic.com/news)
- [Google AI Blog](https://blog.google/technology/ai/)
- [AWS Machine Learning Blog](https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/)
- [Microsoft Research](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/)
- [Google Research](https://research.google/blog/)
- [Simon Willison](https://simonwillison.net/)

## Podcasts

- [AI Daily Brief](https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/the-ai-daily-brief-formerly-th-5260567)
- [TWIML AI Podcast](https://twimlai.com/)
- [Practical AI](https://changelog.com/practicalai)

## Subscribing to feeds

Now that I’ve got you here...

Let’s talk about the best way to access all these feeds. My preferred and recommended approach is using a feed reader.

When subscribing to content on the open web, feed readers are your secret weapon.

RSS might seem like it’s dead (it’s not—yet). In fact, it’s the reason you often hear the phrase, “Wherever you get your podcasts.” But RSS goes beyond podcasts. It’s widely supported by blogs, newsletters, and even social platforms like the Fediverse (Mastodon, PeerTube, etc.) and BlueSky. It’s also how I’m able to compile my [starter packs](/collections/starter-packs/). 

I've written more about RSS in [Rediscovering the RSS Protocol](/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom), but the short version is this: when you build on open standards like RSS and OPML, you’re building on freedom. Freedom to use the tools that work best for you. Freedom to own your experience. And freedom to support a healthier, more independent web.
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-i-keep-up-with-ai</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-i-keep-up-with-ai</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-27 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>starterpack</category>
      <category>newsletter</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Reading Habit with Audiobooks, LibriVox, and AntennaPod</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Last year, I was able to complete my goal of reading 12 books or roughly one book per month. I kept track of some of the books I read in my [library page](/reviews).

I enjoyed most of the books I read. However, despite hitting my goal and averaging a book a month, I didn't build up a habit which is what I would've preferred. Many of the books I read last year, I read them during long periods of uninterrupted time, such as cross-country flights. The topic of goal setting and measuring the right thing could be an entire post, but I'll leave that for another time. 

Taking the learnings from last year, this year, I'll try to focus on building a reading habit rather than reading a set number of books. While I'd still like to finish at least one book per month, that's a metric I'll use to track general progress rather than making it the goal. Unless I'm reading something like War and Peace, I'd expect that by establishing a consistent cadence, I should be able to get through at least one book every month. Also, I'm only accounting for uninterrupted reading time blocks. Using audiobooks, I can continue building my reading habit while working out or doing chores. Kind of like having TV playing in the background. 

There is no shortage of audiobooks out there. Audible is one of the easiest ways to access audiobooks and they have a large selection to choose from. Personally, I don't use Audible. I don't like paying for a separate subscription, getting credits to "buy" books that I don't really own and can only listen through the Audible app. Instead, I use Spotify. I get [15 hours of access to audiobooks per month](https://support.spotify.com/us/article/audiobooks-access-plan/) as part of my subscription. While I still don't own the books and can only listen on the Spotify app, at least I'm not paying a separate subscription. Also, the 15 hour limit at this time is more than enough for me. 

The library is another amazing option. No subscription fees and you get access to your local library's entire digital catalog. Using the [Libby app](https://www.overdrive.com/apps/libby), you can borrow books and start listening for free. Selection though may be an issue here since you are limited to what's available through your local library. Pro-tip, universities and employers sometimes have libraries, so as an alumnus or employee, you can expand the number of books available to you by registering multiple libraries on the Libby app. Regardless of which library you choose though, you still have to go through the Libby app. 

The dream setup for me is, having direct access to the audiobook files so I can listen to them whenever and wherever I'd like. Similar to podcasts. Thanks to LibriVox and AntennaPod, that setup is possible. 

In case you're interested in setting up something similar, in this post, I'll briefly explain what LibriVox and AntennaPod are and show how you can use them to start listening to free audiobooks on your phone. 

## What is LibriVox?

[LibriVox](https://librivox.org/) is a website that provides a collection of free audiobooks from the public domain. Thanks to a vibrant community of volunteers, you can enjoy classics such as:

- [The Divine Comedy](https://librivox.org/the-divine-comedy-by-dante-alighieri/)
- [The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes](https://librivox.org/the-adventures-of-sherlock-holmes/)
- [Discourses of Epictetus](https://librivox.org/discourses-of-epictetus-by-epictetus/)
- [Roughing It](https://librivox.org/roughing-it/)
- [And many others...](https://librivox.org/search?primary_key=0&amp;search_category=title&amp;search_page=1&amp;search_form=get_results&amp;search_order=catalog_date)

It's important to note that the catalog is limited to public domain works. That means you won't have access to the latest self-help, business, or current events books. However, there are still thousands of books to keep you busy for an entire lifetime and the list is constantly growining since there are new works introduced into the public domain every year. 

Here's [a few notable literary works that entered the public domain in 2025](https://blog.archive.org/2025/01/01/welcome-to-the-public-domain-in-2025/) as well as the complete list of [literary works from 1929](https://archive.org/details/internetarchivebooks?tab=collection&amp;query=date%3A1929).

## What is Antennapod?

[AntennaPod](https://antennapod.org/) is an open-source podcast player for Android. 

The app has a ton of great features, such as [Podcast Index](https://podcastindex.org/) support, subscribe via RSS directly,  OPML import and export, chapters, adjustable playback speed, and for the past few years, a personalized yearly summary which is computed locally on your device [(here's my summary from 2024)](/notes/antennapod-echo-2024).

You can get AntennaPod from the Play Store or [F-Droid](https://f-droid.org/en/packages/de.danoeh.antennapod/)

## Keep track of new releases

LibriVox provides [several feeds](https://librivox.org/pages/librivox-feeds/). 

Since podcast distribution is primarly done through RSS and you can subscribe to podcasts directly using RSS feeds in AntennaPod, we can use the app to stay up to date with new audiobook releases. 

To subscribe to the LibriVox New Release feed:

1. Copy the LibriVox New Releases RSS feed URL to your clipboard: [https://librivox.org/rss/latest_releases](https://librivox.org/rss/latest_releases)
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.

    ![AntennaPod Add Podcast Dialog](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/add-podcast-antennapod.png)

1. Paste the LibriVox New Releases RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

At this point, you should see the feed listed in your AntennaPod subscriptions. 

By subscribing the LibriVox New Release feed, AntennaPod treats the feed as a podcast, and each new release entry or audiobook is like a podcast episode. 

For more information on subscribing to podcasts, see the [AntennaPod documentation](https://antennapod.org/documentation/getting-started/subscribe). 

## Add books to Antennapod

Subscribing to the new releases feed only notifies you when new books are added, you can't listen to or download the books. To do that, you'll need to subscribe to the RSS feed of the book you want to listen to in AntennaPod.

### From New Releases Feed

1. In AntennaPod's Subscription screen, select **LibriVox's New Releases**.
1. From the list of new releases, select the book you want to listen to. For example, "Room of One's Own" by Virginia Woolf.

    ![AntennaPod New Releases Feed](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-librivox-new-releases.png)

1. In the audiobook's screen, select **Visit Website**. This will take you to the LibriVox audiobook's page in the browser.

    ![AntennaPod Audiobook Screen](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-room-of-ones-own.png)

1. In the LibriVox audiobook page, select the book's RSS Feed.

    ![A Room of One's Own by Virginia Woolf LibriVox book page](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/librivox-room-ones-own.png)

1. Copy the book's feed URL to your clipboard.
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.
1. Paste the book's RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

### Any other books

The process works the same for other books but you'll have to use LibriVox as the entrypoint to browse books.

1. In your browser, navigate to LibriVox. 
1. Go to the audiobook page. For example, this is the page for [Walden](https://librivox.org/walden-by-henry-david-thoreau).
1. In the audiobook page, select the book's RSS Feed. For Walden, it's [https://librivox.org/rss/549](https://librivox.org/rss/549).
1. Copy the book's feed URL to your clipboard.
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.
1. Paste the book's RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

## Conclusion 

Although AntennaPod wasn't designed for audiobook listening, thanks to the flexibility of RSS feeds and the thankless work of the LibriVox community, you can easily listen to audiobooks for free on your mobile device. I plan on testing out this setup and seeing whether it helps keep my reading habit on track.]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/listen-audiobooks-librivox-antennapod</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/listen-audiobooks-librivox-antennapod</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-05 21:04 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>book</category>
      <category>audiobook</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>librivox</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>publicdomain</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Wrapped 2024 AI Generated Podcast</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;While looking at &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/spotify-wrapped-2024"&gt;Spotify Wrapped this year&lt;/a&gt;, I completely missed the AI-generated podcast that came along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As cool as this is, &lt;strong&gt;it should've been opt-in&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I would hope that when I clicked &amp;quot;I Agree&amp;quot; on the user agreement, the use of my data in this way is covered (for Spotify's sake), it's not clear or easy to find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What data was shared with Google's NotebookLM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What Google will do with that data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a reason I purposefully haven't linked Spotify to other accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there's probably hundreds of worse ways my data is being used I don't know about. This one though was hard to miss and a sad reminder that often you don't learn about how your data is being used until after the fact. Cases like this are not really a big deal. So what if you know I was going through a &amp;quot;Witchy Jam Band Phsychedelic Rock&amp;quot; phase in September? Where it does matter though is when it involves more personal and sensitive data. Again, because we don't realize it until after the fact, it's not until then that we learn what we're giving up when we make the simple, often uninformed, decision to select &amp;quot;I Agree&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://wrappedaipodcast.spotifycdn.com/bDEn3i-uWoItOTYMmcRcNGKBqZ18M9ygFTAY0X8YHXk.mp4" class="img-fluid" alt="AI Genereated Spotify Wrapped Podcast" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;video controls="" autoplay="" name="media"&gt;&lt;source src="https://wrappedaipodcast.spotifycdn.com/bDEn3i-uWoItOTYMmcRcNGKBqZ18M9ygFTAY0X8YHXk.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt; --&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/spotify-wrapped-2024-podcast-notebook-lm</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/spotify-wrapped-2024-podcast-notebook-lm</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-05 09:02 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>spotify</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>spotifywrapped</category>
      <category>google</category>
      <category>notebooklm</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>generativeai</category>
      <category>genai</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations on ten years of Overcast</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I no longer have an iPhone, but whenever anyone asks for a podcast app recommendation, Overcast is the first one I mention. Congrats on 10 years. Here's to many more.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/congratulations-overcast-ten-years</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/congratulations-overcast-ten-years</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-04 17:07 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>app</category>
      <category>overcast</category>
      <category>anniversary</category>
      <category>milestone</category>
      <category>apple</category>
      <category>ios</category>
      <category>rss</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Questions - Debunking AI Model Capabilities / Distributed Webs of Trust</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvlfCW3Ec1g" title="Deep Questions Podcast Debunking AI Episode Thumbnail"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/OvlfCW3Ec1g/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Deep Questions Podcast Debunking AI Episode Thumbnail" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice job by Cal debunking misconceptions about AI model capabilities. The segment highlights a few points I cover in my unpublished &lt;a href="https://github.com/lqdev/luisquintanilla.me/blob/main/_scratch/nolm-not-only-language-models.md"&gt;NoLM - Not Only Language Models&lt;/a&gt; blog post. Specifically the fact that Language Models on their own can't do much and need to be connected to data sources and other systems. Complex AI systems will be built with more specialized roles and leverage various components for their planning and execution. In the end though, models will require integration into existing systems. Those integrations need to be done by people, meaning humans are still in control of the AI-assisted system capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OvlfCW3Ec1g&amp;amp;t=4082" title="Deep Questions Podcast Debunking AI Episode Thumbnail"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/OvlfCW3Ec1g/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Same Deep Questions Podcast Debunking AI Episode Thumbnail" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the podcast, Cal takes a question about distributed webs of trust. I agree with Cal's point of using existing open standards like RSS for content consumption. It's the reason you often hear the phrase, &amp;quot;or wherever you get your podcasts&amp;quot;. Assuming you have a program that can read an RSS feed, you can follow all types of content. On the topic of discovery, Cal makes the suggestion of using distributed webs of trust. Using domain names and linking as ways of discovering content. While blogrolls were not directly called out, it's one of the benefits a curated set of links provides.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/deep-questions-debunking-genai-rss-blogroll</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/deep-questions-debunking-genai-rss-blogroll</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-24 20:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>deepquestions</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>calnewport</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro.blog - Podcast hosting for $5</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;This is cool! The Micro.blog premium plan has tons of great features as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six years ago, we launched our $10/month plan with podcast hosting. Since then we’ve added several big features to the plan...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to bring the podcast feature to more people, so we’re moving it down to the standard $5/month plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/microblog-podcast-hosting</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/microblog-podcast-hosting</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-30 21:27 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>hosting</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New podcast (Better Offline) added to blogroll</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;While doing chores today, I put on one of the episodes from &lt;a href="https://www.wheresyoured.at/about/"&gt;Ed Zitron's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.betteroffline.com/"&gt;Better Offline podcast&lt;/a&gt;. This resulted me in me basically binging the rest of the episodes on the backlog. Also, it's now made its way into the regular rotation with other podcasts and the &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;podroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/better-offline-podroll</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/better-offline-podroll</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-07 16:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>podroll</category>
      <category>betteroffline</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guest host Hank Green makes Nilay Patel explain why websites have a future</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the last platform on the web of any scale or influence is Google Search. And so, over time, webpages have become dramatically optimized for Google Search. And that means the kinds of things people write about, the containers that we write in, are mostly designed to be optimized for Google Search. They’re not designed for, “I need to just quickly tell you about this and move on.” Our little insight was, “Well, what if we just don’t do that? What if we only write for the people who come directly to our website instead of the people who find our articles through Search or Google Discover or whatever other Google platforms are in the world?” And so we just made these little blog posts, and the idea was, if you just come to our website one more time a day because there’s one more thing to look at that you’ll like, we will be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more and more people are starting to realize, “Oh, we should just make the websites more valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...if you start writing for other people, which is the heart of what a blog post really is: it’s you trying to entertain yourself and trying to entertain just a handful of other people, you’re going to go really much farther than trying to satisfy the robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why am I writing in the text box that pays money to Elon and Mark [Zuckerberg] and not my text box?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Why do we all work for free? Look, we want to talk about the platform era and media. Why do we all work for free?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
...It’s very confusing, and there are a lot of reasons. If you just sit back and think about why, there are a million reasons why.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
One, the software is nicer to use than most CMSes. You just pick one. Name a company that makes a CMS. They’re like, “Is this as fun to use as Twitter?” And the answer is no. Flatly no. Even the one we have now for quick posts is not as fun to use as Twitter was in its heyday. Will this immediately bring me the dopamine hit of immediate feedback? No.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
[When redesigning the website]...the first instinct was, “Let’s at least make it easier to publish. Let’s at least remove the barriers to entry to getting on the website, and then we can do comments, and then we can think about how we can distribute in different ways.” So that is working. My team is happier. We did not know that the Twitter thing would happen, but the Twitter thing happened, and our desire to publish in the boxes we controlled went up as a group. And then, on top of it, our audience saw that we were having fun. And once you are having fun anywhere on the internet, people sort of gravitate to you. So traffic has gone up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution actually just creates the work or creates the pressures that force all the work to be the same. And I think over time that’s what drives the audiences away. So there’s a real change in how these platforms work, where, over time, they just become more and more of the same thing and the creators become more and more the same. And that’s a little exhausting. And every place where you see open distribution, you see a huge variety of creators and content.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Podcasts have basically open distribution. Like podcast or distributor RSS feeds, that means people kind of own their distribution, there’s a vast array of podcast creators. There’s a vast array of podcast formats. They don’t all sound like the beginning of YouTube videos or whatever. And I hate to keep picking on YouTube; you can pick any algorithmic platform, and it’s the same. TikTokers are more the same than different. Podcasters are more different than the same. The web is distributed largely through websites and through RSS. There’s a huge variety of websites and the way websites look. But then you see the algorithmic search pressure push web design kind of all under the same box.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Newsletters distributed by email: open distribution. The newsletter economy is full of a huge variety of creators doing a huge variety of things. They’re more different than the same. So all I see with the fediverse is, “Oh, this is going to open social distribution up a little bit.” It’s going to allow us to control our distribution networks. It’s going to say, “I’m not on Twitter, but people on Twitter can follow my website, and I can go promote that follow anywhere I want in different ways and build an audience outside of the pressures of the algorithm.” To me, just that, that ability to try, is 1 percent better.
&lt;br&gt;
If you’re me and you run a big website and you are thinking, “How can I redistribute this website, how can I reach people more directly?” my brain is lit up. You should be able to follow me at TheVerge.com and see all my quick posts in your Threads account when Threads federates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/decoder-nilay-patel-why-websites-are-the-future</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/decoder-nilay-patel-why-websites-are-the-future</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-04 22:45 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>decoder</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>platforms</category>
      <category>blogs</category>
      <category>technology</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JRE - Now available wherever you get your podcasts</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Since Joe Rogan went exclusive with Spotify, I maybe listened to a handful of episodes. The main reason for it is, I don't use Spotify to listen to podcasts. Periodically, I'd scroll through the feed to see if he had any intereting guests on. As part of his new contract, the podcast is now available on other platforms. That means you can listen &lt;a href="https://podbay.fm/p/the-joe-rogan-experience/about"&gt;wherever you get your podcasts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/jre-wherever-you-get-your-podcasts</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/jre-wherever-you-get-your-podcasts</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-26 18:29 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>jre</category>
      <category>joerogan</category>
      <category>audio</category>
      <category>spotify</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast - localfirst.fm</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A podcast about local-first software development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/localfirstfm-podcast</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/localfirstfm-podcast</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-20 21:38 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>development</category>
      <category>software</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>tech</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>localfirst</category>
      <category>local</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Club TWiT Shows Now Open to Everyone!</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that our Club TWiT shows are now available to everyone in audio form. That's right, you can now listen to your favorite shows anytime, anywhere, and it's all starting as early as the end of this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/club-twit-shows-available-to-all</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/club-twit-shows-available-to-all</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-14 22:37 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>twit</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>tech</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talking about Open Source LLMs on Oxide and Friends</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recorded &lt;a href="https://oxide.computer/podcasts/oxide-and-friends/1692510"&gt;an episode&lt;/a&gt; of the Oxide and Friends podcast on Monday, talking with Bryan Cantrill and Adam Leventhal about Open Source LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Too important for a small group to control...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This technology is clearly extremely important to the future of all sorts of things that we want to do.
&lt;br&gt;
I am totally on board with it. There are people who will tell you that it’s all hype and bluster. I’m over that. This stuff’s real. It’s really useful.
&lt;br&gt;
It is far too important for a small group of companies to completely control this technology. That would be genuinely disastrous. And I was very nervous that was going to happen, back when it was just OpenAI and Anthropic that had the only models that were any good, that was really nerve-wracking.
&lt;br&gt;
Today I’m not afraid of that at all, because there are dozens of organizations now that have managed to create one of these things...
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On LLMs for learning...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting things for me about this technology is that it’s a teaching assistant that is always available to you.
&lt;br&gt;
You know that thing where you’re learning—especially in a classroom environment—and you miss one little detail and you start falling further and further behind everyone else because there was this one little thing you didn’t quite catch, and you don’t want to ask stupid questions?
&lt;br&gt;
You can ask stupid questions of ChatGPT anytime you like and it can help guide you through to the right answer.
&lt;br&gt;
That’s kind of a revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/talking-open-source-llms-oxide-friends-willison</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/talking-open-source-llms-oxide-friends-willison</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-17 20:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>llm</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLOSS Weekly is now on Hackaday!</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that Hackaday is the new home of FLOSS Weekly, a long-running podcast about free, libre, and open-source software! The TWiT network hosted the podcast for an incredible seventeen years, but due to some changes on their end, they recently had to wind things down. They were gracious enough to let us pick up the torch, with Jonathan Bennett now taking over hosting duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That didn't take long. Last month &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/floss-weekly-ends-twit-start-of-an-era/"&gt;I learned FLOSS Weekly was ending on the TWiT network&lt;/a&gt;. It's great to see it has found a new home in Hackaday! Time to update the RSS feeds and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;podroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/floss-weekly-now-on-hackaday</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/floss-weekly-now-on-hackaday</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 12:15 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>floss</category>
      <category>hackaday</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning mind, body, and soul</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In the past two weeks I've been listening to a few episodes from the &lt;a href="https://www.hubermanlab.com/podcast"&gt;Huberman Lab podcast&lt;/a&gt;. In many of the episodes, the host, Dr. Andrew Huberman, brings on guests to talk about topics like nutrition, fertility, motivation, finding your purpose, and many others. It's interesting though that despite the large diversity of topics and guests, at their core, many of the conversations ended up coming back to mind, body, and soul. More specifically, nurturing those various aspects of our lives. This includes but is not limited to, fueling your body with the right foods, building community, being active, learning new things, exposing yourself to new experiences, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/mind-body-soul-huberman</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/mind-body-soul-huberman</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-07 15:18 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>lifestyle</category>
      <category>wellness</category>
      <category>health</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLOSS Weekly ended its run on the TWiT network</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 17 years and 761 episodes, FLOSS Weekly ended its run on the TWiT network yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nooo! So sad to hear that FLOSS Weekly is ending, especially after learning that &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/farewell-privacy-security-osint-podcast/"&gt;The Privacy, Security, and OSINT Show with Michael Bazzell ended as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least there's some hope at the end of Doc's post which hints at it living on in some form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, FLOSS Weekly has not slipped below the waves. I expect it will be picked up somewhere else on the Web, and wherever you get your podcasts. (I love that expression because it means podcasting isn’t walled into some giant’s garden.) When that happens, I’ll point to it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it was good while it lasted. Also, there's still &lt;a href="https://www.reality2cast.com/"&gt;Reality 2.0&lt;/a&gt; where the guests and topics are just as interesting and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/floss-weekly-ends-twit-start-of-an-era</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/floss-weekly-ends-twit-start-of-an-era</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-14 21:10 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>floss</category>
      <category>twit</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farewell to The Privacy, Security, and OSINT Show</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...a farewell episode was released on November 20th, 2023 entitled “My Irish Exit”. It was finally officially confirmed that [The Privacy, Security, and OSINT Show with Michael Bazzell]...has reached an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's unfortunate. I really enjoyed listening to this show and even had it listed in my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;podroll&lt;/a&gt;. The UNREDACTED magazine had great content as well.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/farewell-privacy-security-osint-podcast</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/farewell-privacy-security-osint-podcast</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-13 20:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>osint</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress at 25 and the Indie Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Good discussion on the open web, self-hosting, radio, and the indie web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/podcast-wordpress-indieweb-reality2</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/podcast-wordpress-indieweb-reality2</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-08-30 21:02 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terry Carnation</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Can't believe I hadn't heard about these podcasts before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://radiorentalusa.com/"&gt;Radio Rental&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://audioboom.com/channels/5046661"&gt;Dark Air&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love the horror anthology vibes like Tales From The Crypt and Freakshow for Radio Rental. For Dark Air, I really like the Space Ghost Coast to Coast and actual Coast to Coast feel. Best of all, the host Terry Carnation is Rainn Wilson. Even &lt;a href="https://www.terrycarnation.com/"&gt;Terry's website&lt;/a&gt; has a great 90's web feel to it. Looks like Dark Air has been off the air for some time, but hopefully Radio Rental keeps publishing content.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/terry-carnation</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/terry-carnation</guid>
      <pubDate>07/03/2022 22:04 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>terrycarnation</category>
      <category>radiorental</category>
      <category>darkair</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archive 81 - so far so good!</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;About 2 episodes into the show &lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80222802"&gt;Archive 81&lt;/a&gt; on Netflix and so far so good. I listened to a few episodes of the &lt;a href="https://www.archive81.com/"&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; (by the same name) it's based on a few years ago. Now it makes me want to go back and listen to it again. It also makes me think about what the &lt;a href="https://theblacktapespodcast.com/"&gt;Black Tapes&lt;/a&gt; could've been had it gotten a TV or movie adaptation. If you're into the found footage, cult horror type of stories (think Blair Witch + Midsommar + Rosemary's Baby), definitely check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/archive-81-black-tapes</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/archive-81-black-tapes</guid>
      <pubDate>01/15/2022 21:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>archive81</category>
      <category>netflix</category>
      <category>horror</category>
      <category>suspense</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>