<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - curiosity</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/curiosity</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'curiosity' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-01-08 21:27 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>A Year of Curiosity</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we encounter something new and interesting, our brains release dopamine – the same neurotransmitter associated with reward and pleasure. This creates a simple pattern: the more we learn, the more we want to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This drive to explore and understand isn’t just nice to have – it’s essential to who we are as humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no single “right” way to be curious. Learning practical skills like coding or cooking, diving into topics like history or science, joining groups of people who share your interests… These are all great ways to inject more curiosity into your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Designing a year of curiosity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly:&lt;/strong&gt; Design one tiny experiment at the beginning of each month This could be as simple as exploring a topic you know nothing about, trying a new hobby, or doing something that pushes you out of your comfort zone...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekly:&lt;/strong&gt; Every week, take 10 to 15 minutes to conduct a weekly review. What went well this week? What didn’t go as planned? What will you focus on next week? This could mean doubling down on what worked or tweaking something that didn’t...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily:&lt;/strong&gt; Create at least one moment of curiosity in your day, no matter how small. Experiment with a new recipe or tool, have one meaningful conversation, try a journaling prompt, or take a different route to work. Even one minute of curiosity a day can add up to a much richer life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/year-of-curiosity</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/year-of-curiosity</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-08 21:27 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>innovation</category>
      <category>exploration</category>
      <category>curiosity</category>
      <category>growth</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>