<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - smallweb</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/smallweb</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'smallweb' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-09-12 21:50 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Just ordered Internet Phone Book</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[Album containing 0 photos]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/media/just-ordered-internet-phone-book-issue-1</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/media/just-ordered-internet-phone-book-issue-1</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 21:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet's Hidden Creative Renaissance</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Great post from &lt;a href="https://blogtherapy.substack.com/about"&gt;Alexandra&lt;/a&gt;. Tons of great resources to explore as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...recently the indie web has been experiencing a revival, as more netizens look for connection outside the walled gardens created by tech giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kinds of posts and projects you’ll find are creative, personal, experimental, and sometimes so intimate you feel like you’re intruding. However, they’re not the kind of content that usually goes viral on TikTok. That’s beside the point. The focus isn’t on personal branding, growth or monetization, or “content” creation, but on freedom from those things. Instead of polished, 10-second snippets optimized for mass-appeal, engagement, and profit, these are largely slow-cooked projects made just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against a backdrop of accelerating enshittification and living chronically online — especially since the COVID pandemic — there’s growing interest in the slower, more intentional and connected experience the indie web promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In different corners of the mainstream internet, younger users are talking about reclaiming their attention spans, trading in their smartphones, writing essays for fun, journaling, discovering long reads, reading fiction, and picking up hobbies like crocheting or scrapbooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discoverability can be a challenge...But what seems like a bug can really be a feature of the small web experience: the point is to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the greater context of the global internet, the small web will never completely replace big platforms or serve every need, nor should it. Social media is still the main source of news in many parts of the world, offering valuable tools for community-building, commerce, even activism. For their part, most indie web creators are happy to exist outside of the mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/internet-hidden-creative-rennaissance-indieweb</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/internet-hidden-creative-rennaissance-indieweb</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 07:55 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>creativity</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small (web) is beautiful</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dream of a web that fosters healthy conversations, together with personal and intellectual growth. The world is diverse and fascinating, and we can be information explorers together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/small-web-is-beautiful</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/small-web-is-beautiful</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-21 19:13 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using my domain for discovery in Mastodon</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;For a while, I've known that I can use my domain and the WebFinger protocol to aid with discovery in the Fediverse, specifically Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried implementing this feature on my website a while back but was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I got an itch to try it again and got it working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, what I was doing wrong the first time was, I was trying to use &lt;code&gt;lqdev.me&lt;/code&gt; as the domain. Currently, my domain is not set up to use apex / naked domains. Therefore, it makes sense why that didn't work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I used &lt;code&gt;www.lqdev.me&lt;/code&gt;, everything seemed to be working fine. The implementation isn't perfect, because technically you can use any username. &lt;a href="https://www.hanselman.com/blog/use-your-own-user-domain-for-mastodon-discoverability-with-the-webfinger-protocol-without-hosting-a-server"&gt;Scott Hanselman does a nice job explaining that&lt;/a&gt;. The important part though is that &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/now-on-bluesky"&gt;my persence on the Fediverse is now directly linked to my domain, just like it is with Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;. This goes beyond the link verification Mastodon provides. As a result, it provides more flexibility and opportunities to shape my presence on the Fediverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in implementing it for yourself, there's a ton of guides, but here's the one I used: &lt;a href="https://guide.toot.as/guide/use-your-own-domain/"&gt;Use your own user @ domain for Mastodon discoverability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't like the &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain. So far I've put up with it for a while but this might be the forcing function to finally getting the apex domain setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you can search my account in Mastodon using &lt;code&gt;@lqdev@www.lqdev.me&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/using-domain-mastodon-discovery</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/using-domain-mastodon-discovery</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 09:35 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>cdn</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You should be using an RSS reader</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;Yes, you should!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the conduit through which I experience Molly's excellent work is totally enshittification-proof, and the more I use it, the easier it is for everyone to be less enshittified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
This conduit is anti-lock-in, it works for nearly the whole internet. It is surveillance-resistant, far more accessible than the web or any mobile app interface. It is my secret super-power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
It's RSS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
...But RSS isn't just good for the news! It's good for everything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Your RSS reader doesn't (necessarily) have an algorithm. By default, you'll get everything as it appears, in reverse-chronological order.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Now, you sign up to so many feeds that you're feeling overwhelmed and you want an algorithm to prioritize posts – or recommend content. Lots of RSS readers have some kind of algorithm and recommendation system...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
But you control the algorithm, you control the recommendations. And if a new RSS reader pops up with an algorithm you're dying to try, you can export all the feeds you follow with a single click, which will generate an OPML file. Then, with one click, you can import that OPML file into any other RSS reader in existence and all your feeds will be seamlessly migrated there. You can delete your old account, or you can even use different readers for different purposes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
RSS basically works like social media should work. Using RSS is a chance to visit a utopian future in which the platforms have no power, and all power is vested in publishers, who get to decide what to publish, and in readers, who have total control over what they read and how, without leaking any personal information through the simple act of reading.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
And here's the best part: every time you use RSS, you bring that world closer into being!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Unlike those largely useless, performative boycotts of widely used platforms, switching to RSS doesn't require that you give anything up. Not only does switching to RSS let you continue to follow all the newsletters, webpages and social media accounts you're following now, it makes doing so better: more private, more accessible, and less enshittified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Using RSS to follow the stuff that matters to you will have an immediate, profoundly beneficial impact on your own digital life – and it will appreciably, irreversibly nudge the whole internet towards a better state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article by &lt;a href="https://craphound.com/bio/"&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written at length on my website as to &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom"&gt;why I enjoy RSS&lt;/a&gt;. My use goes back to the days of Google Reader. Like many, once that was disbanded, my consumption pretty much shifted to social media for a few years. After growing dissatisfaction with the limitations and lack of control over my feed, I started my journey back to RSS readers eventually landing on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/subscribed-to-1042-feeds-newsblur"&gt;NewsBlur&lt;/a&gt; and elfeed as my readers of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this website, RSS plays an important role in a few areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS is how I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/website-feeds-opml/"&gt;Enable discovery of my own feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;Enable visitors to subscribe and get the latest content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps"&gt;Syndicate posts to Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented/"&gt;Enable feed discovery of websites I subscribe to&lt;/a&gt; through my:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;Blogroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;Podroll (podcasts)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/youtube/"&gt;YouTubeRoll?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/forums/"&gt;ForumRoll?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can you get started?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;a href="https://aboutfeeds.com/"&gt;about feeds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the many &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/we-love-rss"&gt;getting started guides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse through &lt;a href="https://blogroll.club/"&gt;blogrolls and feed catalogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24036427/rss-feed-reader-best"&gt;Explore various feed readers&lt;/a&gt; to find the one that works best for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/you-should-be-using-rss-reader-pluralistic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/you-should-be-using-rss-reader-pluralistic</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-10-18 08:54 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>pluralistic</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>freeweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for our web - A talk from XOXO</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;I haven't watched the entire talk, but here are some excerpts from the transcript that resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MTaeVVAvk-c" title="Thumbnail of Molly White Speaking at XOXO Conference"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/MTaeVVAvk-c/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thumbnail of Molly White Speaking at XOXO Conference" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a lot of people, the web feels worse than it used to. Much of our time is spent on a handful of giant social networks that do everything they can to keep people in their apps for as long as possible, even if it has detrimental effects on the people who are using them, or on the social networks themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites outside of these handful of social networks are harder and harder to even find, and partially because of that, they have a harder and harder time sustaining themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is left for those of us who saw the web as an infinite canvas, a tool to reach those who we never could have dreamed of reaching before, a medium that could stretch the limits of what was even possible in an analog world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...having said all this, would it surprise you to hear that now more than ever, I feel that same burning feeling of excitement around what’s possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s because what really sucks about the web these days, what has us feeling despair and anger, has everything to do with the industry that has formed around the web, but not the web itself. The web is still just a substrate on which anything can be built. Most importantly, the web is the people who use it, not the companies that have established themselves around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the widespread disillusionment that we’re seeing may actually be a good thing. More people than ever have realized that the utopian dreams of a web that could only bring about positive and wonderful things might have been misguided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this knowledge comes power. The power to shape the web that we want to see, while fighting against the one that we don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience in fighting this fight has helped to convince me of just how much power we, everyday normal people, have—even when we’re staring down massive platforms and billion-dollar companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up doing what I enjoy doing—building something cool, mostly for the sake of building it, and writing down what I saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...this simple act of building something interesting and somewhat different had an impact that I could not have anticipated. It turned out that people were starving for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even though I was a nobody, it had a major impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lesson was clear. The tech industry, even with its billions of dollars, is not an indomitable force. Though they can and will ignore what people want from them, they cannot control what those people think. And the tide can turn against them. And it doesn’t always take a job at The New York Times or a huge pre-established platform to become one of the voices speaking up, helping to turn that tide. Sometimes you just have to make something cool. And using the very same technology that enabled crypto guys to sell their scam tokens, or the boosterist journalists to publish obsequious descriptions of companies that were really selling vaporware, or the crypto community to spam social media with promotions for their NFTs, I was able to do something a little different to push back against that very same phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What they don’t seem to realize is that in doing so, by reducing the web only to the types of expression that can happen within their cramped boxes—where you can’t write more than 280 characters, or you can’t publish your cool JavaScript-based art project, or you can’t say the things that you want to say without getting de-boosted by the engagement maximization machine, or you can’t read what your friends are posting without the platform interjecting offensive troll posts or soulless AI-generated meme images—they’re creating a thirst for everything outside of those boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A thirst for what the web really is—a medium, a conduit, a tool that is used by readers and artists and creators and explorers, not a gatekeeper that seems to be in an ever more adversarial relationship with everyone who uses it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platforms I talk about are deeply entrenched to the point where many people barely use the web outside of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the platforms do not exist without the people, and there are a lot more of us than there are of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...it has never been easier to do cool things on the web. What used to be expensive and require a great deal of technical expertise is now becoming more and more accessible, both financially and technologically, by the day. More people than ever have access to the web, both in terms of access to devices, but also in terms of access to internet connectivity and software. What used to be the realm of the nerds and those with the financial wherewithal to purchase expensive home computers, connectivity, and software packages, is now home to people from all walks of life, who bring new ideas, perspectives, and experiences that we often forget were in short supply during what some of us think of as the “good old days” of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, we—all of us—can build the projects we want to see, write the software that the big platforms won’t, and create the services that people need. We can wire everything together, whether the platforms like it or not, to tear down the walls that they put up. We can modify the software, reverse engineer their systems, and wrestle back control of how we experience the web, even through these very platforms. We can share information and help people understand what is happening around them. We can teach others to build the things they want to build, and share with one another the important and meaningful work that is being done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can build the web that we want to see, and we can return to that place where the web is a place of wonder, where all of us feel that same burning feeling of excitement as we push the web back towards the wonderful, beautiful, joyful place it ought to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/fighting-for-our-web-white</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/fighting-for-our-web-white</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-10-10 20:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>protocolsnotplatforms</category>
      <category>humanweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>web3.0</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shipping Tumblr and WordPress</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Automattic acquired Tumblr we’ve made it more efficient, grown its revenue, and worked to improve the platform. But there’s one part of the plan that we haven’t yet started, which is to run Tumblr on WordPress. I’m pleased to say we’re kicking off that project now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little late, but I can't express how much I love this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love Tumblr’s streamlined posting experience and its current product direction. We’re not changing that. We’re talking about running Tumblr’s backend on WordPress. You won’t even notice a difference from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it sounds outside the scope of the original plan, it would be amazing if the shared backend as well as the Tumblr publishing front-end made their way into the open-source version of WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would open the door to self-hosted personal websites that also make it significantly easier to post content in smaller chunks like a microblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pair that with ActivityPub integrations and you now have a connected web of individuals where the first place they post content to is their own website and for discovery / broader reach can also federate and post to other platforms that also support protocols like ActivityPub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't wait to see how this project develops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you yearn for the days when people owned their corner of the internet and expressed themselves in wild and wacky ways? Do you want to see an internet focused on creativity, art, and ideas instead of debating and dividing? Do you think content and data should be owned by authors and artists, instead of getting locked behind the closed platform of a mega-corporation? Do you want to build an internet where anyone with a story can tell it, and anyone with a product can sell it, regardless of income, gender, politics, language, or where they live in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to all of those is YES.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-09-05 22:15 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>posse</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluesky Welcomes Mike Masnick to Board of Directors</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Nice! I remember reading &lt;a href="https://knightcolumbia.org/content/protocols-not-platforms-a-technological-approach-to-free-speech"&gt;Protocols, Not Platforms&lt;/a&gt; many years ago and felt inspired to seek out a better web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mike-masnick-bluesky-board-of-directors</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mike-masnick-bluesky-board-of-directors</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-07 22:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>platforms</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>humanweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll Club - A blog directory</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;A Blog Directory is a cool project from &lt;a href="https://notes.jeddacp.com/"&gt;JC (Probably)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://louplummer.lol/"&gt;Lou Plummer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://blogroll.club/"&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogroll-club-blog-directory</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogroll-club-blog-directory</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-05 20:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>.well-known feeds</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;This is a clever use of &lt;em&gt;.well-known&lt;/em&gt; and OPML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely something I want to experiment with and implement on my site even if it's not widely adopted.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/well-known-feeds</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/well-known-feeds</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-31 09:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>standards</category>
      <category>feeds</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home-Cooked Software and Barefoot Developers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emerging golden age of home-cooked software, barefoot developers, and why the local-first community should help build it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a talk I presented Local-first Conference in Berlin, May 2024. It's specifically directed at the local-first
community, but its relevant to anyone involved in building software.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
For the last ~year I've been keeping a close eye on how language models capabilities meaningfully change the speed, ease, and accessibility of software development. The slightly bold theory I put forward in this talk is that we're on a verge of a golden age of local, home-cooked software and a new kind of developer – what I've called the barefoot developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/home-cooked-software-barefoot-developers-appleton</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/home-cooked-software-barefoot-developers-appleton</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-06 22:02 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>localfirst</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>sofware</category>
      <category>llm</category>
      <category>programming</category>
      <category>talk</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just added Fediverse Open Graph meta tag to my website</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I learned from &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/highlighting-blogging-on-mastodon"&gt;Matthias Ott&lt;/a&gt; that Mastodon created a new Open Graph meta tag which displays a direct link to the website owner's Fediverse (Mastodon, Pixelfed, Threads, etc...) profile as part of the URL preview card on the Mastodon web and mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just added support for it on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was add the following tag to my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;fediverse:creator&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;@lqdev@toot.lqdev.tech&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not running the nightly version of Mastodon on my instance, but if anyone on an instance where this is already supported like mastodon.social can verify and let me know it's working, it's much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-02 21:41 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogs</category>
      <category>news</category>
      <category>journalism</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>opengraph</category>
      <category>html</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molly White's Blogroll</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;Bookmarking for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm already subscribed to many of these websites and publications. However, there's several new ones I found that I think will eventually make their rotation into my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/blogroll-molly-white</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/blogroll-molly-white</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-07 17:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 - The year of Gemini?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;If 2023 was the year of AI and the Fediverse, is 2024 the year of Gemini?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been seeing a few posts about Gemini cross my feed reader which is more than I'm used to seeing. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2023/12/29/the-gopher-revival-is-upon-us/"&gt;The Gopher Revival Is Upon Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://zserge.com/posts/small-web/"&gt;Poor Man's Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gemini is weird in a fun way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since content is text-based, using terminal clients like &lt;a href="https://thelambdalab.xyz/elpher/"&gt;Elpher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/makew0rld/amfora"&gt;Amfora&lt;/a&gt; make it easy to browse pages (capsules) and blogs (gemlogs).&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/2024-year-of-gemini</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/2024-year-of-gemini</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-30 00:34 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>gemini</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>gopher</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 in social media: the case for the fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Good article from David Pierce. I'd add that many of these platforms (i.e. Mastodon, Lemmy, PeerTube, WordPress) have strong RSS support which offer another degree of freedom from opting out of signing up for any of the platforms but still being able to follow the people and topics you care about. Sure, the experience may not be as rich but it's yet another way for people to participate in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new kind of social internet is currently forming. Right now it might still look like “Twitter and Reddit, only different,” but that’s only the very beginning of what’s to come. Hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced we’ll be better off with a hundred different apps for Snapchat or Instagram or X instead of just one...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t make sense that we have a dozen usernames, a dozen profiles, a dozen sets of fans and friends. All that stuff should belong to me, and I should be able to access it and interact with it anywhere and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralizing social media can sound like a sort of kumbaya anti-capitalist manifesto: “It’s about openness and sharing, not capitalism, man!” In practice it’s the opposite: it’s a truly free market approach to social networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...in a fediverse-dominated world, the way to win is not to achieve excellent lock-in and network effects. The only way to win is to build the best product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...so far we’re mostly in the “popular app, but federated” phase of this transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everything in the fediverse is a one-to-one competitor to an existing platform...Some of these apps are very good! But nearly all of them are differentiated only in that they’re federated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s be super clear about this: the point of the fediverse is not that it’s federated...Making the “It’s federated!” argument is like making the “It’s better for privacy!” argument: it makes you feel good, and at best it’s a useful tiebreaker, but it doesn’t actually matter. All that matters is the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023 was the year “fediverse” became a buzzword, 2024 will be the year it becomes an industry. (Hopefully one with a better name, but I’ll get over that.) We’ve spent too long living our lives online in someone else’s spaces. What’s next will belong to all of us. All that’s left to do is start posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/2023-social-media-case-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/2023-social-media-case-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-19 09:26 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>512KB Club</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 512KB Club is a collection of performance-focused web pages from across the Internet. To qualify your website must satisfy both of the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be an actual site that contains a reasonable amount of information, not just a couple of links on a page (more info here).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your total UNCOMPRESSED web resources must not exceed 512KB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/512kb-club</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/512kb-club</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-06-29 10:56 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1MB Club</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1MB Club is a growing collection of performance-focused web pages weighing less than 1 megabyte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/1mb-club</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/1mb-club</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-06-29 10:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>