<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - opensource</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/opensource</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'opensource' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-08-11 23:24 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Self-Hosted</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of Free Software network services and web applications which can be hosted on your own server(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/awesome-self-hosted</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/awesome-self-hosted</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-11 23:24 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>selfhosting</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>FOSS</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faircamp - A static site generator for audio producers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;This is such a cool project. Looks like it's super simple to get started with and it's packed with a ton of features so creators get to stay in their flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like how creators are showcased.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/faircamp-static-site-audio-producers</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/faircamp-static-site-audio-producers</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-05 20:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>faircamp</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>staticsite</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>tools</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discourse and the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we started working on a plugin that brings Discourse and the Fediverse closer together. Discourse communities are online spaces that facilitate open collaboration and communication. The Fediverse offers ways to expand the reach of Discourse communities and help them build bridges with people active in other spaces, all while keeping the conversation civil, meaningful and focused. This post will describe how the ActivityPub plugin works and how you can enable your Discourse community to connect with other communities or Fediverse users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/discourse-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/discourse-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 22:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>discourse</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>forum</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Element Desktop on Windows ARM64 Devices</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In a previous post, I talked about my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/running-linux-gui-apps-windows-wsl-amazing"&gt;workaround for running Element Desktop on my ARM64 Windows device&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm happy that I no longer need that workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/element-hq/element-desktop"&gt;Element Desktop&lt;/a&gt; enabled support for &lt;a href="https://github.com/element-hq/element-desktop/pull/624"&gt;ARM64 on Windows&lt;/a&gt; and shipped it as part of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/element-hq/element-desktop/releases/tag/v1.11.95"&gt;1.11.95 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you could go to the &lt;a href="https://element.io/download"&gt;downloads website&lt;/a&gt; and get the installer from there, you can now also get it via &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/windows/package-manager/winget/"&gt;WinGet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built on the work of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/tree/master/manifests/e/Element/Element"&gt;existing community manifest&lt;/a&gt; in the winget-pkgs repo and via a &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/pull/244768"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; updated the latest 1.11.96 version to include the ARM64 installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I didn't create the manifest from scratch, I thought it was really easy to contribute a new installer. I'll leave the details of my process for another post though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing Element Desktop via WinGet is relativaly straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you already have the WinGet tool installed, all you have to do is run the following commmand in the terminal and you're all set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell"&gt;winget install Element.Element -a arm64
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/install-element-desktop-windows-arm64</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/install-element-desktop-windows-arm64</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-04-07 08:38 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>arm64</category>
      <category>windows</category>
      <category>element</category>
      <category>winget</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mistral Small 3.1</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on Mistral Small 3, this new model comes with improved text performance, multimodal understanding, and an expanded context window of up to 128k tokens. The model outperforms comparable models like Gemma 3 and GPT-4o Mini, while delivering inference speeds of 150 tokens per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight: Mistral Small 3.1 can run on a single RTX 4090 or a Mac with 32GB RAM. This makes it a great fit for on-device use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mistral-small-3-1</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mistral-small-3-1</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-03-18 20:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mistral</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just pre-ordered by PebbleOS Core Time 2 smartwatch</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Just pre-ordered my Pebble Core Time 2 Duo! Sadly it won't be here until December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href="https://store.repebble.com/"&gt;https://store.repebble.com/&lt;/a&gt; to get yours.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/preordered-pebbleos-watch</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/preordered-pebbleos-watch</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-03-18 20:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>pebbleos</category>
      <category>smartwatch</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>pebble</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Pebble Back</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;
We’re making a new Pebble-style smartwatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is amazing news! By the time I decided to get a Pebble, they'd already been sold to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with Eric's points here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've tried every single smart watch out there, but none do it for me. No one makes a smartwatch with the core set of features I want:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always-on e-paper screen&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s reflective rather than emissive. Sunlight readable. Glanceable. Not distracting to others like a bright wrist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long battery life&lt;/strong&gt; (one less thing to charge. It’s annoying to need extra cables when traveling)
Simple and beautiful user experience around a core set of features I use regularly (telling time, notifications, music control, alarms, weather, calendar, sleep/step tracking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buttons!&lt;/strong&gt; (to play/pause/skip music on my phone without looking at the screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hackable&lt;/strong&gt; (apparently you can’t even write your own watchfaces for Apple Watch? That is wild. There were &amp;gt;16k watchfaces on the Pebble appstore!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garmin is the closest I've come to it at least on the battery life and buttons front. Pebble was one-of-a-kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already signed up to stay up to date with the project and plan on being a day one customer. You can too at &lt;a href="https://repebble.com/"&gt;repebble.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. While not surprised, I didn't know Eric was behind another amazing project I'm a fan of, &lt;a href="https://www.beeper.com/"&gt;Beeper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bringing-pebble-back</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/bringing-pebble-back</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-06 19:42 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>eink</category>
      <category>pebble</category>
      <category>smartwatch</category>
      <category>google</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Implementing ActivityPub in a Static Site (or Any Website) - Part 8</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Part 8 of &lt;a href="https://www.maho.dev/2024/02/a-guide-to-implement-activitypub-in-a-static-site-or-any-website/"&gt;&amp;quot;A guide to implement ActivityPub in a static site (or any website)&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.maho.dev/"&gt;maho.dev&lt;/a&gt; recently dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part goes over how to add replies and comments to your static site.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/guide-implementing-activitypub-static-site-pt-8</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/guide-implementing-activitypub-static-site-pt-8</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-02 18:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulcasting to Owncast and YouTube</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;About a week ago, I was telling &lt;a href="https://maho.dev/"&gt;maho.dev&lt;/a&gt; about Owncast and my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/deploy-owncast-azure"&gt;self-hosted setup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our chat, the question of simulcasting came up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;a href="https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/obs-studio-stream-to-multiple-platforms-or-channels-at-once.932/"&gt;guidance from the OBS community&lt;/a&gt; as a starting point, I decided to try it out for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't work as-is but after using an AI assistant to help me tweak the ffmpeg command, I was able to get it working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I posted the command to my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/resources/wiki/owncast"&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; and plan on writing a more detailed post at a later time.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/owncast-simulcast-youtube</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/owncast-simulcast-youtube</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-30 20:25 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>owncast</category>
      <category>obs</category>
      <category>youtube</category>
      <category>livestream</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First live stream using Owncast done</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I tested out my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/deploy-owncast-azure/"&gt;self-hosted Owncast setup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3opjC7fEAJs" title="Video Thumbnail from live stream"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/3opjC7fEAJs/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Video Thumbnail from live stream" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think it went well considering I was using the built-in camera and mic on my laptop. Despite sharing my screen, using the browser, broadcasting and recording the stream, the laptop seemed to handle it just fine. I didn't get a chance to test writing and running code which is going to make up a bulk of the content on stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flow on OBS is straightforward and simple. I might automate it either using my Stream Deck or just mapping hotkeys. It's simple enough that I only need to transition between a few scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as hosting the recordings, the process of uploading to YouTube was straightforward. It took a little over 10 minutes, but that's something that I can just do in the background so not really worried about that. For the time being, I think I'll just use YouTube to host the videos and mark them as unlisted. No particular reason behind that other than I only want YouTube to serve as my video host. The main place I plan on showcasing and organizing videos is on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time being, I'll just create notes like these. Eventually though, I'd like to have a video post type which shows up on my feed. The post card will only display the video but the detailed view, I'd like for it to be like my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/resources/presentations/hello-world"&gt;presentation pages&lt;/a&gt;. Except, instead of a presentation, it'd contain the video, show notes, maybe the transcript, and links mentioned during the stream. Also, I'd like video posts to have their own RSS feed just like other posts on this page so folks who are interested in following along can via their RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other things I want to figure out are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up a custom domain that points to my Owncast server rather than the default one provided by Azure Container Apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Displaying and managing chat outside of the built-in Owncast frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/first-owncast-stream</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/first-owncast-stream</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-20 18:33 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>owncast</category>
      <category>livestream</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>video</category>
      <category>azure</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Owncast live stream into my website</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;The live stream page on my site is up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/live"&gt;/live&lt;/a&gt;, you'll see the stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not sure what stream schedule will look like, but I'm thinking maybe I'll do a test one on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/created-owncast-livestream-page</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/created-owncast-livestream-page</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-18 19:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>owncast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>livestream</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>website</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Subtitles Are Coming to VLC</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shown off at CES 2025 is VLC's upcoming automatic subtitling feature, which is local in nature, running entirely on a user's machine without needing to connect to some distant server.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
According to Jean-Baptiste Kempf, the creator and lead developer of VLC, this new feature is powered by open source AI models, which carry out subtitle generation tasks in two stages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
One aspect is automatic generation of subtitles from the video, and the other is translation of those subtitles into over 100 languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there's no word on when this feature will be arriving on VLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ai-subtitles-coming-vlc</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ai-subtitles-coming-vlc</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-15 20:49 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>vlc</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>local</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Reading Habit with Audiobooks, LibriVox, and AntennaPod</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Last year, I was able to complete my goal of reading 12 books or roughly one book per month. I kept track of some of the books I read in my [library page](/reviews).

I enjoyed most of the books I read. However, despite hitting my goal and averaging a book a month, I didn't build up a habit which is what I would've preferred. Many of the books I read last year, I read them during long periods of uninterrupted time, such as cross-country flights. The topic of goal setting and measuring the right thing could be an entire post, but I'll leave that for another time. 

Taking the learnings from last year, this year, I'll try to focus on building a reading habit rather than reading a set number of books. While I'd still like to finish at least one book per month, that's a metric I'll use to track general progress rather than making it the goal. Unless I'm reading something like War and Peace, I'd expect that by establishing a consistent cadence, I should be able to get through at least one book every month. Also, I'm only accounting for uninterrupted reading time blocks. Using audiobooks, I can continue building my reading habit while working out or doing chores. Kind of like having TV playing in the background. 

There is no shortage of audiobooks out there. Audible is one of the easiest ways to access audiobooks and they have a large selection to choose from. Personally, I don't use Audible. I don't like paying for a separate subscription, getting credits to "buy" books that I don't really own and can only listen through the Audible app. Instead, I use Spotify. I get [15 hours of access to audiobooks per month](https://support.spotify.com/us/article/audiobooks-access-plan/) as part of my subscription. While I still don't own the books and can only listen on the Spotify app, at least I'm not paying a separate subscription. Also, the 15 hour limit at this time is more than enough for me. 

The library is another amazing option. No subscription fees and you get access to your local library's entire digital catalog. Using the [Libby app](https://www.overdrive.com/apps/libby), you can borrow books and start listening for free. Selection though may be an issue here since you are limited to what's available through your local library. Pro-tip, universities and employers sometimes have libraries, so as an alumnus or employee, you can expand the number of books available to you by registering multiple libraries on the Libby app. Regardless of which library you choose though, you still have to go through the Libby app. 

The dream setup for me is, having direct access to the audiobook files so I can listen to them whenever and wherever I'd like. Similar to podcasts. Thanks to LibriVox and AntennaPod, that setup is possible. 

In case you're interested in setting up something similar, in this post, I'll briefly explain what LibriVox and AntennaPod are and show how you can use them to start listening to free audiobooks on your phone. 

## What is LibriVox?

[LibriVox](https://librivox.org/) is a website that provides a collection of free audiobooks from the public domain. Thanks to a vibrant community of volunteers, you can enjoy classics such as:

- [The Divine Comedy](https://librivox.org/the-divine-comedy-by-dante-alighieri/)
- [The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes](https://librivox.org/the-adventures-of-sherlock-holmes/)
- [Discourses of Epictetus](https://librivox.org/discourses-of-epictetus-by-epictetus/)
- [Roughing It](https://librivox.org/roughing-it/)
- [And many others...](https://librivox.org/search?primary_key=0&amp;search_category=title&amp;search_page=1&amp;search_form=get_results&amp;search_order=catalog_date)

It's important to note that the catalog is limited to public domain works. That means you won't have access to the latest self-help, business, or current events books. However, there are still thousands of books to keep you busy for an entire lifetime and the list is constantly growining since there are new works introduced into the public domain every year. 

Here's [a few notable literary works that entered the public domain in 2025](https://blog.archive.org/2025/01/01/welcome-to-the-public-domain-in-2025/) as well as the complete list of [literary works from 1929](https://archive.org/details/internetarchivebooks?tab=collection&amp;query=date%3A1929).

## What is Antennapod?

[AntennaPod](https://antennapod.org/) is an open-source podcast player for Android. 

The app has a ton of great features, such as [Podcast Index](https://podcastindex.org/) support, subscribe via RSS directly,  OPML import and export, chapters, adjustable playback speed, and for the past few years, a personalized yearly summary which is computed locally on your device [(here's my summary from 2024)](/notes/antennapod-echo-2024).

You can get AntennaPod from the Play Store or [F-Droid](https://f-droid.org/en/packages/de.danoeh.antennapod/)

## Keep track of new releases

LibriVox provides [several feeds](https://librivox.org/pages/librivox-feeds/). 

Since podcast distribution is primarly done through RSS and you can subscribe to podcasts directly using RSS feeds in AntennaPod, we can use the app to stay up to date with new audiobook releases. 

To subscribe to the LibriVox New Release feed:

1. Copy the LibriVox New Releases RSS feed URL to your clipboard: [https://librivox.org/rss/latest_releases](https://librivox.org/rss/latest_releases)
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.

    ![AntennaPod Add Podcast Dialog](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/add-podcast-antennapod.png)

1. Paste the LibriVox New Releases RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

At this point, you should see the feed listed in your AntennaPod subscriptions. 

By subscribing the LibriVox New Release feed, AntennaPod treats the feed as a podcast, and each new release entry or audiobook is like a podcast episode. 

For more information on subscribing to podcasts, see the [AntennaPod documentation](https://antennapod.org/documentation/getting-started/subscribe). 

## Add books to Antennapod

Subscribing to the new releases feed only notifies you when new books are added, you can't listen to or download the books. To do that, you'll need to subscribe to the RSS feed of the book you want to listen to in AntennaPod.

### From New Releases Feed

1. In AntennaPod's Subscription screen, select **LibriVox's New Releases**.
1. From the list of new releases, select the book you want to listen to. For example, "Room of One's Own" by Virginia Woolf.

    ![AntennaPod New Releases Feed](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-librivox-new-releases.png)

1. In the audiobook's screen, select **Visit Website**. This will take you to the LibriVox audiobook's page in the browser.

    ![AntennaPod Audiobook Screen](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-room-of-ones-own.png)

1. In the LibriVox audiobook page, select the book's RSS Feed.

    ![A Room of One's Own by Virginia Woolf LibriVox book page](http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/librivox-room-ones-own.png)

1. Copy the book's feed URL to your clipboard.
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.
1. Paste the book's RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

### Any other books

The process works the same for other books but you'll have to use LibriVox as the entrypoint to browse books.

1. In your browser, navigate to LibriVox. 
1. Go to the audiobook page. For example, this is the page for [Walden](https://librivox.org/walden-by-henry-david-thoreau).
1. In the audiobook page, select the book's RSS Feed. For Walden, it's [https://librivox.org/rss/549](https://librivox.org/rss/549).
1. Copy the book's feed URL to your clipboard.
1. In AntennaPod, open up the hamburger menu and select **Add Podcast**.
1. In the *Add Podcast* dialog, select **Add podcast by RSS address**.
1. Paste the book's RSS feed URL into the text box and select **Confirm**. 

## Conclusion 

Although AntennaPod wasn't designed for audiobook listening, thanks to the flexibility of RSS feeds and the thankless work of the LibriVox community, you can easily listen to audiobooks for free on your mobile device. I plan on testing out this setup and seeing whether it helps keep my reading habit on track.]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/listen-audiobooks-librivox-antennapod</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/listen-audiobooks-librivox-antennapod</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-05 21:04 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>book</category>
      <category>audiobook</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>librivox</category>
      <category>android</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>publicdomain</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Openverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Openverse is a tool that allows openly licensed and public domain works to be discovered and used by everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Openverse searches across more than 800 million images and audio tracks from open APIs and the Common Crawl dataset. We aggregate works from multiple public repositories, and facilitate reuse through features like one-click attribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Openverse is the successor to CC Search which was launched by Creative Commons in 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/openverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/openverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 16:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>openverse</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>creativecommons</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of the Word 2024</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Cool retrospective and announcements from this WordPress' State of the Word 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focused mode and templates look interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLybH5YvIPQ" title="State of the Word 2024 YouTube Thumbnail"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/KLybH5YvIPQ/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="State of the Word 2024 YouTube Thumbnail" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/state-of-the-word-2024-wordpress</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/state-of-the-word-2024-wordpress</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 16:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antennapod Echo 2024</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;That's a lot of podcasts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-2024-1.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Antennapod Echo Podcast Hours Listened" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/antennapod-2024-2.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Antennapod Echo Podcast Addict" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2024</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/antennapod-echo-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-11 20:52 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcasts</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>antennapod</category>
      <category>stats</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Llama 3 to life</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;At AI Infra @ Scale 2024, Meta engineers discussed every step of how we built and brought Llama 3 to life, from data and training to inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ELIcy6flgQI" title="Bringing Llama 3 to life talk video thumbnail"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/ELIcy6flgQI/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Bringing Llama 3 to life talk video thumbnail" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/meta-bringing-llama-3-to-life</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/meta-bringing-llama-3-to-life</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-22 16:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>meta</category>
      <category>llama3</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>llm</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic Maps removed from Google Play Store</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night Organic Maps was removed from the Play Store without any warnings or additional details due to &amp;quot;not meeting the requirements for the Family Program&amp;quot;. Compared to Google Maps and other maps apps rated for 3+ age, there are no ads or in-app purchases in Organic Maps. We have asked for an appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app is still available on &lt;a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/app.organicmaps/"&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;. Much better place for getting apps in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/organic-maps-removed-play-store</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/organic-maps-removed-play-store</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-17 11:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>organicmaps</category>
      <category>google</category>
      <category>play</category>
      <category>fdroid</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>osm</category>
      <category>openstreetmaps</category>
      <category>maps</category>
      <category>app</category>
      <category>store</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clock Tables - Org Mode, Plain Text, and AI</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Org-mode appreciation post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use plain text and org-mode for most things in my life, especially when it comes to task and life management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't rehash all the reasons Emacs and org-mode are amazing. There are tons of blog posts and videos out there that would do it more justice than I ever could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, Emacs has become my go-to text editor. Throughout all that time, I've continued to find new features that delight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent is &lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/manual/The-clock-table.html"&gt;clock table&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already use org-mode to track my to-dos and perform some sort of time-block planning by setting deadlines and scheduling tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently though, I've been wanting a way to see all of the things I've worked on over the past [ INSERT TIME PERIOD ]. More importantly, I'd like to have time associated with them to see where my time has gone and evaluate whether I'm spending time on the things I should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew you could &lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/manual/Clocking-commands.html"&gt;clock in and clock out&lt;/a&gt; on tasks. However, I didn't know you could easily build a customized report that automatically updates. That's when I came across clock tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have a way of visualizing all of the things I worked on during a week or month, and as I'm planning for the next week or month, I can adjust and reprioritize the things I'm working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there are enterprise offerings like the Viva suite from Microsoft which provides detailed reports on how you spend your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What excites me about org-mode though is that it's plain text. The clock table report that gets generated is a plain text table which makes it portable and easy to access using any text editor of your choice. It works best with Emacs, but that's not a requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On their own, clock tables are amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given how well language models work on plain text, they could be used as context for your queries. Imagine giving a language model as input an org file which contains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clock table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of TODO tasks (with notes, priorities, deadlines, tags, properties, and other annotations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A high level list of goals you want to achieve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you could enter a prompt along the lines of: &amp;quot;Using the following clock-table and list of goals I want to achieve, provide me with recommendations of tasks I should work on for the next week. Ensure that they align with my goals, are top priority, and provide the highest return on my efforts&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you might also provide your org-agenda view containing appointments and use the results from the first query as context for the following prompt: &amp;quot;Given the agenda view for the next week, schedule the top 3 tasks you recommended&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result would be a list of TODO items containing schedule / active timestamps annotations which now show up on your org-agenda view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, almost every productivity application out there is working on building these kinds of AI features into their products. The difference is, in many cases, the formats used by those applications aren't plain text. This adds complexity to the data extraction and transformation pipelines required to get the data into the right format for a language model to process. With plain text, there's little to no transformations required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's even better, I can extend org-mode and Emacs using elisp to do the things I just talked about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm no elisp expert, so I asked Copilot to generate an elisp function that takes an org-mode clock table as input and generates a written text summary of it. Here are the results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-lisp"&gt;(defun org-clock-summary-to-chatgpt ()
  &amp;quot;Extracts clock table data and requests a summary from ChatGPT.&amp;quot;
  (interactive)
  (let* ((clock-table-data (org-clocktable-get-clocktable))
         (summary-text (org-clocktable-format-summary clock-table-data))
         (api-endpoint &amp;quot;https://api.openai.com/v1/engines/davinci/completions&amp;quot;)
         (api-key &amp;quot;YOUR_API_KEY&amp;quot;)) ; Replace with your actual API key

    ;; Construct the HTTP request and send it to ChatGPT
    (with-current-buffer
        (url-retrieve-synchronously api-endpoint
                                    `((&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; . ,summary-text)
                                      (&amp;quot;api_key&amp;quot; . ,api-key)))
      (goto-char (point-min))
      (search-forward &amp;quot;\n\n&amp;quot;)
      (let ((response-json (json-read)))
        (message &amp;quot;ChatGPT summary: %s&amp;quot; (cdr (assoc 'choices response-json)))))))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you elisp experts out there, let me know how it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know at least the API endpoint is wrong, but generally speaking, it seems to be doing the right thing. Such function could be extended to include org-agenda information, TODO items, and many other things that would use AI to augment the existing functionality of Emacs and org-mode to tailor them to my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/love-plain-text-org-mode-clocktable</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/love-plain-text-org-mode-clocktable</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-09 22:07 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>emacs</category>
      <category>orgmode</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>plaintext</category>
      <category>productivity</category>
      <category>tools</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>gnu</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>gtd</category>
      <category>calendar</category>
      <category>agenda</category>
      <category>llm</category>
      <category>openai</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Years of WordPress</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 years since Mike and I did the first release of WordPress, forking Michel’s work on b2/cafélog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about elements that made WordPress successful in its early years that we should keep in mind as we build this year and beyond. Here’s 11 opinions:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple things should be easy and intuitive, and complex things possible.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikis are amazing, and our documentation should be wiki-easy to edit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s important that we all do support, go to meetups and events, anything we can to stay close to regular end-users of what we make.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats to WordPress and the team on 21 years. I think the following are some good elements to keep building on.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/21-years-of-wordpress</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/21-years-of-wordpress</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-27 21:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>anniversary</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>