<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - personalweb</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/personalweb</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'personalweb' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-05-30 13:32 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Resources List for the Personal Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is to help guide and help those who are in every stage of their web-building journey on the personal web. This list is not meant to overwhelm you, but rather give you options and find tools, graphics, utilities, codes, and everything in between to help get you creating more on the independent web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/resource-list-personal-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/resource-list-personal-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-30 13:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>32bitcafe</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>retro</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The stage has been set for the growth of small social media</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month during Meta's antitrust trial, Mark Zuckerberg admitted that his company's focus has changed radically from where it began...[his] testimony implies that Facebook (Meta) may no longer be as much of an option if we actually want to talk to each other on line. But, neither are many of the other large social media sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...if companies allowed us to discover great new small blogs and small social media sites, many of us would decide to spend more time there. Then, companies would be less able to advertise to us on their own sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...we have been told by the mainstream media for well over a decade that small social media is dead. They say the same about small blogs, yet small blogs are actually more plentiful than ever, with over &lt;a href="https://firstsiteguide.com/blogging-stat"&gt;600 million blogs&lt;/a&gt; on the Internet and about 7 million new blog articles published each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to create your own forum, do yourself a favor. The way to protect yourself and your users is by &lt;strong&gt;running your social media site at a domain that you own and on a server that you control&lt;/strong&gt;, and don't agree to hand over any of your rights to anyone for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe large corporate-run social media sites are vulnerable in a way they have not been for twenty years. Their users have reached a state of extreme dissatisfaction with their &amp;quot;enshittified&amp;quot; platforms, and they are looking for something, anything, better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But each of you who are reading these words can help end this situation by creating your own small social media site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need to start your own small site is a domain name, a server that you can buy, rent, or set up on an old computer, perhaps social media software (see above), patience, a willingness to work, and ideas for ways of notifying potential users of the existence of your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run your new site as you and your users see fit, and make it far superior to Facebook, Twitter (X), Reddit, or any of the other major sites whose owners think you have no other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/stage-set-growth-small-social-media-cheapskate</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/stage-set-growth-small-social-media-cheapskate</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-26 18:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Site Is a Home</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;While going through a backlog of personal blogs I haven't read in a few weeks, I'm noticing a trend in posts that express similar sentiments to those in Naz's post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm happy to see more people choosing to have a place that gives them more autonomy and freedom to express themselves in whichever form makes the most sense for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your site is a home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, social networks were created...novelty and the promise of interconnectedness by gathering in a common town square to blast out whatever was going on in our lives eventually won out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you might have still had your website, your home to return to...the place you built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things started to change and instead of going home, you, and everybody else started to live in the town square.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a shape to your physical home. Arranged and organized in the ways that make sense for you, the reward is a space that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A platform or network doesn’t allow for much configuration. The town square isn’t owned by you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People became absolutely reliant on the same gathering place...the convenience of seeing friends (sometimes) outweighed your other neighbors spouting garbage and hate. You came to rely on this place for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can still have a home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have very little at the town square, because it’s not a public one. It’s a walled-off town square, whose rules and borders change at the whims of those who created it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting my home. I’m glad you dropped by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to see yours sometime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/your-site-is-a-home-hamid</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/your-site-is-a-home-hamid</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-25 20:49 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unplatform</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unplatform is an interactive guidebook, online library, and recommendations database intended to help you escape social media and join the indie web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love this guide.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/unplatform-indieweb</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/unplatform-indieweb</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-25 20:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a link blog</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Great to see more people sharing knowledge and linking to others from their own websites / platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to follow simon's approach to creating a link blog, where I can share interesting links I find on the internet along with my own comments and thoughts about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...this is an excellent way to share knowledge while also keeping a personal record. It’s much better than simply saving something to Readwise to read later and leaving a few highlights or dull comments like &amp;quot;interesting.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/build-a-link-blog-xuanwo</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/build-a-link-blog-xuanwo</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-04 22:29 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>linkblog</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Implementing ActivityPub in a Static Site (or Any Website) - Part 8</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Part 8 of &lt;a href="https://www.maho.dev/2024/02/a-guide-to-implement-activitypub-in-a-static-site-or-any-website/"&gt;&amp;quot;A guide to implement ActivityPub in a static site (or any website)&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.maho.dev/"&gt;maho.dev&lt;/a&gt; recently dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part goes over how to add replies and comments to your static site.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/guide-implementing-activitypub-static-site-pt-8</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/guide-implementing-activitypub-static-site-pt-8</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-02 18:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital soverignity is more important than ever</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...you needed to move anything you care about online to a space you control. Digital sovereignty is more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💯💯💯💯💯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best time was yesterday. Next best time is now.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/digital-sovereignty-white</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/digital-sovereignty-white</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-20 20:46 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>digitalsoverignty</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making space for a handmade web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Love this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the web was more commercialized, it was personal...A website was a way to represent yourself and connect to others, a space to tend and call your very own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imperfect, handmade character of websites has been sanded away in favor of efficiency, and social media platforms have risen in the stead of amateur sites. Many of us conform to these containers and retreat from expressing our authentic selves publicly...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the idea of a more handcrafted internet resonates with you, the best way to be part of the movement is simply to make your own website. This may seem intimidating if we expect webpages to be a holistic reflection of ourselves, like a resume, portfolio, or blog. We limit the web as a medium when we expect that a website must fulfill a host of needs, or serve any function at all. &lt;strong&gt;A website doesn’t need to be anything but your own&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more personal web becomes possible once we turn away from our preconceived notions of what a website must be. Let’s use our tools to continuously push at the boundaries of the web. Doing so will create a more creative, expansive environment that allows us to reclaim our agency and reinvigorate our collective understanding of software as an artisanal craft. Instead of concentrating on a few, monolithic sites, what if we visited many, more personalized sites? We should explore the far reaches of the web and invite our friends to join in: After all, &lt;strong&gt;we make the internet, and only we can build the web we want&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/making-space-handmade-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/making-space-handmade-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-18 19:25 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>websites</category>
      <category>handmadeweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Social Web - Hello, Social Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're A New Social, a new non-profit organization focused on building cross-protocol tools and services for the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our mission is to liberate people's networks from their platforms, enabling &lt;a href="https://www.augment.ink/bridges-the-last-network-effect/?ref=anew.social"&gt;The Last Network Effect&lt;/a&gt; and leveling the playing field across the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The first project we'll take on to accomplish this mission is &lt;a href="https://fed.brid.gy/?ref=anew.social"&gt;Bridgy Fed&lt;/a&gt;, a service that enables users of ActivityPub-based platforms like Mastodon, ATProto-based platforms like Bluesky, and websites to interact and engage across ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:39 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>anewsocial</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>atproto</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weird, Inc. and 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
I don't remember how I came across Weird and their projects but I'm glad I did. I appreciate their approach of using existing platforms, protocols, and practices from the yesterweb to put the personal website front and center. 

## Weird, Inc

First, the topic of [Weird the organization and their aspirations](https://blog.muni.town/weird-inc/).

&gt; We have big aspirations for Weird. At minimum, a 'social network of personal websites' can be catalyzed by simply mapping and linking existing web spaces together, playing the role of social glue. On a grander scale there's potential for a pro-social reformation of the web as we know it, putting people's websites at the center of our sociodigital interactions.

By aligning to the foundations of [Seth Godin's Modern Business Plan](https://seths.blog/2010/05/the-modern-business-plan/), they aim to focus on:

1. Truth -  describe the world as it is
1. Assertions - how you’re going to change things
1. Alternatives - what you'll do if assertions don't pan out.
1. People - who is on your team, who is going to join your team
1. Money - how much do you need and how will you spend it

Below are some of the points that resonated with me. 

### Truth

&gt; Home ownership on the web, remarkably, is just as fraught with rent-seeking monopolists as our physical spaces. No one gets to own anything anymore.

While they're mainly referring to the social web, this is is generally true across many areas of our digital spaces. 

&gt;  Bluesky...is bringing into mainstream a nearly forgotten cornerstone of the Indie Web: Domain sovereignty  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; In a reinvigorated social web where your domain-name is your universal address in the digital sphere, Weird is the virtual home to which that address is pointing  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; 'Weird the data importer' is our wedge into the data fortresses keeping our digital identities captive. What will start as a Publish Elsewhere, Syndicate (to your) Own Site (PESOS) strategy makes way for a fully self-sovereign Publish (on your) Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere (POSSE) end state.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; Imagine a WordPress-like website engine that aggregates all of your digital personas into a unified mosaic, completely under your control by combination of cloud backing and local storage.  

### Alternatives

If the assertions don't pan out, the alternatives that I think might be interesting:

- Local-first knowledge base with cloud synchronization. [AnyType](https://anytype.io/) comes to mind.
- Cloud + local archiver for many other 3rd party accounts such as Bluesky, Mastodon, Discourse etc. This might make PESOS scenarios easier. Of course, this only works if the 3rd party services allow developer access to their APIs.

## Weird in 2025

Speaking specifically about [Weird the product and what the team plans of shipping in 2025](https://blog.muni.town/weird-2025/).

&gt; Weird is best understood as a single-page website generator

### Q1 and Q2

&gt; 'Weird the data importer' is our wedge into the data fortresses keeping our digital identities captive.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; 'Weird: ₱ESOS-edition' aggregates all of your digital personas into a harmonious mosaic, made completely yours by combination of cloud backing and local-first storage.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; Setting up a POSSE pipeline however requires not just the right infrastructure...but also a big shift in workflow.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; Most people will probably want a combination of both.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; Hence our commitment to both models, starting with the least laborious one [PESOS].  

Personally, [I prefer POSSE](/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps/), but it's great to see that Weird plans on meeting people where they are.

### Late 2025

&gt; Around half-way through 2025, we're hoping to shift some of our attention away from Weird as an individualistic publishing tool to Weird as a network engine.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; We think there's massive untapped potential in the web 1.0 concept of webrings, and we fully intend to bring them back.  
&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&gt; All of this culminates in one of the key motivations behind the Weird project: [A Network of Shared Purpose](https://github.com/muni-town/weird/issues/3).  

I'm not sure yet what this looks like but making it easier to discover and build networks of personal websites is a good problem to try to solve.

## Conclusion

I wish them luck and success in what they're aiming to accomplish. I'm excited to see more projects like this sprouting to shake up the status-quo in our digital spaces. ]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/weird-inc-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/weird-inc-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 18:41 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>weird</category>
      <category>cms</category>
      <category>munitown</category>
      <category>2025</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>posse</category>
      <category>pesos</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement ActivityPub on a static site series by maho.dev</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I've been following along with this amazing series from &lt;a href="https://maho.dev/"&gt;Maho&lt;/a&gt; on implementing ActivityPub on static websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I think about what I want out of my website and the way I engage in the Fediverse, there's a lot of overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, what I mainly use my Mastodon instance for is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a Fediverse presence on a self-hosted Mastodon instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps/"&gt;Cross-posting posts on by website using the POSSE pattern&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I have learned a ton from self-hosting my own Mastodon instance, neither of the points listed above require me self-hosting or even having an account on someone else's instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/using-domain-mastodon-discovery"&gt;I took the first step in linking my Fediverse presence to my domain&lt;/a&gt;. That fulfills my first requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rarely post original content on Mastodon and for consumption, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/subscribed-to-1042-feeds-newsblur"&gt;I already subscribe to accounts and tags via RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, the second requirement is one that can naturally occur without having to use a Mastodon instance as an intermediary. I can just post on my website and because my posts can show up in my outbox, there's no need to POSSE. I don't want my presence to be limited to Mastodon though, but since I plan on supporting media, reviews, and other types of posts, I expect my posts to be accessible across other platforms on the Fediverse like Pixelfed, Bookwyrm, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my website and website features are built using .NET, Maho's guide simplifies my implementation. Because &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/colophon"&gt;I'm not using any of the existing static site generators and rolled my own&lt;/a&gt;, that means that there's going to be some effort and customizations required on my end. It would no different from my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/receive-webmentions-fsharp-az-functions-fsadvent/"&gt;custom Webmentions implementation&lt;/a&gt; though. My hope is that I will save time I often spend maintaining the server as well as money since I no longer need to rent a server to host my instance. At the same time, I get to learn and contribute to building a more open, decentralized, and personal web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/implement-activitypub-static-site-series-maho</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/implement-activitypub-static-site-series-maho</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 10:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>acvititypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>staticsite</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why YOU Should Make A Website</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;This video showed up in my feed yesterday. &lt;a href="https://luvstarkei.com/"&gt;LuvstarKei&lt;/a&gt; makes some great points for building your own space on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uNlZ50b6wSs" title="LuvstarKei Thumbnail Why You Should Make A Website YouTube Video"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/uNlZ50b6wSs/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="LuvstarKei Thumbnail Why You Should Make A Website YouTube Video" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the most recent Twitter / X exodus, it's great to see folks moving to places built on more open protocols like AT (Bluesky) or ActivityPub (Fediverse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, those platforms are not your own, even in cases where you self-host. If tomorrow Threads, Bluesky, or Mastodon stop hosting your instance or stop development altogether, what happens to the content and your community? In the case of the Fediverse, many projects are being built in the open and there are other providers you could switch to. The switching costs though may not make it worth bothering to export and keep your content as is usually the case. That's not to say with a personal website you might not have similar issues (i.e. switching from WordPress to Ghost). However, HTML is HTML and you can rehost that anywhere on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is looking for different things from the social platforms, and that's not to say they don't have their value. However, from an ownership, permanence, and creative freedom perspective, nothing beats having your own website.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/why-you-should-make-a-website-luvstarkei</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/why-you-should-make-a-website-luvstarkei</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-16 18:08 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shipping Tumblr and WordPress</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Automattic acquired Tumblr we’ve made it more efficient, grown its revenue, and worked to improve the platform. But there’s one part of the plan that we haven’t yet started, which is to run Tumblr on WordPress. I’m pleased to say we’re kicking off that project now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little late, but I can't express how much I love this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love Tumblr’s streamlined posting experience and its current product direction. We’re not changing that. We’re talking about running Tumblr’s backend on WordPress. You won’t even notice a difference from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it sounds outside the scope of the original plan, it would be amazing if the shared backend as well as the Tumblr publishing front-end made their way into the open-source version of WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would open the door to self-hosted personal websites that also make it significantly easier to post content in smaller chunks like a microblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pair that with ActivityPub integrations and you now have a connected web of individuals where the first place they post content to is their own website and for discovery / broader reach can also federate and post to other platforms that also support protocols like ActivityPub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't wait to see how this project develops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you yearn for the days when people owned their corner of the internet and expressed themselves in wild and wacky ways? Do you want to see an internet focused on creativity, art, and ideas instead of debating and dividing? Do you think content and data should be owned by authors and artists, instead of getting locked behind the closed platform of a mega-corporation? Do you want to build an internet where anyone with a story can tell it, and anyone with a product can sell it, regardless of income, gender, politics, language, or where they live in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to all of those is YES.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-09-05 22:15 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>posse</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll Club - A blog directory</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;A Blog Directory is a cool project from &lt;a href="https://notes.jeddacp.com/"&gt;JC (Probably)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://louplummer.lol/"&gt;Lou Plummer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://blogroll.club/"&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogroll-club-blog-directory</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogroll-club-blog-directory</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-05 20:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zombie Internet</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, the supermajority of engagement on viral AI Facebook pages is just as artificially-generated as the content they publish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it's a child transforming into a water bottle cyborg, a three-armed flight attendant rescuing Tiger Jesus from a muddy plane crash, or a hybrid human-monkey baby being stung to death by giant hornets, all tend to have copy+pasted captions, reactions &amp;amp; comments which usually make no sense in the observed context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've noticed similar patterns on YouTube. Sometime the comments include timestamp links which makes them seem more credible, but upon further inspection, it's all bot activity.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/facebook-zombie-internet-willison</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/facebook-zombie-internet-willison</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-16 11:48 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bots</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>comments</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>facebook</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test response using org capture templates</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Testing org-capture template generated response file&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/test-emacs-capture-response-org</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/test-emacs-capture-response-org</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-14 13:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>org</category>
      <category>emacs</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>automation</category>
      <category>orgmode</category>
      <category>templates</category>
      <category>capturetemplates</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>capture</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just added Fediverse Open Graph meta tag to my website</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I learned from &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/highlighting-blogging-on-mastodon"&gt;Matthias Ott&lt;/a&gt; that Mastodon created a new Open Graph meta tag which displays a direct link to the website owner's Fediverse (Mastodon, Pixelfed, Threads, etc...) profile as part of the URL preview card on the Mastodon web and mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just added support for it on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was add the following tag to my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;fediverse:creator&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;@lqdev@toot.lqdev.tech&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not running the nightly version of Mastodon on my instance, but if anyone on an instance where this is already supported like mastodon.social can verify and let me know it's working, it's much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-02 21:41 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogs</category>
      <category>news</category>
      <category>journalism</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>opengraph</category>
      <category>html</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Affirmations for bloggers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The affirmations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I've seen and learned. Each of these will be expanded in its own section.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have things to write about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your perspective matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are good enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts don't have to be novel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will read it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are okay!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's okay to ask for things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get started quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can write on a schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgflip.com/1otri4.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Meme of man pointing at himself in the mirror" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ntietz-blogging-affirmations</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ntietz-blogging-affirmations</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-11 21:42 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Permadomain</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;I'm guilty of owning way too many domains but this short-hand (lqdev.me) and other permadomain (luisquintanilla.me) are the ones I use mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A potential happy medium I've seen is using subdomains (i.e. project.lqdev.me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2018/pathnames-to-subdomains/"&gt;Jim Nielsen has great examples&lt;/a&gt; of how he's doing that today. Though that's an older post, he also addressed it most recently in the post &lt;a href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2023/domain-sins-of-my-youth/"&gt;Domain Sins of My Youth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That somehow feels better than the URL you get when you use free hosting like GitHub Pages. As a bonus, it's already tied to your identity (if using your personal domain). Also, you save some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a few ways I practice this today. In addition to the previously mentioned domains, I also own lqdev.tech. Services and projects I host live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon Instance (toot.lqdev.tech)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matrix server (matrix.lqdev.tech)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmentions service (webmentions.lqdev.tech)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far it's been working well.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/my-permadomain-rscottjones</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/my-permadomain-rscottjones</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-30 21:41 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>domains</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>permadomain</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>projects</category>
      <category>selfhosting</category>
      <category>hosting</category>
      <category>self-hosting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll discovery enabled</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Just enabled discovery for my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt; based on the &lt;a href="https://opml.org/blogroll.opml"&gt;OPML blogroll spec&lt;/a&gt;. While technically not part of the spec, I also have similar collections for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. I've added those as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!--...--&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;blogroll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Blogroll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/blogroll//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;youtuberoll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's YouTube Roll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/youtube//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;podroll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Podroll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/podroll//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!--...--&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;youtuberoll doesn't really roll off the tongue, but I'm hesitant to call it videoroll or vidroll. My concerns mainly come from the fact that YouTube != video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-25 22:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>