<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - socialweb</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/socialweb</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'socialweb' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-09-12 21:50 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Just ordered Internet Phone Book</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[Album containing 0 photos]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/media/just-ordered-internet-phone-book-issue-1</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/media/just-ordered-internet-phone-book-issue-1</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 21:50 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Rule Says We Have To Stay on Social Media</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;💯💯💯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we can go back to vinyl records and film cameras, we can go back to blogs and RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we need permission from the masses before we do something that might bring us joy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/no-rule-says-stay-on-social-media</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/no-rule-says-stay-on-social-media</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 20:46 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>rss</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Days of Social Media</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media was built on the romance of authenticity. Early platforms sold themselves as conduits for genuine connection: stuff you wanted to see, like your friend’s wedding and your cousin’s dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feed no longer feels crowded with people but crowded with content. At this point, it has far less to do with people than with consumers and consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever remains of genuine, human content is increasingly sidelined by algorithmic prioritization, receiving fewer interactions than the engineered content and AI slop optimized solely for clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While content proliferates, engagement is evaporating...People aren’t connecting or conversing on social media like they used to; they’re just wading through slop, that is, low-effort, low-quality content produced at scale, often with AI, for engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engagement is now about raw user attention – time spent, impressions, scroll velocity – and the net effect is an online world in which you are constantly being addressed but never truly spoken to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media’s death rattle will not be a bang but a shrug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These networks once promised a single interface for the whole of online life...But now, the model is splintering, and users are drifting toward smaller, slower, more private spaces, like group chats, Discord servers and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24063290/fediverse-explained-activitypub-social-media-open-protocol"&gt;federated microblogs&lt;/a&gt; — a billion little gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intentional, opt-in micro‑communities are rising in their place — like Patreon collectives and Substack newsletters — where creators chase depth over scale, retention over virality. A writer with 10,000 devoted subscribers can potentially earn more and burn out less than one with a million passive followers on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the last days of social media, not because we lack content, but because the attention economy has neared its outer limit — we have exhausted the capacity to care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our offline reality is irrevocably shaped by our online world. Consider the worker who deletes or was never on LinkedIn, excluding themselves from professional networks that increasingly exist nowhere else&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These platforms haven’t just captured attention, they’ve enclosed the commons where social, economic and cultural capital are exchanged. But enclosure breeds resistance, and as exhaustion sets in, alternatives begin to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...as social media collapses on itself, the future points to a quieter, more fractured, more human web, something that no longer promises to be everything, everywhere, for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can dream of a digital future where belonging is no longer measured by follower counts or engagement rates, but rather by the development of trust and the quality of conversation...None of this is about escaping the social internet, but about reclaiming its scale, pace, and purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical architecture of the next social web is already emerging through federated and distributed protocols like ActivityPub...But protocols alone won’t save us. The email protocol is decentralized, yet most email flows through a handful of corporate providers. We need to “rewild the internet,” as Maria Farrell and Robin Berjon mentioned in a Noema essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media as we know it is dying, but we’re not condemned to its ruins. We are capable of building better — smaller, slower, more intentional, more accountable — spaces for digital interaction, spaces where the metrics that matter aren’t engagement and growth but understanding and connection, where algorithms serve the community rather than strip-mining it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last days of social media might be the first days of something more human: a web that remembers why we came online in the first place — not to be harvested but to be heard, not to go viral but to find our people, not to scroll but to connect. We built these systems, and we can certainly build better ones. The question is whether we will do this or whether we will continue to drown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/last-days-social-media-noemag</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/last-days-social-media-noemag</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 20:19 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>essay</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon Launching Quote Posts</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting next week, you’ll see an option to quote another user by selecting the repost — or “boost” — button, allowing you to add your thoughts to someone else’s post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastodon is bringing quote posts to mastodon.online and mastodon.social first, but will roll out the feature more broadly with the Mastodon 4.5 update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also worked on a technical &lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/fediverse/fep/src/branch/main/fep/044f/fep-044f.md"&gt;specification&lt;/a&gt; for quote posting in the fediverse and hopes that other platforms will adopt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/masdoton-launches-quote-posts</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/masdoton-launches-quote-posts</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 19:51 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet's Hidden Creative Renaissance</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Great post from &lt;a href="https://blogtherapy.substack.com/about"&gt;Alexandra&lt;/a&gt;. Tons of great resources to explore as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...recently the indie web has been experiencing a revival, as more netizens look for connection outside the walled gardens created by tech giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kinds of posts and projects you’ll find are creative, personal, experimental, and sometimes so intimate you feel like you’re intruding. However, they’re not the kind of content that usually goes viral on TikTok. That’s beside the point. The focus isn’t on personal branding, growth or monetization, or “content” creation, but on freedom from those things. Instead of polished, 10-second snippets optimized for mass-appeal, engagement, and profit, these are largely slow-cooked projects made just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against a backdrop of accelerating enshittification and living chronically online — especially since the COVID pandemic — there’s growing interest in the slower, more intentional and connected experience the indie web promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In different corners of the mainstream internet, younger users are talking about reclaiming their attention spans, trading in their smartphones, writing essays for fun, journaling, discovering long reads, reading fiction, and picking up hobbies like crocheting or scrapbooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discoverability can be a challenge...But what seems like a bug can really be a feature of the small web experience: the point is to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the greater context of the global internet, the small web will never completely replace big platforms or serve every need, nor should it. Social media is still the main source of news in many parts of the world, offering valuable tools for community-building, commerce, even activism. For their part, most indie web creators are happy to exist outside of the mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/internet-hidden-creative-rennaissance-indieweb</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/internet-hidden-creative-rennaissance-indieweb</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-09-12 07:55 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>creativity</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webmentions are back</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Nice to see my GitHub Actions back to green after fixing my script to send webmentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to discover more amazing content I can link out to.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/webmentions-are-back</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/webmentions-are-back</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-21 19:15 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>webmention</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the social web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work of a product team, when working with new technology, is to abstract away as much of this complexity as possible, so that it feels friendly and approachable to new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My strongest belief about the social web is that if we want it to succeed, we have to keep lowering the barrier to entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/reflections-on-social-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/reflections-on-social-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-18 19:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ghost</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghost 6.0</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Ghost 6.0 we're introducing another new distribution channel: The social web. Now, millions of people can discover, follow, like and reply to your posts from any supported social web client - including Bluesky, Mastodon, Threads, Flipboard, Ghost, WordPress, Surf, WriteFreely, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as people can visit your Ghost website in any browser, subscribe with any feed reader, or receive newsletters in any email client, they can now follow your Ghost publication from any social web client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike closed platforms with restrictive algorithms, open web protocols create a direct connection between you and your subscribers which you have full control over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've been around on the web for while, and you can remember back that far... you might even call it the return of the blogosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love the introduction of social components to the Ghost platform. I'm so ready for the return of the blogosphere and the return to open protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ghost-6-changelog</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ghost-6-changelog</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-18 19:24 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ghost</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>publishing</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The newly redesigned Blogroll Club</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] ]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/newly-redesigned-blogroll</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/newly-redesigned-blogroll</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-18 19:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogrollclub</category>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLS over ActivityPub Draft</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://messaginglayersecurity.rocks/"&gt;Messaging Layer Security (MLS)&lt;/a&gt; is an IETF standard for end-to-end encrypted (E2EE) messaging. It lets people on laptops and phones communicate with each other in a secure way that no one in between can see.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
MLS is designed to use pluggable lower-level protocols. This specification defines an envelope format for distributing MLS messages through the network, and an Activity Streams 2.0 profile for the packets of application data stored inside the messages.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This specification is ready for review from both ActivityPub developers and security analysts. It’s time to start making proof-of-concept implementations and testing interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: https://socialwebfoundation.org/2025/06/13/mls-over-activitypub-draft/&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mls-over-activitypub-draft</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mls-over-activitypub-draft</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-14 10:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>protocol</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>w3c</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faircamp - A static site generator for audio producers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;This is such a cool project. Looks like it's super simple to get started with and it's packed with a ton of features so creators get to stay in their flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like how creators are showcased.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/faircamp-static-site-audio-producers</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/faircamp-static-site-audio-producers</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-05 20:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>faircamp</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>staticsite</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>tools</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FediForum Day One Recap</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Just wrapped up a successful first day of FediForum.

The vibes and energy were high. Tons of great conversations and projects around the social web.

A few emerging themes I noticed:

- Identity
- Portability / Interoperability
- Feeds
- Commerce

Ian Forrester kicked us off with his Public Service &amp; The Fediverse keynote [(Slides)](https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HuQF_sI19zwByM793uvdl7BECneRmni_H9uOG-oFkdM/edit?slide=id.g420c517061_0_0#slide=id.g420c517061_0_0). 

One of the ideas that struck a chord of public service integrated into the fediverse. More specifically the interest that sparked in me was that publishing and social shouldn't be two separate things. Following the POSSE principle from the IndieWeb. You publish on your own site and then it's syndicated elsewhere. 

This was interesting enough for me I even hosted a session on the topic, I think it was called Tightening the Loop between CMS and the Fediverse. It was my first unconference, so I appreciated the way the agenda was built. Announce your topic, see whether there's interest, put it on the agenda, chat with fellow participants. Super easy.

## Identity &amp; Portability

These are such a huge topic but for the purpose of this post, I'm lumping them together.

[https://bounce-migrate.appspot.com/](https://bounce.so) is one of the projects aiming to make portability easy. What's so interesting is they're making it easy to migrate across protocols. So if you're in one network like ATProto (Bluesky), migrating to the Fediverse should be relatively seamless with https://bounce.so. 

Some great discussions that emerged on the topic as well include:

- **Reputation** - How do you build a web of trust?
- **Compartmentalization and Deduplication** - A single identity or multiple identities? When "following" someone, which of their feeds takes priority?

## Feeds

Talk of feeds was everywhere. I made a note to myself throughout the conference.

&gt; It's amazing how big the feeds theme is. Feed ownership, customization, and sharing. All powered by open protocols.

- [Bonfire releases 1.0](https://bonfirenetworks.org/posts/bonfire_social_rc/) - Congrats to the Bonfire team on this milestone. I haven't tried Bonfire myself, but the Circles feature caught my attention. It made me reminiscent of Google+.
- [Surf.Social is now in beta](https://https://surf.social) - As an avid user and curator of RSS feeds, I'd heard about Surf before but hadn't really looked into it. The beta release was announced at the conference and I quickly was able to sign up and download it. Kudos to the team on this milestone and thanks for being so responsive to my request to join the beta. I did almost no waiting in the waitlist. Once I have a chance to try it out and get familiar with it, I'll share some thoughts.
- [Channels](https://home.channel.org/) from the folks at [Newsmast Foundation](https://www.newsmastfoundation.org/) looks like an interesting way to curate and customize feeds. 
[Bring Your Own Timeline Algorithm](https://huggingface.co/spaces/mozilla-ai/byota) leverages semantic search to help you seamlessly leverage the power of algorithmic feeds but doing so under your control. Cool use of AI. 

There were a few unconference sessions on the topic as well. 

## Commerce

It was great to see folks talking about enabling creators to earn a living on open platforms and the social web. 

I believe [Bandwagon.fm](https://bandwagon.fm/home) showed of an implementation of a payments and subscription system built on top of [Emmisary](https://emissary.dev/), a social web toolkit.

## Additional Resources

Here's a list of other links and projects I was exposed to during the conference.

- [FediForum Advisory Board and Organizers](https://fediforum.org/people/)
- [An Internet of Many Autonomous Communities](https://blog.rudyfraser.com/an-internet-of-many-autonomous-communities/)
- [FediMeteo - Weather updates in your Fediverse Timeline](https://fedimeteo.com/)
- [Public Interest Technology Group (PITG)](https://pitg.network/)
- [Coalition for Content Provenance and Authenticity (C2PA)](https://c2pa.org/)
- [A New Social](https://www.anew.social/)
- [WeDistribute FediForum Live Coverage](https://wedistribute.org/2025/06/fediforum-june-2025/)
- [BBC Human Values](https://bbc.github.io/humanvalues/)
- [The Indie Beat Radio](https://theindiebeat.fm/)
- [Tie Yourself to a Federated Mastodon](https://pluralistic.net/2024/11/02/ulysses-pact/#tie-yourself-to-a-federated-mast)
- [The No Network Effect](https://snarfed.org/2013-04-13_the-no-network-effect)

As always, Cory Doctorow was great way to close out the first day. I even learned a new term, tron-pilled. Which means as a creator of a platform, you're on the side of the users.  

Looking forward to tomorrow's sessions!]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/fediforum-day-1-jun-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/fediforum-day-1-jun-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-05 17:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediforum</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;Agentic Fediverse&amp;quot; is the idea of a new kind of network federation, a complementary iteration on the concept of federation currently established with ActivityPub. It's an experiment and something that we in Muni Town are still trying to define more concretely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tenets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still working on defining the core tenets of the agentic fediverse, but here is what we have so far.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An agentic fediverse is...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fediverse of agents; agent-centric, as opposed to server-centric.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local-first; solve local problems for local people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessible by default; inaccessibility is a bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematically consensual; architected on the basis of informed consent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/agentic-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/agentic-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>munitown</category>
      <category>agents</category>
      <category>agentic</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Social Web - Hello, Social Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're A New Social, a new non-profit organization focused on building cross-protocol tools and services for the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our mission is to liberate people's networks from their platforms, enabling &lt;a href="https://www.augment.ink/bridges-the-last-network-effect/?ref=anew.social"&gt;The Last Network Effect&lt;/a&gt; and leveling the playing field across the open social web.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The first project we'll take on to accomplish this mission is &lt;a href="https://fed.brid.gy/?ref=anew.social"&gt;Bridgy Fed&lt;/a&gt;, a service that enables users of ActivityPub-based platforms like Mastodon, ATProto-based platforms like Bluesky, and websites to interact and engage across ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/hello-social-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-17 19:39 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>anewsocial</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>atproto</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Affirmations for bloggers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The affirmations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I've seen and learned. Each of these will be expanded in its own section.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have things to write about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your perspective matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are good enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts don't have to be novel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will read it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are okay!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's okay to ask for things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get started quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can write on a schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgflip.com/1otri4.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Meme of man pointing at himself in the mirror" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ntietz-blogging-affirmations</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/ntietz-blogging-affirmations</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-11 21:42 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll discovery enabled</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Just enabled discovery for my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt; based on the &lt;a href="https://opml.org/blogroll.opml"&gt;OPML blogroll spec&lt;/a&gt;. While technically not part of the spec, I also have similar collections for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. I've added those as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!--...--&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;blogroll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Blogroll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/blogroll//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;youtuberoll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's YouTube Roll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/youtube//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;podroll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Podroll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/podroll//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!--...--&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;youtuberoll doesn't really roll off the tongue, but I'm hesitant to call it videoroll or vidroll. My concerns mainly come from the fact that YouTube != video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-25 22:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>