<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - facebook</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/facebook</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'facebook' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-07-16 11:48 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Zombie Internet</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, the supermajority of engagement on viral AI Facebook pages is just as artificially-generated as the content they publish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it's a child transforming into a water bottle cyborg, a three-armed flight attendant rescuing Tiger Jesus from a muddy plane crash, or a hybrid human-monkey baby being stung to death by giant hornets, all tend to have copy+pasted captions, reactions &amp;amp; comments which usually make no sense in the observed context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've noticed similar patterns on YouTube. Sometime the comments include timestamp links which makes them seem more credible, but upon further inspection, it's all bot activity.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/facebook-zombie-internet-willison</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/facebook-zombie-internet-willison</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-16 11:48 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bots</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>comments</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>facebook</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Meta’s GenAI Infrastructure</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marking a major investment in Meta’s AI future, we are announcing two 24k GPU clusters. We are sharing details on the hardware, network, storage, design, performance, and software that help us extract high throughput and reliability for various AI workloads. We use this cluster design for Llama 3 training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are strongly committed to open compute and open source. We built these clusters on top of Grand Teton, OpenRack, and PyTorch and continue to push open innovation across the industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This announcement is one step in our ambitious infrastructure roadmap. By the end of 2024, we’re aiming to continue to grow our infrastructure build-out that will include 350,000 NVIDIA H100 GPUs as part of a portfolio that will feature compute power equivalent to nearly 600,000 H100s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/building-meta-genai-infrastructure</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/building-meta-genai-infrastructure</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-17 21:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>meta</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>infrastraucture</category>
      <category>generativeai</category>
      <category>genai</category>
      <category>facebook</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Each Facebook User is Monitored by Thousands of Companies</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now most internet users know their online activity is constantly tracked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is the scale of this surveillance? Judging from data collected by Facebook and &lt;a href="https://innovation.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/CR_Who-Shares-Your-Information-With-Facebook.pdf"&gt;newly described in a unique study&lt;/a&gt; by non-profit consumer watchdog Consumer Reports, it’s massive, and examining the data may leave you with more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a panel of 709 volunteers who shared archives of their Facebook data, Consumer Reports found that a total of 186,892 companies sent data about them to the social network. On average, each participant in the study had their data sent to Facebook by 2,230 companies. That number varied significantly, with some panelists’ data listing over 7,000 companies providing their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Exactly Does This Data Contain?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The data examined by Consumer Reports in this study comes from two types of collection: events and custom audiences. Both categories include information about what people do outside of Meta’s platforms.
&lt;br&gt;
Custom audiences allow advertisers to upload customer lists to Meta, often including identifiers like email addresses and mobile advertising IDs...
&lt;br&gt;
The other category of data collection, “events,” describes interactions that the user had with a brand, which can occur outside of Meta’s apps and in the real world. Events can include visiting a page on a company’s website, leveling up in a game, visiting a physical store, or purchasing a product...
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Can I See My Data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Facebook users can browse through the list of companies that have sent their data to Facebook by going to: [https://accountscenter.facebook.com/info_and_permissions](https://accountscenter.facebook.com/info_and_permissions)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/facebook-users-monitored-thousands-companies-markup</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/facebook-users-monitored-thousands-companies-markup</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-17 20:09 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>facebook</category>
      <category>meta</category>
      <category>surveillance</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta announces AI experiences in Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re starting to roll out AI stickers across our apps, and soon you’ll be able to edit your images or even co-create them with friends on Instagram using our new AI editing tools, restyle and backdrop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re introducing Meta AI in beta, an advanced conversational assistant that’s available on WhatsApp, Messenger, and Instagram, and is coming to Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses and Quest 3. Meta AI can give you real-time information and generate photorealistic images from your text prompts in seconds to share with friends. (Available in the US only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re also launching 28 more AIs in beta, with unique interests and personalities. Some are played by cultural icons and influencers, including Snoop Dogg, Tom Brady, Kendall Jenner, and Naomi Osaka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over time, we’re making AIs for businesses and creators available, and releasing our AI studio for people and developers to build their own AIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These new AI experiences also come with a new set of challenges for our industry. We’re rolling out our new AIs slowly and have built in safeguards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/meta-announces-ai-experiences-fb-whatsapp-ig</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/meta-announces-ai-experiences-fb-whatsapp-ig</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-28 10:12 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>meta</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>facebook</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>