<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - radio</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/radio</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'radio' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-04-14 15:18 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Rock AlterLatino from Radio Bilingue</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;While listening to &lt;a href="https://891khol.org/"&gt;KHOL&lt;/a&gt; earlier today, they were rebroadcasting a recording of &lt;a href="http://https://https://radiobilingue.org/rb-programas/alterlatino/"&gt;A Todo Pulmon&lt;/a&gt;, a radio show from &lt;a href="https://https://radiobilingue.org/"&gt;Radio Bilingue&lt;/a&gt; in Fresno, CA. Good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/radio-bilingue-rock-alterlatino</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/radio-bilingue-rock-alterlatino</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-14 15:18 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>rock</category>
      <category>alternative</category>
      <category>fresno</category>
      <category>radiobilingue</category>
      <category>khol</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enjoying El Sonido from KEXP</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I just found &lt;a href="https://www.kexp.org/shows/El-Sonido/"&gt;El Sonido from KEXP&lt;/a&gt;. Albina Cabrera is a great host. I've already found a few new songs and artists to listen to I otherwise wouldn't have been aware of or exposed to.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/enjoying-kexp-el-sonido</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/enjoying-kexp-el-sonido</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-08 23:36 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>kexp</category>
      <category>shows</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Year For Blogging To Pump Up The Volume</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of pontificating lately that the web is ripe for a blogging renaissance, wishing for it to be true. Much of it from people who don’t seem to notice that’s it’s already begun. Maybe they don’t anymore know quite where to look. Maybe the sorts of blogging they’re seeing isn’t what they mean. (To the blognoscenti, do things like “wordvomits” count?) If you haven’t seen it, either, that’s okay. All you have to do is choose to be a part of it. There’s never been a better time: those who managed to monopolize our attentions and keep too many of us chattering for a few hundred characters at a time to the benefit of advertisers are losing their relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not one for making personal resolutions, but let me suggest one on behalf of the blogosphere: this is the year we pump up the volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogging-pump-up-volume</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blogging-pump-up-volume</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-02 18:36 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>writing</category>
      <category>movie</category>
      <category>radio</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radiooooo, The Musical Time Machine</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiooooo is a project born in 2013, dreamt up by a little family of friends, both djs and music lovers, who decided to share their record collections and the fruit of many years of research, for all to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Sharing and discovering » , « curiosity and pleasure » these are the foundations of this musical time machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiooooo is a collaborative website, whose goal is to open each and everyone’s horizons through culture and beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/radiooooo</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/radiooooo</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-10-06 09:33 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>radio</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress at 25 and the Indie Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Good discussion on the open web, self-hosting, radio, and the indie web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/podcast-wordpress-indieweb-reality2</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/podcast-wordpress-indieweb-reality2</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-08-30 21:02 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>selfhost</category>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QRZ New Ham Jumpstart Program</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Very cool! QRZ just announced the &lt;a href="https://forums.qrz.com/index.php?threads/announcing-the-qrz-new-ham-jumpstart-program.823607/"&gt;New Ham Jumpstart Program&lt;/a&gt;, a new program to make it easier for new ham radio operators to quickly get on the air.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/qrz-new-ham-jumstart-program</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/qrz-new-ham-jumstart-program</guid>
      <pubDate>08/31/2022 21:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>qrz</category>
      <category>hamradio</category>
      <category>fcc</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to listen to internet radio using VLC</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

Music streaming services like Spotify generally do a good job of making recommendations based on your music tastes. By applying algorithms to your listening history, they're able to provide you with a listening experience tailored to you. When it comes to music discovery though, it can be difficult to find new music so you often end up listening to music that sounds very similar. Internet radio can help expose you to music you otherwise wouldn't normally listen to. Radio stations like those on [SomaFM](https://somafm.com/) provide a wide variety of high quality music channels. There's other online radio stations out there, many which provide a built-in audio player. As I've written in previous posts though ([How to watch Twitch streams using VLC](/posts/how-to-watch-twitch-using-vlc/) &amp; [Podcast management with RSS &amp; VLC](/notes/rss-vlc-podcast-management)), VLC is a versatile tool. As a result, it's no surprise you can also use it to listen to online radio streams. This post is mostly a note to myself, but I encourage you to try it as well. 

## Prerequisites

- [VLC](https://www.videolan.org/index.html)

The commands below were run on Linux. Since VLC is cross-platform, the same commands should work on those platforms as well. 

## Listen to internet radio

The first thing you'll need is the URL of the stream you want to listen to. Usually it's provided on the station's website. You can also browse through [RadioBrowser](https://www.radio-browser.info/) to find a station and its stream URL.

Once you have the URL, in the terminal, enter the following command:

```bash
vlc &lt;STREAM-URL&gt;
```

Replace `&lt;STREAM-URL&gt;` with the address of your stream.

After a few seconds, VLC launches and your stream should start playing.

If you prefer to stream audio without VLC's visual interface, use the following command.

```bash
cvlc &lt;STREAM-URL&gt;
```

Note that without the UI you won't have access to any playback controls. 

Happy listening! 
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-to-listen-internet-radio-using-vlc</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-to-listen-internet-radio-using-vlc</guid>
      <pubDate>12/28/2021 16:24 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>vlc</category>
      <category>open source</category>
      <category>radio</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Radio History (U.S)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;While browsing the interwebs, I ran into the site &lt;a href="https://earlyradiohistory.us/"&gt;United States Early Radio History&lt;/a&gt; which contains events spanning different time periods. As an operator it's fascinating to learn about the history and see how radio continues to play a large role in our day-to-day.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/early-radio-history-us</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/early-radio-history-us</guid>
      <pubDate>10/29/2021 02:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>communication</category>
      <category>hamradion</category>
      <category>history</category>
      <category>unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>