<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - digitalminimalism</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/digitalminimalism</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'digitalminimalism' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-01-14 21:13 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Calm Technology with Amber Case</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Interesting interview and introduction to &lt;a href="https://calmtech.com/"&gt;Calm Technology&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.calmtech.institute/"&gt;Calm Tech Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/calm-tech-interview</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/calm-tech-interview</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-14 21:13 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>digitalminimalism</category>
      <category>technology</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital minimalism: A moral duty?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I saw a reference to this paper yesterday and added it to my Read-It-Later list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a link to the original paper: &lt;a href="https://philpapers.org/archive/AYLITA.pdf"&gt;https://philpapers.org/archive/AYLITA.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chances are, I wasnt going to get to it until way later with the backlog of other things I want to read later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucky for me, that was the subject of the latest Deep Questions episode. Cal does a nice job breaking down the main arguments of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KK9ktzbBDPE" title="A thumbnail of Deep Questions Podcast Episode on Digital Minimalism"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/KK9ktzbBDPE/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="A thumbnail of Deep Questions Podcast Episode on Digital Minimalism" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main takeaway for me was, technology is a great tool. However, when it robs you of your rational decision making abilities and pushes you to compulsive behaviors that move you away from the habits and practices that fuel your growth, it's a problem. For example, lets say you want to build a habit of reading or working out. Unfortunately, when you &lt;INSERT TIME SUCKING DISTRACTION OF CHOICE&gt;, time, attention, and energy that would've otherwise been spent on those habits is now diverted towards the distraction. That is irrational and goes against your desire to grow, yet making the rational choice is where most of us struggle. Although the paper focuses on our digital lives, I can see other ways similar arguments can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also included the audio version as well: &lt;a href="https://www.buzzsprout.com/1121972/episodes/16124495-ep-327-would-kant-use-tiktok"&gt;https://www.buzzsprout.com/1121972/episodes/16124495-ep-327-would-kant-use-tiktok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/digital-minimalism-moral-duty-deep-questions</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/digital-minimalism-moral-duty-deep-questions</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 09:56 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>digitalminimalism</category>
      <category>postcast</category>
      <category>deepquestions</category>
      <category>philosophy</category>
      <category>calnewport</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Daylight DC1 is a $729 attempt to build a calmer computer</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Like many in the comments, I like the idea of this device and what it's aiming to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;LivePaper&amp;quot; display technology seems interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At $729 though, it seems a little steep. I paid a fraction of that for my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/uses"&gt;Onyx Boox Nova Air 2&lt;/a&gt; and I have most of the functionality of this device. As an e-reader, note-taking device, and tablet that can install any Android app, it works perfectly fine for my use cases and I'm very happy with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I'm interested in seeing whether this takes off or whether it ends up being another Rabbit R1 or Humane Ai Pin.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/daylight-dc-1-tablet-computer</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/daylight-dc-1-tablet-computer</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-26 16:48 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>eink</category>
      <category>digitalminimalism</category>
      <category>daylight</category>
      <category>tablet</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>gadgets</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year with the Light Phone 2</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://media1.giphy.com/media/v1.Y2lkPTc5MGI3NjExZXVrN2kxamptbnZtdTVwZnM1ZndnOWFydnBlOTdja2FpMTI1cjdnZSZlcD12MV9pbnRlcm5hbF9naWZfYnlfaWQmY3Q9Zw/3o6ZtfZp8ID54YUne0/giphy.gif" class="img-fluid" alt="GIF image with man signing into microphone with caption don't call it a comeback" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between this article and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/dumbphone-boom-real"&gt;The Dumbphone Boom is Real&lt;/a&gt;, I'm seeing more publications on the subject. Far from a comeback, but still cool to see.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/one-year-retrospect-lightphone-2-verge</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/one-year-retrospect-lightphone-2-verge</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-28 20:43 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>dumbphone</category>
      <category>retro</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>lightphone</category>
      <category>minimalism</category>
      <category>digitalminimalism</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dumbphone Boom Is Real</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will Stults spent too much time on his iPhone, doom-scrolling the site formerly known as Twitter and tweeting angrily at Elon Musk as if the billionaire would actually notice. Stults’s partner, Daisy Krigbaum, was addicted to Pinterest and YouTube, bingeing videos on her iPhone before going to sleep. Two years ago, they both tried Apple’s Screen Time restriction tool and found it too easy to disable, so the pair decided to trade out their iPhones for more low-tech devices. They’d heard about so-called dumbphones, which lacked the kinds of bells and whistles—a high-resolution screen, an app store, a video camera—that made smartphones so addictive. But they found the process of acquiring one hard to navigate. “The information on it was kind of disparate and hard to get to. A lot of people who know the most about dumbphones spend the least time online,” Krigbaum said. A certain irony presented itself: figuring out a way to be less online required aggressive online digging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing dumbphone fervor may be motivated, in part, by the discourse around child safety online. Parents are increasingly confronted with evidence that sites like Instagram and TikTok intentionally try to hook their children. Using those sites can increase teens’ anxiety and lower their self-esteem, according to some studies, and smartphones make it so that kids are logged on constantly. Why should this situation be any healthier for adults? After almost two decades with iPhones, the public seems to be experiencing a collective ennui with digital life. So many hours of each day are lived through our portable, glowing screens, but the Internet isn’t even fun anymore. We lack the self-control to wean ourselves off, so we crave devices that actively prevent us from getting sucked into them. That means opting out of the prevailing technology and into what Cal Newport, a contributing writer for The New Yorker, has called a more considered “digital minimalism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While dumbphones aren't a cure-all for unhealthy technology habits, as a dumbphone user, I can relate to the frustrations that come from the lack of device availability and support. Even when new devices hit the market, they tend to be targeted towards non-US markets.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/dumbphone-boom-real</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/dumbphone-boom-real</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 23:38 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>dumbphone</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>culture</category>
      <category>digitalminimalism</category>
      <category>minimalism</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>