<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - automattic</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/automattic</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'automattic' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-06-30 20:21 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr’s move to WordPress and fediverse integration is ‘on hold’</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;That's unfortunate. Having Tumblr as your frontend for posting and curating feeds, with WordPress as the backend and integrated with decentralized networks like the Fediverse for distribution would've been amazing. It sounds like Tumblr is still strategic to Automattic and as more people move away from the centralized social platforms and towards their own corners of the internet, having these differente building blocks in place will be even more important.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-wordpress-fediverse-integration-pause</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-wordpress-fediverse-integration-pause</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-30 20:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gen Z Leading Tumblr Revival</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Gen Z, the site has found new life. As of 2025, Gen Z makes up 50% of Tumblr’s active monthly users and accounts for 60% of new sign-ups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't call it a comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User numbers spiked in January during the near-ban of TikTok and jumped again last year when Brazil temporarily banned X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep up with the momentum, Tumblr introduced Reddit-style Communities in December, letting users connect over shared interests like photography and video games. In January, it debuted Tumblr TV—a TikTok-like feature that serves as both a GIF search engine and a short-form video platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps Tumblr’s greatest strength is that it isn’t TikTok or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For its users...that’s part of the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr's been through a rough ride, but at the core there's a lot of nice things to like about it. In previous posts, I talked about some opportunities for Tumblr as a result of &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr/"&gt;replatforming on top of WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and its expressed intent for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-still-working-fediverse-integration/"&gt;ActivityPub integration&lt;/a&gt;. In doing so, not only would it enable an intuitive front-end for publishing different kinds of posts, but it would also provide opportunities for self-hosting and a more federated and decentralized social platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to see where this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/gen-z-flocking-tumblr-millennials-musk-zuckerberg-safe-space-2025-4"&gt;Related post from Business Insider's Amanda Hoover&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/gen-z-tumblr-revival</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/gen-z-tumblr-revival</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-04-08 06:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>genz</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr adds Reddit-like ‘communities’</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr is introducing a new Community feature — in-app groups organized by topic or interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communities are similar to subreddits or Facebook groups and had previously been in beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given recent announcements like &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr/"&gt;Tumblr replatforming on top of WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/wordpress-activitypub-plugin/"&gt;WordPress adding support for ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt;, I could see communities becoming not only an alternative to Reddit, but also Lemmy in the Fediverse.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-adding-reddit-like-communities</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tumblr-adding-reddit-like-communities</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-16 22:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>reddit</category>
      <category>communities</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>lemmy</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shipping Tumblr and WordPress</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Automattic acquired Tumblr we’ve made it more efficient, grown its revenue, and worked to improve the platform. But there’s one part of the plan that we haven’t yet started, which is to run Tumblr on WordPress. I’m pleased to say we’re kicking off that project now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little late, but I can't express how much I love this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love Tumblr’s streamlined posting experience and its current product direction. We’re not changing that. We’re talking about running Tumblr’s backend on WordPress. You won’t even notice a difference from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it sounds outside the scope of the original plan, it would be amazing if the shared backend as well as the Tumblr publishing front-end made their way into the open-source version of WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would open the door to self-hosted personal websites that also make it significantly easier to post content in smaller chunks like a microblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pair that with ActivityPub integrations and you now have a connected web of individuals where the first place they post content to is their own website and for discovery / broader reach can also federate and post to other platforms that also support protocols like ActivityPub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't wait to see how this project develops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you yearn for the days when people owned their corner of the internet and expressed themselves in wild and wacky ways? Do you want to see an internet focused on creativity, art, and ideas instead of debating and dividing? Do you think content and data should be owned by authors and artists, instead of getting locked behind the closed platform of a mega-corporation? Do you want to build an internet where anyone with a story can tell it, and anyone with a product can sell it, regardless of income, gender, politics, language, or where they live in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to all of those is YES.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/shipping-wordpress-tumblr</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-09-05 22:15 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>microblog</category>
      <category>posse</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beeper was just acquired by Automattic</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beeper, the upstart messaging app that attempts to corral all your messaging services into one inbox, is being acquired by Automattic, the giant that runs Wordpress.com, Tumblr, and a number of other hugely popular web properties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exciting especially given some of the recent developments in the EU. What's most interesting to me is how Beeper leverages open protocols like Matrix and for bridging capabilities where possible to provide secure messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more people moving to smaller spaces to communicate with their communities, being able to do so in a single place without everyone being on the same platform like in the early days of the internet is a welcome development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional coverage from the &lt;a href="https://blog.beeper.com/2024/04/09/beeper-is-now-available/"&gt;Beeper blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we’re announcing today…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more waitlist – Beeper is now available to everyone!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beeper has been acquired by Automattic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our new Android app is out of beta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re renaming Beeper Cloud → Beeper (sorry for the confusion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and &lt;a href="https://ma.tt/2024/04/beeper-texts/"&gt;Matt Mullenweg's blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the announcement went out that we’re combining the best technology from Beeper and Texts to create a great private, secure, and open source messaging client for people to have control of their communications. We’re going to use the Beeper brand, because it’s fun. This is not unlike how browsers have evolved, where solid tech and encryption on top of an open ecosystem has created untold value for humanity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A lot of people are asking about iMessage on Android… I have zero interest in fighting with Apple, I think instead it’s best to focus on messaging networks that want more engagement from power-user clients. This is an area I’m excited to work on when I return from my sabbatical next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/beeper-acquired-automattic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/beeper-acquired-automattic</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-09 22:06 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>beeper</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>matrix</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr and WordPress to Sell Users’ Data to Train AI Tools</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tumblr and WordPress.com are preparing to sell user data to Midjourney and OpenAI, according to a source with internal knowledge about the deals and internal documentation referring to the deals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal documentation details a messy and controversial process within Tumblr itself. One internal post made by Cyle Gage, a product manager at Tumblr, states that a query made to prepare data for OpenAI and Midjourney compiled a huge number of user posts that it wasn’t supposed to. It is not clear from Gage’s post whether this data has already been sent to OpenAI and Midjourney, or whether Gage was detailing a process for scrubbing the data before it was to be sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally enjoy what Automattic does for the web as a whole. However, if these claims are true, it's unfortunate. I believe there's a way to opt-out, but I'd love to learn more before jumping to conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, WordPress (.com not .org) and Tumblr are platforms just like Reddit, Twitter, and the Meta set of offerings. I'm sure somewhere in their Terms of Service, there's some clauses around their ownserhip of the data you published on their platforms and just like it's sold to data brokers and advertisers, they can also sell it to companies training AI models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To counter these types of moves from platforms, I wish it were as easy as saying &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/own_your_data"&gt;&amp;quot;build your own platform&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Doing so can be as &amp;quot;simple&amp;quot; as setting up a website using &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/own_your_links"&gt;your own domain&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, today, it's still not as easy to do and one of the products / companies that help you do that is WordPress. I think it's important though to note the distinction there between WordPress the company and WordPress the technology. Another piece that complicates building your own site is, there's still other ways for companies training AI models to use data that's publicly available on the internet. These are the arguments that are currently being litigated in several legal cases. Maybe there are opportunities to explore &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/verge-ai-robots-txt/"&gt;a robots.txt for AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI models need high quality data that's representative and as close as possible to the real world in order to improve. There is a role here for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/cosmopedia-ai-synthetic-dataset/"&gt;synthetic data&lt;/a&gt;. High quality synthetic data is behind &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/phi-2-huggingface/"&gt;groundbreaking models like Microsoft's Phi&lt;/a&gt;. Instincts tell me that synthetic data can only go so far though and real data is still needed. In that case, as an AI consumer who makes use of these AI models, but don't want to contribute my data, do I have a responsibility to contribute my data to improve the systems that I use? Piracy aside, in some ways it reminds me of torrenting. You usually run into scenarios where there are multiple people downloading a file. However, there's only a handful of seeders who once obtained, make the file available for others to download. There are also additional considerations such as how people are compensated for contributing their data to these systems. It's important to note that this is not a new problem and people had been thinking about this though in different contexts. Maybe it's time to reconsider ideas like &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/research/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Inverse11.pdf"&gt;inverse privacy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://hbr.org/2018/09/a-blueprint-for-a-better-digital-society"&gt;data dignity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no clear answers here and there are a lot of things to consider. However, it's comforting that as a society we're having these conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/automattic-ai-data-tumblr-wordpress</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/automattic-ai-data-tumblr-wordpress</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-27 21:09 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>ai</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Shared Journals for Day One</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shared Journals are a private space for your closest friends and family to shared life updates and memories. Shared Journals introduce a new dimension to journaling, offering a unique way to share your personal stories and experiences with up to 30 selected individuals, while keeping your individual entries private and secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome! When I was writing the post &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/private-social-media"&gt;Private Social Media&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, I wasn't aware that these had already launched. I knew they were in beta but it's great to see they're now generally available. I'll have to give them a try.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/introducing-shared-journals-day-one</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/introducing-shared-journals-day-one</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-23 20:26 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>dayone</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>journal</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goblin - Tumblr meets the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goblin band is an attempt to replicate the colletive creative energy that happens on tumblr and take it to the fediverse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repo&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/johnHackworth/goblin"&gt;https://github.com/johnHackworth/goblin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/goblin-tumblr-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/goblin-tumblr-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 16:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>activitypub</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>firefish</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>federation</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gravatar - Your digital profile beyond blog comments</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I had known about &lt;a href="https://gravatar.com/"&gt;Gravatar&lt;/a&gt; since its early days. I was under the (incorrect) impression that it could only be used to comment on blogs. I thought when you created an account, you added your name, e-mail, and image as part of your profile. Then, when you wanted to comment on blogs, instead of creating individual accounts or profiles, you could just reuse your Gravatar profile. That's partially true. However, I'm happy to report I was wrong and there's so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While commenting on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/blog-posts-can-be-any-length-matt"&gt;Matt Mullenweg's Birthday Gift post&lt;/a&gt;, I didn't use a Gravatar profile. This prompted Matt to kindly respond via e-mail and suggest I check out Gravatar. I put it off for a few days. Eventually, I decided to check it out and I'm glad I did. Thanks &lt;a href="https://ma.tt"&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The signup process was simple. All I had to do was enter my e-mail address. This immediately sent me a confirmation e-mail which I then used to proceed with onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's where things got interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add all the things I was already aware of (name, e-mail, photo). However, you can also do much more than that! You can add your own verified accounts, links, contact information, and payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of this writing these options include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounts
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X / Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TikTok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tumblr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fediverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vimeo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TripIt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foursquare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact info
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E-mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone number (home, work, mobile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Payments
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PayPal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venmo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Litecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dogecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethereum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XRP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cardano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to those integrations, you can also provide as many of your own custom links as you'd like. In my case, I've chosen to link to my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt;. The options are endless though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have a &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/"&gt;Linktree&lt;/a&gt; profile so I can't objectively say how Gravatar compares to those offerings. At their core though, Gravatar and Linktree seem to address similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not yet committed to having your own place on the internet (website/blog) or if you're looking for a way to organize your digital identity in single place, Gravatar is an excellent option. I'd encourage you to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find my Gravatar profile at &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/gravatar"&gt;lqdev.me/gravatar&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/gravatar-digital-profile-beyond-blog-comments</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/gravatar-digital-profile-beyond-blog-comments</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-15 11:18 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>profile</category>
      <category>online</category>
      <category>gravatar</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>comments</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>identity</category>
      <category>linktree</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>bloggin</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Automaticc owns Tumblr</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Last I heard of Tumblr, they were owned by Verizon. While readying the book &lt;a href="https://book.micro.blog/"&gt;Indie Microblogging&lt;/a&gt; by Manton Reece, I learned (and later confirmed) they were owned by Automaticc, the company behind WordPress. Out of the the different homes it's had, I can't think of a better place for it.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/til-automaticc-tumblr</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/til-automaticc-tumblr</guid>
      <pubDate>2022-10-09 20:49 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tumblr</category>
      <category>automattic</category>
      <category>til</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>