<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - physicalmedia</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/physicalmedia</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'physicalmedia' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-01-14 18:55 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>How do you watch Blu-Ray on PC?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I have a preference for physical media. There's many reasons, some related to the sentiment of &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/landlord-of-your-notes"&gt;owning vs. renting content&lt;/a&gt;. Along the same lines, streaming services and service providers can change the terms of service and you have little to no control over it. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westworld_(TV_series)"&gt;Westworld&lt;/a&gt; is an example of that. One day, HBO decided to pull it from its streaming service and physical copies were the only way you could watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on to my most recent experience trying to play a Blu-Ray disc on my PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I decided to sit down to watch an episode of Westworld. Usually, I get the DVD version. In this case though, I had the Blu-Ray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an external Blu-Ray player so I thought, &amp;quot;Great! Let me just plug that into my laptop and start the show&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I thought was a simple task, ended up taking me about 20 minutes to figure out and even then I got to a subpar solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer playing media either with MPV or VLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it wouldn't play so I decided to go online and figure out why. Turns out, that's not supported out of the box and to get it working you need to download an additional DLL and &lt;a href="https://www.easefab.com/resource/play-blu-ray-with-vlc.html"&gt;configure a few things in the VLC settings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could've gone through that process, but I just wanted to watch a show. There's got to be an easier way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I turned to the built-in Media Player in Windows. No luck there either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up going with the &lt;a href="https://www.leawo.com/blu-ray-player/"&gt;Leawo Blu-Ray player&lt;/a&gt;. Although it's free, you have to deal with pop-ups prompting you to upgrade to the paid version. It works though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would prefer to use VLC or the built-in media player but it's unfortunate using them isn't as straightforward. Now that I have some more time, I'll set up VLC so that next time, it can &amp;quot;just work&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll close it out with a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you watch Blu-Rays on your PC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/contact"&gt;Send me a message&lt;/a&gt; and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/how-do-you-watch-blueray-on-pc</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/how-do-you-watch-blueray-on-pc</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-14 18:55 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>bluray</category>
      <category>media</category>
      <category>physicalmedia</category>
      <category>vlc</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My streaming fatigue got so bad I started collecting DVDs</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending years reassuring myself that I don’t need physical copies of movies because of streaming, DVDs have officially reentered my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walmart...Thrift stores, flea markets, the library, and even my local mall’s FYE have also become places I frequent to get my hands on oft-ignored discs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense to subscribe to all these services if you’re into the exclusive content on each one and have the patience to sift through their massive libraries. However, all I’ve been watching lately is the junk on Discovery Plus, simply because I’m too tired to find anything else — especially when the extremely specific shows and movies I want to watch keep switching services or just aren’t available. One of the most devastating examples of this was when both The Office and Parks and Recreation moved from Netflix to Peacock, disrupting the casual binge-watching sessions that I would default to when I was done with work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the past year, nearly every streaming service has raised its prices, including Netflix, Disney Plus, Hulu, Paramount Plus, Discovery Plus, and Apple TV Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying DVDs are flawless: there’s a reason no one wants them anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, it’s still nice to have something that you physically own and don’t even need an internet connection to use. So when Best Buy confirmed it would stop selling DVDs this year and rumors emerged that Walmart would do the same, I was pretty disappointed. I can’t imagine Walmart without its bin of DVDs, nor can I even see Best Buy without its already-shrunken selection of movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2024, and I’m not ready to say goodbye to DVDs — in fact, I’m just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article from Emma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I've been doing the same. Just a few weekends ago, I got something like 8-10 DVDs for ~$25 at my local thrift store. That haul included 3 seasons of The Sopranos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With streaming services taking back control of their content and putting it on their own platforms, I don't want to have to keep signing up for a new service just to watch the shows and movies I enjoy. Also, that's assuming you can find the content to begin with (i.e. Westworld).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parks and Recreation, The Office, and Breaking Bad were some of the first shows I started collecting and have slowly been building up my collection. To save on space, I've ditched the cases and have the DVDs organized in a CD case. I've not only limited myself to DVDs but have also started collecting CDs as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I want variety, I just use one of the free streaming services like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justwatch.com/us/provider/freevee"&gt;Freevee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pluto.tv/"&gt;Pluto TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://tubitv.com/"&gt;Tubi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are ads but at least I'm not paying for it and I know that's part of the deal. There are a ton of good older (and sometimes original) TV shows and movies on those platforms to keep me entertained. The most recent ones being Stargate and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/vampires-kiss-movie"&gt;Vampire's Kiss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-26 15:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>streaming</category>
      <category>media</category>
      <category>dvds</category>
      <category>movies</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>physicalmedia</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>