<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - posts</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/posts</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'posts' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-01-20 21:21 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Short Long Form</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;This is something I've been dealing with on my site. I separate my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/1"&gt;long-form&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;short-form&lt;/a&gt; posts. However, I don't have a hard limit that clearly defines which is which. An initial reason for the separation was, I wanted to have a feed that was easy to scroll through. That was harder to do if I was rendering an entire long-form post as part of the feed. In the end though, most of my posts are all markdown files and their main distinction is how they are rendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I work on my website redesign, I want to change how I think about posts. I want to separate the post content from the rendering. A post is a post regardless of content and length. Regardless of whether it's a response, image, video, note, or anything in between, I don't want to constrain the content of my post. I can choose to render posts differently depending on whether it's being viewed in a feed or individual post page. The content driving those different views though shouldn't change.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/short-long-form-moreale</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/short-long-form-moreale</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-01-20 21:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>instagram</category>
      <category>posts</category>
      <category>attention</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New RSS links</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Based on the post, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/own-your-rss-links"&gt;own your RSS links&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to set up redirects for all my RSS feeds which was very easy to do using Azure CDN. You can find the updated links in my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;feed page&lt;/a&gt;. If you're currently subscribed to any of those feeds, you can keep using the old URLs but I'd recommend updating your feed reader with the latest URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-rss-feed-links</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/new-rss-feed-links</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-07 19:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>identity</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>posts</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>