<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - mozilla</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/mozilla</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'mozilla' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-05-22 20:21 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Pocket shutting down</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;I haven't used Pocket in a long time but sad to hear it's shutting down. It's great they're offering the option of letting you export your data and platforms like &lt;a href="https://www.manton.org/2025/05/22/with-pocket-shutting-down-ive.html"&gt;Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; are making it easy to host that content on your own site (assuming you're using Micro.blog).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For bookmarking solutions, I've been using my website as well as messages-to-self on Element. What's on my website is the content that I really want to make sure I archive, whereas the messages to self I treat more as a read-it-later solution. Eventually, some of those make it to my website. I'm working on my mobile publishing flow to simplify my bookmarking process but overall, I'm happy with my current system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also another great reminder why owning your content is important.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/pocket-shutting-down</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/pocket-shutting-down</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-22 20:21 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>pocket</category>
      <category>mozilla</category>
      <category>bookmark</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solo - an AI website builder for solopreneurs</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are excited to introduce a new Mozilla Innovation Project, Solo, an AI website builder for solopreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you scour Yelp, it appears a third of businesses lack a website. However, building a website not only provides you with a presence that you own and control but it is also good for business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our survey data shows that the majority of solopreneurs rely upon their “tech buddy” to help build their website. As a result, the websites become stale and harder to maintain as it relies on a call to their buddy. Others without a “tech buddy” try popular website authoring tools and then abandon because it’s simply too hard to author and curate content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using AI to generate the content of your site and source your images, which a solopreneur can then revise into their own unique voice and style levels the playing field. Solo takes this a step further and can also scrape your existing business Yelp or other page so you have an online presence that is totally authentic to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/solo-mozilla-ai-website-builder</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/solo-mozilla-ai-website-builder</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-14 10:10 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>mozilla</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Innovation Week - Explore the Future of AI with Mozilla</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla’s Innovation Week is a journey into the future of technology, where AI is not just a buzzword, but a reality we're actively shaping. Here, we're not just talking about innovation – we're living it through a series of AI-driven explorations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, Innovation Week is more than a showcase. It's a platform for collaboration and inspiration. It's about bringing together ideas, people, and technology to pave the way for a more open and responsible future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/mozilla-innovation-week-dec-2023</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/mozilla-innovation-week-dec-2023</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-12 19:34 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>mozilla</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>