<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - meme</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/meme</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'meme' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-05-25 19:55 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Kabosu</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The face of one of the defining memes of the 2010s, the doge meme, died on Friday. Kabosu, the shiba inu with the knowing face that launched a million internet jokes, was 18 when she died&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/rip-kabosu-doge</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/rip-kabosu-doge</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-25 19:55 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>shiba</category>
      <category>doge</category>
      <category>meme</category>
      <category>dog</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are farm animals thinking?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;I think I've read about this somewhere before...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.”
― George Orwell, Animal Farm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Four legs good, two legs bad.”
― George Orwell, Animal Farm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/what-farm-animals-think-orwell</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/what-farm-animals-think-orwell</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-27 14:57 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>science</category>
      <category>animals</category>
      <category>farm</category>
      <category>orwell</category>
      <category>animallfarm</category>
      <category>meme</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conor McGregor pitching Zune and Windows Phone to Cristiano Ronaldo</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/amplify_video_thumb/1738661229822967808/img/nmYicHlHX6lR_pha.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Conor McGregor speaking to someone with Cristiano Ronaldo next to him" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was probably being said according to Copilot 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristiano, you need to listen to me, mate. You're wasting your time and money on those Apple products. They're overpriced, overrated, and outdated. They're nothing compared to the real champions of technology: Windows Phone and Zune. Trust me, I know what I'm talking about. I've used them both, and they're the best phone and MP3 player ever made. Let me tell you why. First of all, they had a sleek design, a smooth interface, and a unique tile system that was way ahead of its time. They were also compatible with Microsoft's ecosystem, which gave you access to Office, Xbox, and Bing. And don't get me started on the Zune Pass, which let you stream and download unlimited music for a low monthly fee. You can't beat that, mate. Second of all, they had no apps, no games, no support, and no market share. Wait, what? No, no, no, that's not a bad thing. That's a good thing. That means they were exclusive, elite, and original. They were not for the masses, they were for the class. They were not for the sheep, they were for the lions. They were not for the followers, they were for the leaders. They were not for the weak, they were for the strong. They were not for you, they were for me. And they can be for you too, if you have the courage, the vision, and the taste to switch to Windows Phone and Zune. I'm telling you, Cristiano, you're missing out on the best phone and MP3 player ever made. And I'm willing to prove it to you. I'll bet you a million euros that if you try them for a week, you'll never go back to your Apple products. What do you say? Are you man enough to take the challenge? Or are you too scared to face the truth? Come on, Cristiano, don't be a coward. Don't be a fool. Don't be a loser. Be a winner. Be a legend. Be a Windows Phone and Zune user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mcgregor-ronaldo-zune-windows-phone-meme</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/mcgregor-ronaldo-zune-windows-phone-meme</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-23 20:23 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>windowsphone</category>
      <category>zune</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>copilot</category>
      <category>meme</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Microblogging" prior art</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Just published a blog post, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/ai-1999-1899"&gt;AI like it's 1999 or 1899&lt;/a&gt;, inspired by this post from jwz, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/111/583/682/973/573/497/original/1d93c25bbdc52784.png" class="img-fluid" alt="A meme of a telegram saying F**k You Strong Letter to Follow" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/microblogging-telegram-jwz</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/microblogging-telegram-jwz</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-12-15 11:18 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>microblogging</category>
      <category>telegram</category>
      <category>meme</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>