<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - open-source</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/open-source</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'open-source' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2021-08-10 18:00:00 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting made easy with YunoHost</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

Over the past few months I've started self-hosting a few of the services I use. Among those are a Matrix chat server and Mastodon instance. It may be of special interest to call out, many of these services are hosted on a Raspberry Pi 4, which not only speaks to the capabilities of the device but also shows opportunities for individuals to take control over the services they use and their data. Self-hosting however isn't the easiest thing to get started with. Mainly because each service has their own setup requirements. Technically you could use something like Docker to standardize the process, but that has its own complexities. In particular, there was a recent experience where I had trouble setting up a service which I got up and running in no time using YunoHost. YunoHost describes itself as "...a libre operating system aiming to simplify server administration and democratize self-hosting.". In this post, I'll describe my experience with it and why you might consider it for your self-hosting project.

![Image of server racks by Taylor Vick (Unsplash @tvick)](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/128647305-c30ef44e-901d-4bf1-8e9d-af2449d5fd1d.png)

## Why Self-Host?

First off, why even go through the trouble of self-hosting? Service providers nowadays have made it so easy to use their services, self-hosting seems like a lot of work. However, there are several reasons why you might consider self-hosting the applications and services you use. A few that I find interesting include:

1. Explore "new" technologies
2. Own your data
3. Learn something new

### Explore "new" technologies

The saying goes "there's nothing new under the sun". However as with all things, people have found alternative uses and solutions to existing technologies. For example, in simple terms, the [Fediverse](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fediverse) can be summarized as E-mail + RSS. It consists of a common decentralized protocol to handle communication between individuals who may not use the same server while providing "follow" capabilities for services like micro-blogging, photos, and video sharing. Though the Fediverse has been around for some time, it's still relatively new. Whether it's a new technology or new to you, self-hosting can help you learn more about technologies like the Fediverse.

### Own your data

Part of accepting terms of service agreements is sometimes giving up some ownership of your personal data. Although you hope the company and service provider is responsible with your data, you can't always be 100% sure. With self-hosting, you're fully in control of your data and in most cases don't rely on third parties. As a result, your data is as private and secure as you want it to. From a security standpoint though, I'll note that in many cases, service providers have dedicated security teams whose main job is to keep your data secure. Therefore chances are that your data is usually secure when hosted by service providers. In any case, if you want to have complete control and ownership of your data, self-hosting might be for you.

### Learn something new

Over the past few months, I've learned a few things that I don't usually deal with on my day-to-day like DNS records, Nginx, Systemd, certificates, and a few others. Self-hosting these services usually involves setting up several components some of which you may already be familiar with while others may be new to you. Self-hosting gives you the opportunity to learn new skills and as mentioned previously work with new technologies.

## Self-hosting with YunoHost

Recently I was trying to set up an instance of [Pixelfed](https://pixelfed.org/), which describes itself as "A free and ethical photo sharing platform". You can think of it as a self-hosted Instagram. The application is built with PHP and a few other components I'm not very familiar with. I spent about a week trying to configure my Raspberry Pi to successfully run these services. Unfortunately, I had no luck. I had heard about YunoHost previously but had never tried it. Essentially they offer a way to simplify self-hosting. I noticed YunoHost provided a way to self-host Pixelfed. All I had to do was:

1. [Install YunoHost](https://yunohost.org/en/install). In my case, I installed it on a Linode VM (the smallest one) running Debian 10, but you have options including a Raspberry Pi.
2. [Install Pixelfed](https://github.com/YunoHost-Apps/pixelfed_ynh). YunoHost has a variety of [applications](https://yunohost.org/en/apps) with pre-configured scripts that make it easy to install applications like Pixelfed.

The entire process took about one hour. Some parts I skipped mentioning were getting a domain name and configuring DNS records, but aside from that, getting started with YunoHost was incredibly simple. If you're looking to self-host but don't want to spend too much time configuring your server and each of the services you host on it, give YunoHost a try.
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/yunohost-self-hosting-simplified</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/yunohost-self-hosting-simplified</guid>
      <pubDate>2021-08-10 18:00:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>open-source</category>
      <category>self-hosting</category>
      <category>raspberry-pi</category>
      <category>matrix</category>
      <category>pixelfed</category>
      <category>mastodon</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Duo offline navigation hiking setup</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

Over the past few months, I've been going on a hike almost every weekend. Not only does hiking provide an opportunity to discover the natural wonders all around you, it's also good exercise and free (if you don't count entry fees for some state and national parks). Throughout these trips, the [Surface Duo](https://www.microsoft.com/surface/devices/surface-duo), Microsoft's dual-screen Android phone has been a reliable companion. Although it's not the smallest or most rugged device, its large screen(s) paired with OSMAnd~ and AllTrails make it easy to navigate while on the trail. In this post, I'll detail my navigation setup.

![Picture of half-dome taken from Four Mile Trail](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/127246913-58472929-f067-41f0-9011-17193f863f71.JPG)

## Getting trail routes from AllTrails

Although trails are often well marked, it's always a good idea to have a map of the trail and surrounding area. This is especially true if it's your first time there. I almost exclusively get my trail maps from [AllTrails](https://www.alltrails.com/). If you're not familiar with AllTrails, it's a platform and community where members share maps, reviews, and information about trails for all kinds of outdoor activities. The site is completely free and while you can pay for premium features, the free offering provides you with all the essentials you'd need to plan your trip.

Trail information, maps, and reviews are entirely user supported. One of the (free) features is the ability to download trails to a variety of formats.

![AllTrails Download Route](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/127243740-5ef2e2e3-4c9c-4dbc-a8c5-be608fafeea5.png)

Typically, the format I'll download routes to is GPX Route and GPX Track. [GPX](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPS_Exchange_Format) is an XML schema for representing GPS data in software applications. Because GPX is a standard format, you can open and view these files in any app that supports them.

## Offline navigation with OSMAnd~

AllTrails has a mobile app. However, for offline navigation, I use the [OSMAnd~](https://f-droid.org/en/packages/net.osmand.plus/) Android app which I downloaded from [F-Droid](https://f-droid.org/). It's also available in the Google Play Store and Apple App Store.

OSMAnd~ is a free map and navigation app supported by [OpenStreetMaps](https://www.openstreetmap.org/). OpenStreetMaps, like AllTrails is free and entirely community driven. OSMAnd~ lets you download **detailed** maps for offline use. Detailed is the key here. Although you can save maps for offline use with applications like Here Maps and Google Maps, they often limit the size of the area you can save for offline use and don't provide much detail. With OSMAnd~ you can:

- Download entire state and country maps for offline use.
- View details like contour-lines, hill shading, and other trail details.
- Turn-by-turn navigation.
- View and edit GPX files

Using the GPX files I get from AllTrails, I load them onto my Surface Duo and view them using OSMAnd~. Using offline maps and the Duo's GPS I'm able to see my position on the trail and quickly find my way when I've gone off it even if I have no reception. This combination makes for a navigation device and experience like no other because I have the full screen real estate that the Duo provides to view areas beyond the trail.

![OSMAnd Android App Displaying Track](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/127246186-6b5f02ec-7fef-4f2e-909b-8a54615dc790.png)

## Conclusion

By leveraging the power of crowd-sourcing and open-source, access to quality information has never been easier. When this information is displayed on a device like the Surface Duo it makes it easy to navigate when you're out on the trail especially in situations when you have no reception and you're not familiar with your surroundings.

If you've been looking for an offline navigation solutions, hopefully this post helps provide some guidance. If you do any outdoor activities especially in remote areas, even if you don't have a Duo, I'd suggest giving AllTrails and OSMAnd~ a try. See you on the trail!

P.S. Over the past month, I've transitioned to the Garmin Fenix 6X Pro for navigation. It's a smaller device that supports loading GPX files and provides offline maps with turn-by-turn navigation. I'm also not worried about dropping or scratching it because it's designed for the outdoors. This in no way takes away with how amazing the OSMAnd~ and Surface Duo pairing are for offline navigation. In fact, I still use the Duo for backup navigation when it's difficult to see the map on the Fenix.

]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/surface-duo-offline-navigation-hiking-setup</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/surface-duo-offline-navigation-hiking-setup</guid>
      <pubDate>2021-07-27 19:00:00 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>hiking</category>
      <category>openstreetmaps</category>
      <category>open-source</category>
      <category>surface</category>
      <category>lifestyle</category>
      <category>apps</category>
      <category>fdroid</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives to WhatsApp</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
## Introduction

Recently I've heard a lot of buzz around people moving away from the WhatsApp messaging app. I'm not tuned into all the details as to why there's been a mass exodus, but from what I understand it has to do with its privacy policies. I've seen many people including Elon Musk recommend Signal. Signal is a great alternative but there are a few others that are worth considering. This recommendation was originally planned as a tweet, but there's so many details that just can't be captured in a tweet or thread so instead I turned it into a blog post. If you haven't made the switch or if you're still not completely committed to the platform you've switched to, this post is for you.

![Phone and notebook - Oscar Mucyo Unsplash](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/104107289-08689180-5289-11eb-890d-54527902df97.png)

## Matrix

![Element web client screenshot](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/104107320-3e0d7a80-5289-11eb-9449-71e34315b96e.png)

[Matrix](https://matrix.org/) is my go-to messaging platform. Matrix is an open-source project that provides an open standard for real-time communication. Built on top of this standard are several implementations with [Synapse](https://github.com/matrix-org/synapse) being the most popular server and [Element](https://element.io/) being the most popular client.

Matrix is relatively new. However, it has a lot of potential and there are a lot of exciting things happening around it. Some of the most notable include:

- [Mozilla selected Matrix](https://matrix.org/blog/2019/12/19/welcoming-mozilla-to-matrix) to be the successor to its IRC communications.
- Matrix recently [acquired Gitter](https://matrix.org/blog/2020/09/30/welcoming-gitter-to-matrix), a popular chat platform for software projects, and has quickly worked to [integrate Gitter with Matrix](https://matrix.org/blog/2020/12/07/gitter-now-speaks-matrix) allowing for it to take advantage of many of the features provided by the protocol. 
- [Matrix will power FOSDEM 2021](https://matrix.org/blog/2021/01/04/taking-fosdem-online-via-matrix) communications.
- [Matrix is experimenting with P2P architectures](https://matrix.org/blog/2020/06/02/introducing-p-2-p-matrix) to help users have full control over their communications.

Although Matrix provides several features commonly associated with messaging platforms such as 1:1 messaging, video/audio calls, and group chat, there are a few features worth highlighting:

- End-to-end encryption
- Interoperability with other communication platforms
- Decentralization

### End-to-end encryption

End-to-end encryption makes sure your communications stay private. Only you and the intended recipients of the message are able to see the messages. 

### Interoperability

One of the biggest challenges of moving over to a new platform is that your friends and family don't or won't join you, making it a lonely place. Matrix provides interoperability with other communication platforms and protocols through [bridges](https://matrix.org/bridges/). Bridges facilitate the exchange of messages with other platforms without requiring all participants to be on Matrix. The core team maintains bridges for Slack, IRC, XMPP, and Gitter. There are also community maintained bridges for WhatsApp, Discord, Facebook Messenger, Signal, and many others. 

### Decentralization 

Decentralization means that there's no central authority that holds control over the platform or data. Matrix is decentralized through federation. One of the most common examples of federation is e-mail. I may have an AOL e-mail address and you may have a Hotmail e-mail address, yet we're still able to exchange messages. With Matrix, in a similar way, users and groups don't have to have their accounts on the same server in order to communicate. It also means that users have a choice over [which server they join](https://www.hello-matrix.net/public_servers.php). If I don't agree with the conversations or moderation of a particular server, I have the choice to open an account on another server without leaving Matrix altogether. Even better, because Matrix is built using open technologies, I have the option of hosting my own server.

To get started with Matrix, visit the [Element](https://element.io/get-started) website and create an account.

## Jami

![Jami Screenshot](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11130940/104107348-64331a80-5289-11eb-8606-944269e17d10.png)

Another project that I like but haven't used it to the same extent as Matrix is [Jami](https://jami.net/). Jami is an open-source project for real-time communication. Similar to Matrix, Jami is cross-platform, free (as in freedom and beer), end-to-end encrypted, and decentralized. Jami achieves decentralization by using P2P protocols. This means that the data is stored on your device so you're in full control of your data. Jami also doesn't require the internet to work. As long as you're in the same local network as your peers, you're able to communicate. 

To get started with Jami, [download the app](https://jami.net/download/) and create an account.

## Conclusion

In this post, I've mentioned some communication platforms that I consider great alternatives to WhatsApp. Regardless of the platform you choose, some things that I believe should be top of mind are security and privacy. It's important that you own your data and you have control over who has access to it and what they do with it. Feel free say hi on Matrix [@lqdev:lqdev.tech](https://matrix.to/#/@lqdev:lqdev.tech) or Jami where you can find me as lqdev1.]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/alternatives-to-whatsapp</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/alternatives-to-whatsapp</guid>
      <pubDate>2021-01-09 13:44:27 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>privacy</category>
      <category>self-hosted</category>
      <category>security</category>
      <category>open-source</category>
      <category>apps</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>