<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - workflow</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/workflow</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'workflow' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-07-28 16:53 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Nyxt Emacs Hacks</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;p&gt;Saving this guide for future reference as I set up my elfeed / Nyxt capture workflows for the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional articles that might be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ag91.github.io/blog/2021/07/09/org-capture-in-nyxt-taking-notes-while-browsing/"&gt;Org capture in Nyxt: Taking Notes While Browsing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/nyxt-emacs-hacks</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/nyxt-emacs-hacks</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-28 16:53 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>nyxt</category>
      <category>emacs</category>
      <category>orgmode</category>
      <category>capture</category>
      <category>templates</category>
      <category>workflow</category>
      <category>lisp</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I need to optimize my response publishing workflow</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I like to use my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed/responses"&gt;response feed&lt;/a&gt; to bookmark and reshare interesting content I find online. Typically my workflow looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-mermaid"&gt;flowchart TD
  A[&amp;quot;Scroll through feed reader&amp;quot;] --&amp;gt; B[&amp;quot;Open articles I want to read in a new tab&amp;quot;]
  B --&amp;gt; C[&amp;quot;Read articles&amp;quot;]
  C --&amp;gt; D[&amp;quot;Create a response file to publish on my website&amp;quot;]
  D --&amp;gt; E[&amp;quot;Capture interesting information from the article in the response file&amp;quot;]
  E --&amp;gt; F[&amp;quot;Publish the response&amp;quot;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottleneck I usually find is in the middle steps of creating a response file and capturing the relevant content. This usually happens as I'm reading the article. For a single file, it's not a big deal. Doing it for several can be time consuming, especially with the &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/subscribed-to-1042-feeds-newsblur"&gt;number of feeds I subscribe to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a few things I think could help here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create one response file and do a daily link dump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a browser extension or system where I can:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight text or content on a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right-click or use a keyboard shortcut to create an entry for the content I highlighted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an entry in a database somewhere which captures the URL of the page I'm looking at.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enter a few more details like the file name I want to use and response type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I'm done with my session, I can publish. This will use the database content to compose the content for my response and create a PR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option is simple but I don't like it because although most of the content I come across is tech related, I prefer having individual articles I can link to with their own tags to make it easier to build relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second option sounds complex, but it's basically a web highlighting tool. I know there's a few out there already so maybe worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd prefer to build my own to tailor it specifically to what I want just like my website generator. However, it would mean that I'd have to spend some time thinking about how to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'd be a fun project though. Maybe worthwhile experimenting with building an AI agent to help me use the content I captured to nicely format the response.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/simplifying-feed-publishing-workflow</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/simplifying-feed-publishing-workflow</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-17 20:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>workflow</category>
      <category>publishing</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>personalknowledgemanagement</category>
      <category>pkm</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>