<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - interoperability</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/interoperability</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'interoperability' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-02-06 20:03 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s how WhatsApp plans to interoperate with other messaging apps</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp, like many other major tech platforms, will have to make some significant changes to comply with the European Union’s Digital Markets Act (DMA). One of those changes is interoperability with other messaging platforms...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift toward interoperability will first include text messages, images, voice messages, videos, and files sent from one person to another. In theory, this would allow users to chat with people on WhatsApp through third-party apps, like iMessage, Telegram, Google Messages, and Signal, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted by Wired, WhatsApp wants the messaging services it connects with to use the same Signal Protocol to encrypt messages. Meta is also open to apps using alternate encryption protocols so long as companies can prove “they reach the security standards that WhatsApp outlines in its guidance.” The third-party services will also have to sign a contract with Meta before they plug into WhatsApp, with more details about the agreement coming in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-whatsapp-plans-interoperate-other-messaging-services</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-whatsapp-plans-interoperate-other-messaging-services</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-06 20:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>whatsapp</category>
      <category>messaging</category>
      <category>interoperability</category>
      <category>signal</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cory Doctorow: Interoperability Can Save the Open Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his new book &lt;a href="https://www.versobooks.com/products/3035-the-internet-con"&gt;The Internet Con: How to Seize the Means of Computation&lt;/a&gt;, author &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/about/staff/cory-doctorow"&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt; presents a strong case for disrupting Big Tech. While the dominance of Internet platforms like Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, or Amazon is often taken for granted, Doctorow argues that these walled gardens are fenced in by legal structures, not feats of engineering. Doctorow proposes forcing interoperability—any given platform’s ability to interact with another—as a way to break down those walls and to make the Internet freer and more democratic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/interoperability-can-save-open-web-doctorow</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/interoperability-can-save-open-web-doctorow</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-06 00:09 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>interoperability</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>