<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - tv</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/tv</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'tv' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-08-19 21:47 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Pain and sorrow on repeat</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I've had this song on repeat since&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/new-flying-lotus-garmonbozia"&gt;Friday&lt;/a&gt;. Also, I didn't know the name of the song is a &lt;a href="https://twinpeaks.fandom.com/wiki/Garmonbozia"&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/a&gt; reference. Given his recent focus as a composer, I hope this means there's a bigger Twin Peaks project or collaboration in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CfB0Uqd2aRE" title="Garmonbozia by Flying Lotus visualizer video thumbnail"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/CfB0Uqd2aRE/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Garmonbozia by Flying Lotus visualizer video thumbnail" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/pain-and-sorrow-on-repeat</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/pain-and-sorrow-on-repeat</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-19 21:47 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>flyinglotus</category>
      <category>twinpeaks</category>
      <category>davidlynch</category>
      <category>flylo</category>
      <category>tv</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘PBS Retro’ is coming to Roku as a FAST channel</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PBS is making child edutainment classics like Zoboomafoo, Mister Rogers’ Neighborhood, and Reading Rainbow available for free on a new ‘PBS Retro’ channel on Roku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is cool! Although I'm kind of bummed the stuff I grew up watching is now considered &amp;quot;retro&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/pbs-retro-roku-channel</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/pbs-retro-roku-channel</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-04-25 23:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>pbs</category>
      <category>roku</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>fast</category>
      <category>retro</category>
      <category>education</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tubi’s new redesign wants to push you down the rabbit hole</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tubi says its new ‘turple’-forward brand identity is all about encouraging viewers to fall down rabbit holes to find exciting shows and movies to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've often found &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds"&gt;good content to watch on Tubi&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, they're not the latest blockbusters but there are decades worth of movies out there. Just like today, not all movies that come out are good but there's still tons of great content. Sometimes, there's even &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/responses/dread-central-overlook-motel"&gt;overlooked gems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tubi-redesign-down-the-rabbit-hole</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/tubi-redesign-down-the-rabbit-hole</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-28 21:51 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>movies</category>
      <category>tubi</category>
      <category>streaming</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My streaming fatigue got so bad I started collecting DVDs</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending years reassuring myself that I don’t need physical copies of movies because of streaming, DVDs have officially reentered my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walmart...Thrift stores, flea markets, the library, and even my local mall’s FYE have also become places I frequent to get my hands on oft-ignored discs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense to subscribe to all these services if you’re into the exclusive content on each one and have the patience to sift through their massive libraries. However, all I’ve been watching lately is the junk on Discovery Plus, simply because I’m too tired to find anything else — especially when the extremely specific shows and movies I want to watch keep switching services or just aren’t available. One of the most devastating examples of this was when both The Office and Parks and Recreation moved from Netflix to Peacock, disrupting the casual binge-watching sessions that I would default to when I was done with work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the past year, nearly every streaming service has raised its prices, including Netflix, Disney Plus, Hulu, Paramount Plus, Discovery Plus, and Apple TV Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying DVDs are flawless: there’s a reason no one wants them anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, it’s still nice to have something that you physically own and don’t even need an internet connection to use. So when Best Buy confirmed it would stop selling DVDs this year and rumors emerged that Walmart would do the same, I was pretty disappointed. I can’t imagine Walmart without its bin of DVDs, nor can I even see Best Buy without its already-shrunken selection of movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2024, and I’m not ready to say goodbye to DVDs — in fact, I’m just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article from Emma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I've been doing the same. Just a few weekends ago, I got something like 8-10 DVDs for ~$25 at my local thrift store. That haul included 3 seasons of The Sopranos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With streaming services taking back control of their content and putting it on their own platforms, I don't want to have to keep signing up for a new service just to watch the shows and movies I enjoy. Also, that's assuming you can find the content to begin with (i.e. Westworld).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parks and Recreation, The Office, and Breaking Bad were some of the first shows I started collecting and have slowly been building up my collection. To save on space, I've ditched the cases and have the DVDs organized in a CD case. I've not only limited myself to DVDs but have also started collecting CDs as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I want variety, I just use one of the free streaming services like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justwatch.com/us/provider/freevee"&gt;Freevee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pluto.tv/"&gt;Pluto TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://tubitv.com/"&gt;Tubi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are ads but at least I'm not paying for it and I know that's part of the deal. There are a ton of good older (and sometimes original) TV shows and movies on those platforms to keep me entertained. The most recent ones being Stargate and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/vampires-kiss-movie"&gt;Vampire's Kiss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/streaming-fatigue-collecting-dvds</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-26 15:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>streaming</category>
      <category>media</category>
      <category>dvds</category>
      <category>movies</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>physicalmedia</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The direct influence of Twin Peaks on Zelda</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 2010 interview, Link’s Awakening director Takashi Tezuka revealed the inspiration for this memorably bizarre cast of characters. “At the time, Twin Peaks was rather popular. The drama was all about a small number of characters in a small town,” Tezuka said. “So I wanted to make something like that, while it would be small enough in scope to easily understand, it would have deep and distinctive characteristics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... [Mark] Frost reveals in an interview with The Verge, he actually spoke with Nintendo about the Zelda franchise. “I don’t want to overstate it. It was a single conversation. But it was fun,” he tells me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They were talking to me about a Twin Peaks game, and they mentioned Zelda at the time,” says Frost. “They said, ‘One of the things we love about your show is how there’s all sorts of sideways associations that can drive the story forward.’ They asked me about that as they were thinking about expanding the Zelda universe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though he’d never played a Zelda game, Frost had enough experience with fantasy storytelling that he had some suggestions. “I’d played lots of Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons when I was young, so I was familiar with the kind of story they were thinking about,” he says. “I think I said, ‘Don’t be afraid to use dreamlike, Jungian symbolism. Things can connect thematically without having to connect concretely.’ It was things like that that I was urging them [to consider].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/direct-influence-twin-peaks-zelda</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/direct-influence-twin-peaks-zelda</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-02-24 12:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>twinpeaks</category>
      <category>nintendo</category>
      <category>zelda</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>culture</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Laundry on Campus Without a Phone</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;This article reminds me of this gem 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mzb355qT8RI" title="Dennis Orders a Boba Tea - Scene | It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia | FX"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/mzb355qT8RI/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Dennis Orders a Boba Tea - Scene | It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia | FX" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/doing-laundry-without-phone</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/doing-laundry-without-phone</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-09-02 18:45 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>tv</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archive 81 - so far so good!</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;About 2 episodes into the show &lt;a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80222802"&gt;Archive 81&lt;/a&gt; on Netflix and so far so good. I listened to a few episodes of the &lt;a href="https://www.archive81.com/"&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; (by the same name) it's based on a few years ago. Now it makes me want to go back and listen to it again. It also makes me think about what the &lt;a href="https://theblacktapespodcast.com/"&gt;Black Tapes&lt;/a&gt; could've been had it gotten a TV or movie adaptation. If you're into the found footage, cult horror type of stories (think Blair Witch + Midsommar + Rosemary's Baby), definitely check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/archive-81-black-tapes</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/archive-81-black-tapes</guid>
      <pubDate>01/15/2022 21:01 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>tv</category>
      <category>archive81</category>
      <category>netflix</category>
      <category>horror</category>
      <category>suspense</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>