<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - elixir</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/elixir</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'elixir' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-01-17 20:40 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>How Discord Serves 15-Million Users on One Server</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early summer 2022, the Discord operations team noticed unusually high activity on their dashboards. They thought it was a bot attack, but it was legitimate traffic from MidJourney - a new, fast-growing community for generating AI images from text prompts.
&lt;br&gt;
To use MidJourney, you need a Discord account. Most MidJourney users join one main Discord server. This server grew so quickly that it soon hit Discord’s old limit of around 1 million users per server.
&lt;br&gt;
This is the story of how the Discord team creatively solved this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord’s real-time messaging backend is built with Elixir. Elixir runs on the BEAM virtual machine. BEAM was created for Erlang - a language optimized for large real-time systems requiring rock-solid reliability and uptime.
&lt;br&gt;
A key capability BEAM provides is extremely lightweight parallel processes. This enables a single server to efficiently run tens or hundreds of thousands of processes concurrently.
&lt;br&gt;
Elixir brings friendlier, Ruby-inspired syntax to the battle-tested foundation of BEAM. Combined they make it much easier to program massively scalable, fault-tolerant systems.
&lt;br&gt;
So by leveraging BEAM's lightweight processes, the Elixir code powering Discord can &amp;quot;fan out&amp;quot; messages to hundreds of thousands of users around the world concurrently. However, limits emerge as communities grow larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-discord-serves-15-million-users-using-one-server</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/how-discord-serves-15-million-users-using-one-server</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-01-17 20:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>beam</category>
      <category>erlang</category>
      <category>elixir</category>
      <category>discord</category>
      <category>scale</category>
      <category>enterprise</category>
      <category>chat</category>
      <category>communities</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>