<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - history</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/history</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'history' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-05-09 20:54 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Blogging</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...around 1997, when Jorn Barger launched his website, titling it “The Robot Wisdom Weblog.” Barger’s plan was to curate his favorite links from around the web, and add bits of commentary to each one. In other words, he meant to keep a log of his web experience. Hence weblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their earliest days, webloggers stood as gatekeepers to the web’s ever-growing well of content. Each day, these URL pioneers would post a few new links and sprinkle in their own commentary. Blogs acted as a signpost for web users, and following a few key blogs was enough to keep track of just about everything new on the web. Many began to look at the blogging community as a brand new type of media, one that often stood far closer to an impartial truth than traditional mediums would allow for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1999, Peter Merholz threw up his own weblog, and in the sidebar added the tagline: &amp;quot;I’ve decided to pronounce the word “weblog” as wee’- blog. Or “blog” for short.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, most bloggers hand coded their sites, adding a new HTML page to their server each time they had a new entry, or just updating the homepage to include the newest links. But soon enough, tools showed up to help bloggers with the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...on the fringes, a new type of blog was emerging. The personal blog. These sites ditched the curated links and focused exclusively on commentary. Bloggers used their site to chronicle their personal journey, from the almost boring and banal to the weird and wonderful. This new type of blog was less an alternative media source and more akin to an online journal or diary. And these writers saw themselves not as gatekeepers to the web, but as sharers of their own identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New tools soon caught up with this shifting perspective. The first of the bunch to do so was LiveJournal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogger came next. And it would prove to be the most popular of the early blogging tools. The platform first launched in August of 1999, but picked up steam the following year when it introduced the concept of a permalink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These platforms made blogging open, in every sense of the word. Visitors were greeted with a single, open textarea on a free platform that was open to all to participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogger became the platform choice for a lot of writers out there. It certainly was for Mena Trott&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trott had the feeling that platforms like Blogger did not go nearly far enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trott wanted her own site to stand out from the crowd. To be quintessentially hers. Blogger wouldn’t let her do that. So together with her husband, a Perl programmer, she built Movable Type...And with that move, Trott ushered in a third generation of blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movable Type allowed users to set up their blog on their own server, and have complete control over its look and feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog (the noun and verb) became a word familiar not just to web geeks, but to everyone. Lots of imitators and innovators followed in the wake of Moveable Type. Open source platforms like WordPress rose to meet the rising demand. But for a long time, Moveable Type was the standard. It fed its community with a constant stream of new features that promoted openness and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging, as a community and a practice, continues to be refined to this day thanks to the dedication of web users everywhere. But its sharpest point was made the day Mena Trott decided that &lt;strong&gt;a blog could be more than just some text on a page. It could be one of a kind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/evolution-of-blogging-history-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/evolution-of-blogging-history-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 20:54 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>history</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI abundance after scarcity cycles</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;While writing the post &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/rss-community-calendars-new-events"&gt;RSS for new event notifications&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned how the flow of getting new event notifications through RSS might work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new event is added to the calendar, the RSS feed can be updated. The &lt;code&gt;channel&lt;/code&gt;property has the link to the shared calendar you can subscribe to and the individual events have &lt;em&gt;.ics&lt;/em&gt; files embedded in the &lt;code&gt;enclosure&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually didn't know if that was possible until I looked at the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS_enclosure"&gt;RSS enclosure syntax&lt;/a&gt;. Based on that page, as long as you provide the URL to the &lt;em&gt;.ics&lt;/em&gt; file, length of the file, and the MIME type (text/calendar), you can link to your events inside enclosures. So it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not the point of this post though. When I was looking at the references, I came across this post talking about the &lt;a href="https://www.rssboard.org/rss-enclosures-use-case"&gt;use case for RSS enclosures&lt;/a&gt;. I don't know when this post was published but given the problems mentioned with accessing high quality video, I assume it was in the days when the internet was on dial-up or DSL speeds. At that time, downloading webpages or e-mail was slow. Forget about downloading multimedia. As that post mentions, with enclosures, you could schedule your RSS client to download content like videos during off-peak hours so any content you'd want to access would download overnight and be available to you in the morning. About 30 years later, in many places, even with a connection that has 1MB download speeds, downloading a podcast that's 100MB or a video that's 2GB is relatively fast. It might take a while, but compared to 30 years ago, it's &amp;quot;instant&amp;quot;. So at this point, it's not really technical challenge as much as it is an access challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low bandwith speeds forced people to get creative in how they utilized their resources. The internet was not the only time this happened. About 30 years ago or so when cell phones were just becoming mainstream they too suffered from scarcity. Cell phones and plans were very expensive. You had limited minutes and when SMS became a thing, those too were limited. If you wanted to have hour long conversations with friends and loved ones, you'd have to wait until off-peak hours so you could use your &amp;quot;free&amp;quot; minutes. Fast-forward 30 years later, cell phones and cell phone plans are relatively affordable. When you purchase these plans, you get access to unlimited minutes, messages, and data. So again, the technical limitations aren't as prevalent. It's mainly a matter of access and whether your cell phone provider offers good coverage in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings me to my point. We're seeing this cycle again with AI. Large Language Models today are expensive to run and I'm not overindexing on the financial perspective. You pay per call, access to these models can be throttled at times, there's only so many GPUs you can get access to in a data center to run them, you pay the latency penalty by going through the network as well as the cost of inferencing, and you also have token limits. About a year into the release of ChatGPT, access to these models has been expanded, the models have gotten more capable (&lt;a href="https://openai.com/research/gpt-4v-system-card"&gt;GPT-4V&lt;/a&gt; and GPT4 with 128k tokens), it's become &lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/new-models-and-developer-products-announced-at-devday"&gt;cheaper to run these models&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/onq/2023/10/rethink-whats-possible-with-new-snapdragon-x-elite-platform"&gt;computing is becoming more efficient&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://ai.meta.com/llama/#inside-the-model"&gt;smaller &amp;quot;open-source&amp;quot; models&lt;/a&gt; are becoming more capable. Today, we have to be creative with how we utilize our resources, but we're only a year in. If we extrapolate how these cycles play out though, in 30 years we'll forget how challenging it was to use and access early AI technologies and AI will become more abundant like the internet, cell phones, and other technologies before it.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/ai-abundance-scarcity-cycle-repeats-rss-enclosure-use-case</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/ai-abundance-scarcity-cycle-repeats-rss-enclosure-use-case</guid>
      <pubDate>2023-11-12 10:37 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>history</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>openai</category>
      <category>llm</category>
      <category>gpt</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Radio History (U.S)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;While browsing the interwebs, I ran into the site &lt;a href="https://earlyradiohistory.us/"&gt;United States Early Radio History&lt;/a&gt; which contains events spanning different time periods. As an operator it's fascinating to learn about the history and see how radio continues to play a large role in our day-to-day.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/early-radio-history-us</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/early-radio-history-us</guid>
      <pubDate>10/29/2021 02:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>radio</category>
      <category>communication</category>
      <category>hamradion</category>
      <category>history</category>
      <category>unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coffee with a Codex</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Came accross this event series via &lt;a href="https://boffosocko.com/type/status/"&gt;Chris Aldrich's microblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's Chris' original post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Monday, I sit down with a cup of coffee and learn something interesting about history through old manuscripts. Join our friends Dot Porter (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/leoba"&gt;@leoba&lt;/a&gt;) and the Schoenberg Institute for Manuscript Studies (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sims_mss"&gt;@sims_mss&lt;/a&gt;) at &lt;a href="https://schoenberginstitute.org/coffee-with-a-codex/"&gt;Coffee with a Codex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically it's a virtual meeting where experts go over manuscripts on a variety of topics. I'll probably check out next week's event.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/coffee-with-codex</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/coffee-with-codex</guid>
      <pubDate>10/19/2021 10:21 AM -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>event</category>
      <category>learning</category>
      <category>history</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>