<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - openweb</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/openweb</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'openweb' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-06-14 10:57 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Local Artist Websites</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I saw these really cool murals around the neighborhood. The artists signed their work either with their name or Instagram handle. I don't use Instagram, so it was nice to see that some of them also had websites where I could follow their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.shawnimals.com/"&gt;Shawnimals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cydsmillie.com/"&gt;Cyd Smillie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/local-mural-artist-websites</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/local-mural-artist-websites</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-14 10:57 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>art</category>
      <category>website</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faircamp - A static site generator for audio producers</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;p&gt;This is such a cool project. Looks like it's super simple to get started with and it's packed with a ton of features so creators get to stay in their flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like how creators are showcased.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/faircamp-static-site-audio-producers</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/faircamp-static-site-audio-producers</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-05 20:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>faircamp</category>
      <category>music</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>staticsite</category>
      <category>technology</category>
      <category>tools</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FediForum Day One Recap</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
Just wrapped up a successful first day of FediForum.

The vibes and energy were high. Tons of great conversations and projects around the social web.

A few emerging themes I noticed:

- Identity
- Portability / Interoperability
- Feeds
- Commerce

Ian Forrester kicked us off with his Public Service &amp; The Fediverse keynote [(Slides)](https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HuQF_sI19zwByM793uvdl7BECneRmni_H9uOG-oFkdM/edit?slide=id.g420c517061_0_0#slide=id.g420c517061_0_0). 

One of the ideas that struck a chord of public service integrated into the fediverse. More specifically the interest that sparked in me was that publishing and social shouldn't be two separate things. Following the POSSE principle from the IndieWeb. You publish on your own site and then it's syndicated elsewhere. 

This was interesting enough for me I even hosted a session on the topic, I think it was called Tightening the Loop between CMS and the Fediverse. It was my first unconference, so I appreciated the way the agenda was built. Announce your topic, see whether there's interest, put it on the agenda, chat with fellow participants. Super easy.

## Identity &amp; Portability

These are such a huge topic but for the purpose of this post, I'm lumping them together.

[https://bounce-migrate.appspot.com/](https://bounce.so) is one of the projects aiming to make portability easy. What's so interesting is they're making it easy to migrate across protocols. So if you're in one network like ATProto (Bluesky), migrating to the Fediverse should be relatively seamless with https://bounce.so. 

Some great discussions that emerged on the topic as well include:

- **Reputation** - How do you build a web of trust?
- **Compartmentalization and Deduplication** - A single identity or multiple identities? When "following" someone, which of their feeds takes priority?

## Feeds

Talk of feeds was everywhere. I made a note to myself throughout the conference.

&gt; It's amazing how big the feeds theme is. Feed ownership, customization, and sharing. All powered by open protocols.

- [Bonfire releases 1.0](https://bonfirenetworks.org/posts/bonfire_social_rc/) - Congrats to the Bonfire team on this milestone. I haven't tried Bonfire myself, but the Circles feature caught my attention. It made me reminiscent of Google+.
- [Surf.Social is now in beta](https://https://surf.social) - As an avid user and curator of RSS feeds, I'd heard about Surf before but hadn't really looked into it. The beta release was announced at the conference and I quickly was able to sign up and download it. Kudos to the team on this milestone and thanks for being so responsive to my request to join the beta. I did almost no waiting in the waitlist. Once I have a chance to try it out and get familiar with it, I'll share some thoughts.
- [Channels](https://home.channel.org/) from the folks at [Newsmast Foundation](https://www.newsmastfoundation.org/) looks like an interesting way to curate and customize feeds. 
[Bring Your Own Timeline Algorithm](https://huggingface.co/spaces/mozilla-ai/byota) leverages semantic search to help you seamlessly leverage the power of algorithmic feeds but doing so under your control. Cool use of AI. 

There were a few unconference sessions on the topic as well. 

## Commerce

It was great to see folks talking about enabling creators to earn a living on open platforms and the social web. 

I believe [Bandwagon.fm](https://bandwagon.fm/home) showed of an implementation of a payments and subscription system built on top of [Emmisary](https://emissary.dev/), a social web toolkit.

## Additional Resources

Here's a list of other links and projects I was exposed to during the conference.

- [FediForum Advisory Board and Organizers](https://fediforum.org/people/)
- [An Internet of Many Autonomous Communities](https://blog.rudyfraser.com/an-internet-of-many-autonomous-communities/)
- [FediMeteo - Weather updates in your Fediverse Timeline](https://fedimeteo.com/)
- [Public Interest Technology Group (PITG)](https://pitg.network/)
- [Coalition for Content Provenance and Authenticity (C2PA)](https://c2pa.org/)
- [A New Social](https://www.anew.social/)
- [WeDistribute FediForum Live Coverage](https://wedistribute.org/2025/06/fediforum-june-2025/)
- [BBC Human Values](https://bbc.github.io/humanvalues/)
- [The Indie Beat Radio](https://theindiebeat.fm/)
- [Tie Yourself to a Federated Mastodon](https://pluralistic.net/2024/11/02/ulysses-pact/#tie-yourself-to-a-federated-mast)
- [The No Network Effect](https://snarfed.org/2013-04-13_the-no-network-effect)

As always, Cory Doctorow was great way to close out the first day. I even learned a new term, tron-pilled. Which means as a creator of a platform, you're on the side of the users.  

Looking forward to tomorrow's sessions!]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/fediforum-day-1-jun-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/fediforum-day-1-jun-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-06-05 17:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediforum</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources List for the Personal Web</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is to help guide and help those who are in every stage of their web-building journey on the personal web. This list is not meant to overwhelm you, but rather give you options and find tools, graphics, utilities, codes, and everything in between to help get you creating more on the independent web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/resource-list-personal-web</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/resource-list-personal-web</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-30 13:32 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>32bitcafe</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>retro</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do I keep up with AI?</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
This question comes up a lot in conversations. The short answer? I don’t. There’s just too much happening, too fast, for anyone to stay on top of everything.

While I enjoy sharing links and recommendations, I realized that a blog post might be more helpful. It gives folks a single place they can bookmark, share, and come back to on their own time, rather than having to dig through message threads where things inevitably get lost.

That said, here are some sources I use to try and stay informed:

- **Newsletters** are great for curated content. They highlight the top stories and help filter through the noise.
- **Blogs** are often the primary sources behind those newsletters. They go deeper and often cover a broader set of topics that might not make it into curated roundups.
- **Podcasts** serve a similar role. In some cases, they provide curation like newsletters and deep dives like blogs in others. Best of all, you can tune in while on the go making it a hands-free activity.

For your convenience, if any of the sources (including podcasts) I list below have RSS feeds, I’ve included them in my [AI Starter Pack](/collections/starter-packs//ai), which you can [download and import into your favorite RSS reader](/collections/starter-packs//ai/index.opml) (as long as it supports OPML file imports).

If you have some sources to share, [send me an e-mail](/contact). I'd love to keep adding to this list! If they have a feed I can subscribe to, even better.

## Newsletters

- [AlphaSignal](https://alphasignal.ai/)
- [The Batch](https://www.deeplearning.ai/the-batch/)
- [Latent Space](https://www.latent.space/)
- [TLDR AI](https://tldr.tech/ai)

## Blogs

I pride myself on being able to track down an RSS feed on just about any website, even if it’s buried or not immediately visible. Unfortunately, I haven't found a feed URL for either OpenAI or Anthropic which is annoying. 

**OpenAI and Anthropic, if you could do everyone a favor and drop a link, that would be great.** 

UPDATE: Thanks to [@m2vh@mastodontech.de](https://toot.lqdev.tech/@m2vh@mastodontech.de) for sharing the OpenAI news feed. 

I know I could use one of those web-page-to-RSS converters, but I'd much rather have an official link directly from the source.

- [OpenAI](https://openai.com/news/)
- [Anthropic](https://www.anthropic.com/news)
- [Google AI Blog](https://blog.google/technology/ai/)
- [AWS Machine Learning Blog](https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/)
- [Microsoft Research](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/)
- [Google Research](https://research.google/blog/)
- [Simon Willison](https://simonwillison.net/)

## Podcasts

- [AI Daily Brief](https://www.podchaser.com/podcasts/the-ai-daily-brief-formerly-th-5260567)
- [TWIML AI Podcast](https://twimlai.com/)
- [Practical AI](https://changelog.com/practicalai)

## Subscribing to feeds

Now that I’ve got you here...

Let’s talk about the best way to access all these feeds. My preferred and recommended approach is using a feed reader.

When subscribing to content on the open web, feed readers are your secret weapon.

RSS might seem like it’s dead (it’s not—yet). In fact, it’s the reason you often hear the phrase, “Wherever you get your podcasts.” But RSS goes beyond podcasts. It’s widely supported by blogs, newsletters, and even social platforms like the Fediverse (Mastodon, PeerTube, etc.) and BlueSky. It’s also how I’m able to compile my [starter packs](/collections/starter-packs/). 

I've written more about RSS in [Rediscovering the RSS Protocol](/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom), but the short version is this: when you build on open standards like RSS and OPML, you’re building on freedom. Freedom to use the tools that work best for you. Freedom to own your experience. And freedom to support a healthier, more independent web.
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-i-keep-up-with-ai</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/how-i-keep-up-with-ai</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-27 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>starterpack</category>
      <category>newsletter</category>
      <category>blog</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>podcast</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The stage has been set for the growth of small social media</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month during Meta's antitrust trial, Mark Zuckerberg admitted that his company's focus has changed radically from where it began...[his] testimony implies that Facebook (Meta) may no longer be as much of an option if we actually want to talk to each other on line. But, neither are many of the other large social media sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...if companies allowed us to discover great new small blogs and small social media sites, many of us would decide to spend more time there. Then, companies would be less able to advertise to us on their own sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...we have been told by the mainstream media for well over a decade that small social media is dead. They say the same about small blogs, yet small blogs are actually more plentiful than ever, with over &lt;a href="https://firstsiteguide.com/blogging-stat"&gt;600 million blogs&lt;/a&gt; on the Internet and about 7 million new blog articles published each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to create your own forum, do yourself a favor. The way to protect yourself and your users is by &lt;strong&gt;running your social media site at a domain that you own and on a server that you control&lt;/strong&gt;, and don't agree to hand over any of your rights to anyone for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe large corporate-run social media sites are vulnerable in a way they have not been for twenty years. Their users have reached a state of extreme dissatisfaction with their &amp;quot;enshittified&amp;quot; platforms, and they are looking for something, anything, better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But each of you who are reading these words can help end this situation by creating your own small social media site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need to start your own small site is a domain name, a server that you can buy, rent, or set up on an old computer, perhaps social media software (see above), patience, a willingness to work, and ideas for ways of notifying potential users of the existence of your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run your new site as you and your users see fit, and make it far superior to Facebook, Twitter (X), Reddit, or any of the other major sites whose owners think you have no other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/stage-set-growth-small-social-media-cheapskate</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/stage-set-growth-small-social-media-cheapskate</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-26 18:14 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>See you at FediForum June 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Super excited to be attending &lt;a href="https://fediforum.org/"&gt;FediForum&lt;/a&gt; in a few weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/fediforum-ticket.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Screenshot of Fediforum ticket showing name and event title" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/attending-fediforum-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/attending-fediforum-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-16 19:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediforum</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>community</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme web surfing</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;This is what my browser looks like every time &lt;a href="https://shellsharks.com/"&gt;shellsharks&lt;/a&gt; drops one of their &lt;a href="https://shellsharks.com/scrolls/"&gt;scrolls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.lqdev.tech/files/images/too-many-browser-tabs.png" class="img-fluid" alt="A lot of open browser tabs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/too-many-browser-tabs-shellsharks</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/too-many-browser-tabs-shellsharks</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-10 18:31 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>surfing</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>blog</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discourse and the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we started working on a plugin that brings Discourse and the Fediverse closer together. Discourse communities are online spaces that facilitate open collaboration and communication. The Fediverse offers ways to expand the reach of Discourse communities and help them build bridges with people active in other spaces, all while keeping the conversation civil, meaningful and focused. This post will describe how the ActivityPub plugin works and how you can enable your Discourse community to connect with other communities or Fediverse users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/discourse-fediverse</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/discourse-fediverse</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 22:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>discourse</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>forum</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Links</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperlinks deserve more recognition in light of all the ways their value has been sidelined and denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, I present a link compilation in praise of links. It includes things I agree with entirely and things I don't, spanning from the 2020s to the early 2000s, to supply a tapestry of perspectives, context, and examples on the value and importance of links. Links may have their downsides, challenges, and vulnerabilities, but my hope is that this compilation will (re)invigorate your appreciation for linking as a technology and a social practice, all the better to understand what's at stake when links are discarded and devalued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/in-praise-of-links-osteophage</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/in-praise-of-links-osteophage</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 21:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>decentralization</category>
      <category>web</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>socialweb.network</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your gateway to decentralized social networking protocols, resources, and community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/socialweb-network</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/socialweb-network</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 20:49 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>social</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>decentralized</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fediverse House 2025 Roundup</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[star] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Walls, Just Vibes at SXSW’s Fediverse House&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fediverse House was SXSW’s first physical gathering dedicated entirely to the constellation of interoperable social platforms powered by protocols like ActivityPub and AT Protocol. (We know “Fediverse” isn’t quite accurate to describe the whole ecosystem; in this case, it was just a convenient, fun way to name the space.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t matter which platform you preferred or which protocol you were building on; everyone was focused on the singular goal of building a better internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the real power move for creators is ownership and control of their work and livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...identity portability is a radical shift, and...decentralization could lead to more humane social spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://dot-social.simplecast.com/"&gt;DotSocial Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://flipboard.video/c/fediverse.house/videos"&gt;Fediverse House PeerTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/fediverse-house-2025-roundup</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/fediverse-house-2025-roundup</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-05-09 20:36 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>conference</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a link blog</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;Great to see more people sharing knowledge and linking to others from their own websites / platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to follow simon's approach to creating a link blog, where I can share interesting links I find on the internet along with my own comments and thoughts about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...this is an excellent way to share knowledge while also keeping a personal record. It’s much better than simply saving something to Readwise to read later and leaving a few highlights or dull comments like &amp;quot;interesting.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/build-a-link-blog-xuanwo</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/build-a-link-blog-xuanwo</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-02-04 22:29 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>linkblog</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starter Packs with OPML and RSS</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[
One of the things I like about Bluesky is the [Starter Pack feature](https://bsky.social/about/blog/06-26-2024-starter-packs). 

In a gist, a Starter Pack is a collection of feeds. 

Bluesky users can:

- Create starter packs
- Share starter packs
- Subscribe to starter packs

Unfortunately, Starter Packs are limited to Bluesky. 

Or are they? 

As mentioned, starter packs are a collection of feeds that others can create, share, and subscribe to. 

[Bluesky supports RSS](/responses/bluesky-rss-support/), which means you could organize the feeds using an OPML file that you can share with others and others can subscribe to. The benefits of this is, you can continue to keep up with activity on Bluesky from the feed reader of your choice without being required to have an account on Bluesky. 

More importantly, because RSS and OPML are open standards, you're not limited to building starter packs for Bluesky. You can create, share, and subscribe to starter packs for any platform that supports RSS. That includes blogs, podcasts, forums, YouTube, Mastodon, etc. [Manton seems to have something similar in mind](https://www.manton.org/2024/12/07/with-the-success.html) as a means of building on open standards that make it easy for Micro.blog to interop with various platforms. 

If you're interested in what that might look like in practice, check out my "starter packs" which you can subscribe to using your RSS reader of choice and the provided OPML files. 

- [Blogs](/collections/blogroll)
- [Podcasts](/collections/podroll)
- [YouTube](/collections/youtube)
- [Forums](/collections/forums)

I'm still working on similar collections for Mastodon and Bluesky but the same concept applies.  

Although these are just simple examples, it shows the importance of building on open standards and the open web. Doing so introduces more freedom for creators and communities. 

Here are other "starter packs" you might consider subscribing to. 

- [People and Blogs](https://www.thingelstad.com/2024/12/03/people-blogs-list.html)
- [Blogroll Club](https://blogroll.club/faq/)

If this is interesting to you, [Feedland](https://feedland.org/) might be a project worth checking out.  ]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-opml-starter-packs</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-opml-starter-packs</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-12-08 19:40 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>starterpacks</category>
      <category>community</category>
      <category>bluesky</category>
      <category>socialmedia</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>openstandards</category>
      <category>feedland</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement ActivityPub on a static site series by maho.dev</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;I've been following along with this amazing series from &lt;a href="https://maho.dev/"&gt;Maho&lt;/a&gt; on implementing ActivityPub on static websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I think about what I want out of my website and the way I engage in the Fediverse, there's a lot of overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, what I mainly use my Mastodon instance for is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a Fediverse presence on a self-hosted Mastodon instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps/"&gt;Cross-posting posts on by website using the POSSE pattern&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I have learned a ton from self-hosting my own Mastodon instance, neither of the points listed above require me self-hosting or even having an account on someone else's instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/using-domain-mastodon-discovery"&gt;I took the first step in linking my Fediverse presence to my domain&lt;/a&gt;. That fulfills my first requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rarely post original content on Mastodon and for consumption, &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/subscribed-to-1042-feeds-newsblur"&gt;I already subscribe to accounts and tags via RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, the second requirement is one that can naturally occur without having to use a Mastodon instance as an intermediary. I can just post on my website and because my posts can show up in my outbox, there's no need to POSSE. I don't want my presence to be limited to Mastodon though, but since I plan on supporting media, reviews, and other types of posts, I expect my posts to be accessible across other platforms on the Fediverse like Pixelfed, Bookwyrm, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my website and website features are built using .NET, Maho's guide simplifies my implementation. Because &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/colophon"&gt;I'm not using any of the existing static site generators and rolled my own&lt;/a&gt;, that means that there's going to be some effort and customizations required on my end. It would no different from my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/receive-webmentions-fsharp-az-functions-fsadvent/"&gt;custom Webmentions implementation&lt;/a&gt; though. My hope is that I will save time I often spend maintaining the server as well as money since I no longer need to rent a server to host my instance. At the same time, I get to learn and contribute to building a more open, decentralized, and personal web.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/implement-activitypub-static-site-series-maho</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/implement-activitypub-static-site-series-maho</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 10:03 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>acvititypub</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>staticsite</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>dotnet</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using my domain for discovery in Mastodon</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;For a while, I've known that I can use my domain and the WebFinger protocol to aid with discovery in the Fediverse, specifically Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried implementing this feature on my website a while back but was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I got an itch to try it again and got it working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, what I was doing wrong the first time was, I was trying to use &lt;code&gt;lqdev.me&lt;/code&gt; as the domain. Currently, my domain is not set up to use apex / naked domains. Therefore, it makes sense why that didn't work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I used &lt;code&gt;www.lqdev.me&lt;/code&gt;, everything seemed to be working fine. The implementation isn't perfect, because technically you can use any username. &lt;a href="https://www.hanselman.com/blog/use-your-own-user-domain-for-mastodon-discoverability-with-the-webfinger-protocol-without-hosting-a-server"&gt;Scott Hanselman does a nice job explaining that&lt;/a&gt;. The important part though is that &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/now-on-bluesky"&gt;my persence on the Fediverse is now directly linked to my domain, just like it is with Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;. This goes beyond the link verification Mastodon provides. As a result, it provides more flexibility and opportunities to shape my presence on the Fediverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in implementing it for yourself, there's a ton of guides, but here's the one I used: &lt;a href="https://guide.toot.as/guide/use-your-own-domain/"&gt;Use your own user @ domain for Mastodon discoverability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't like the &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain. So far I've put up with it for a while but this might be the forcing function to finally getting the apex domain setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you can search my account in Mastodon using &lt;code&gt;@lqdev@www.lqdev.me&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/using-domain-mastodon-discovery</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/using-domain-mastodon-discovery</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-11-19 09:35 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>cdn</category>
      <category>internet</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You should be using an RSS reader</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reply] &lt;p&gt;Yes, you should!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the conduit through which I experience Molly's excellent work is totally enshittification-proof, and the more I use it, the easier it is for everyone to be less enshittified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
This conduit is anti-lock-in, it works for nearly the whole internet. It is surveillance-resistant, far more accessible than the web or any mobile app interface. It is my secret super-power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
It's RSS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
...But RSS isn't just good for the news! It's good for everything.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Your RSS reader doesn't (necessarily) have an algorithm. By default, you'll get everything as it appears, in reverse-chronological order.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Now, you sign up to so many feeds that you're feeling overwhelmed and you want an algorithm to prioritize posts – or recommend content. Lots of RSS readers have some kind of algorithm and recommendation system...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
But you control the algorithm, you control the recommendations. And if a new RSS reader pops up with an algorithm you're dying to try, you can export all the feeds you follow with a single click, which will generate an OPML file. Then, with one click, you can import that OPML file into any other RSS reader in existence and all your feeds will be seamlessly migrated there. You can delete your old account, or you can even use different readers for different purposes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
RSS basically works like social media should work. Using RSS is a chance to visit a utopian future in which the platforms have no power, and all power is vested in publishers, who get to decide what to publish, and in readers, who have total control over what they read and how, without leaking any personal information through the simple act of reading.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
And here's the best part: every time you use RSS, you bring that world closer into being!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Unlike those largely useless, performative boycotts of widely used platforms, switching to RSS doesn't require that you give anything up. Not only does switching to RSS let you continue to follow all the newsletters, webpages and social media accounts you're following now, it makes doing so better: more private, more accessible, and less enshittified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Using RSS to follow the stuff that matters to you will have an immediate, profoundly beneficial impact on your own digital life – and it will appreciably, irreversibly nudge the whole internet towards a better state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great article by &lt;a href="https://craphound.com/bio/"&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written at length on my website as to &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rediscovering-rss-user-freedom"&gt;why I enjoy RSS&lt;/a&gt;. My use goes back to the days of Google Reader. Like many, once that was disbanded, my consumption pretty much shifted to social media for a few years. After growing dissatisfaction with the limitations and lack of control over my feed, I started my journey back to RSS readers eventually landing on &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/subscribed-to-1042-feeds-newsblur"&gt;NewsBlur&lt;/a&gt; and elfeed as my readers of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this website, RSS plays an important role in a few areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS is how I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/website-feeds-opml/"&gt;Enable discovery of my own feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/feed"&gt;Enable visitors to subscribe and get the latest content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/posts/rss-to-mastodon-posse-azure-logic-apps"&gt;Syndicate posts to Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented/"&gt;Enable feed discovery of websites I subscribe to&lt;/a&gt; through my:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;Blogroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;Podroll (podcasts)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/youtube/"&gt;YouTubeRoll?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/forums/"&gt;ForumRoll?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can you get started?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;a href="https://aboutfeeds.com/"&gt;about feeds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the many &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/we-love-rss"&gt;getting started guides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse through &lt;a href="https://blogroll.club/"&gt;blogrolls and feed catalogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24036427/rss-feed-reader-best"&gt;Explore various feed readers&lt;/a&gt; to find the one that works best for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/you-should-be-using-rss-reader-pluralistic</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/you-should-be-using-rss-reader-pluralistic</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-10-18 08:54 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>pluralistic</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>protocols</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>freeweb</category>
      <category>internet</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just added Fediverse Open Graph meta tag to my website</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I learned from &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/highlighting-blogging-on-mastodon"&gt;Matthias Ott&lt;/a&gt; that Mastodon created a new Open Graph meta tag which displays a direct link to the website owner's Fediverse (Mastodon, Pixelfed, Threads, etc...) profile as part of the URL preview card on the Mastodon web and mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just added support for it on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was add the following tag to my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;meta property=&amp;quot;fediverse:creator&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;@lqdev@toot.lqdev.tech&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not running the nightly version of Mastodon on my instance, but if anyone on an instance where this is already supported like mastodon.social can verify and let me know it's working, it's much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/added-fediverse-og-creator-tag</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-07-02 21:41 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mastodon</category>
      <category>fediverse</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>blogs</category>
      <category>news</category>
      <category>journalism</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>distributedweb</category>
      <category>smallweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
      <category>opengraph</category>
      <category>html</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Years of WordPress</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 years since Mike and I did the first release of WordPress, forking Michel’s work on b2/cafélog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about elements that made WordPress successful in its early years that we should keep in mind as we build this year and beyond. Here’s 11 opinions:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple things should be easy and intuitive, and complex things possible.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikis are amazing, and our documentation should be wiki-easy to edit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s important that we all do support, go to meetups and events, anything we can to stay close to regular end-users of what we make.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats to WordPress and the team on 21 years. I think the following are some good elements to keep building on.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/21-years-of-wordpress</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/21-years-of-wordpress</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-27 21:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>wordpress</category>
      <category>blogging</category>
      <category>web</category>
      <category>anniversary</category>
      <category>opensource</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll discovery enabled</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Just enabled discovery for my &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/blogroll/"&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt; based on the &lt;a href="https://opml.org/blogroll.opml"&gt;OPML blogroll spec&lt;/a&gt;. While technically not part of the spec, I also have similar collections for &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/podroll/"&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.lqdev.me/collections/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. I've added those as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!--...--&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;blogroll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Blogroll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/blogroll//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;youtuberoll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's YouTube Roll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/youtube//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;podroll&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/xml&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Luis Quintanilla's Podroll&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;/collections/podroll//index.opml&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!--...--&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;youtuberoll doesn't really roll off the tongue, but I'm hesitant to call it videoroll or vidroll. My concerns mainly come from the fact that YouTube != video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/notes/blogroll-discovery-implemented</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-05-25 22:44 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>blogroll</category>
      <category>opml</category>
      <category>rss</category>
      <category>indieweb</category>
      <category>openweb</category>
      <category>socialweb</category>
      <category>personalweb</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>