<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - mojo</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/mojo</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'mojo' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-06-11 21:20 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive into Ownership in Mojo</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the ownership series in Mojo, we built on the mental model developed in the &lt;a href="http://www.modular.com/blog/what-ownership-is-really-about-a-mental-model-approach"&gt;first part&lt;/a&gt; and provided practical examples to illustrate how ownership works in Mojo. We covered the different kinds of values (BValue, LValue, and RValue) and how they propagate through expressions. We also explained the function argument conventions (borrowed, inout, owned) and demonstrated how these conventions help manage memory safely and efficiently. We concluded with three fundamental rules:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Owned arguments take RValue on the caller side but are LValue on the callee side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Owned arguments own the type if the transfer operator ^ is used; otherwise, they copy the type if it is Copyable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Copy operations are optimized to move operations if the type is Copyable and Movable and isn’t used anymore, reducing unnecessary overhead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Lastly, we emphasized that the main goals of ownership in Mojo are:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Safety&lt;/strong&gt;: Enforcing exclusive ownership and proper lifetimes to prevent memory errors such as use-after-free and double-free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: Converting unnecessary copy operations into move operations to reduce overhead and enhance performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ease of Use&lt;/strong&gt;: Automating memory management through ownership rules and the transfer operator, simplifying development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compile-Time Guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;: Providing strong compile-time guarantees through type-checking and dataflow lifetime analysis, catching errors early in the development process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/deep-dive-ownership-mojo</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/deep-dive-ownership-mojo</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-11 21:20 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>mojo</category>
      <category>python</category>
      <category>c</category>
      <category>cpp</category>
      <category>c++</category>
      <category>pl</category>
      <category>programming</category>
      <category>programminglanguage</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>