<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Luis Quintanilla - transformer</title>
    <link>https://www.lqdev.me/tags/transformer</link>
    <description>All content tagged with 'transformer' by Luis Quintanilla</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2024-08-14 21:51 -05:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Transformer Explainer: Interactive Learning of Text-Generative Models</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[bookmark] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformers have revolutionized machine learning, yet their inner workings remain opaque to many. We present Transformer Explainer, an interactive visualization tool designed for non-experts to learn about Transformers through the GPT-2 model. Our tool helps users understand complex Transformer concepts by integrating a model overview and enabling smooth transitions across abstraction levels of mathematical operations and model structures. It runs a live GPT-2 instance locally in the user's browser, empowering users to experiment with their own input and observe in real-time how the internal components and parameters of the Transformer work together to predict the next tokens. Our tool requires no installation or special hardware, broadening the public's education access to modern generative AI techniques. Our open-sourced tool is available at this https URL. A video demo is available at this https URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://poloclub.github.io/transformer-explainer/"&gt;Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ECR4oAwocjs"&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/transformer-explainer-interactive-learning-text-generative-models</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/bookmarks/transformer-explainer-interactive-learning-text-generative-models</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-08-14 21:51 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>transformer</category>
      <category>neuralnetwork</category>
      <category>learning</category>
      <category>gpt</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrej Karpathy - Let's reproduce GPT-2 (124M)</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l8pRSuU81PU" title="YouTube thumbnail of Karpathy Let's Preproduce GPT video tutorial"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/l8pRSuU81PU/0.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="YouTube thumbnail of Karpathy Let's Preproduce GPT video tutorial" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/karpathy-reproduce-gpt-2-124m-tutorial</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/karpathy-reproduce-gpt-2-124m-tutorial</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-06-11 19:59 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>gpt</category>
      <category>transformer</category>
      <category>tutorial</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Transformer Debugger</title>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[[reshare] &lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformer Debugger (TDB) is a tool developed by OpenAI's Superalignment team with the goal of supporting investigations into specific behaviors of small language models. The tool combines automated interpretability techniques with sparse autoencoders.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
TDB enables rapid exploration before needing to write code, with the ability to intervene in the forward pass and see how it affects a particular behavior. It can be used to answer questions like, &amp;quot;Why does the model output token A instead of token B for this prompt?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Why does attention head H attend to token T for this prompt?&amp;quot; It does so by identifying specific components (neurons, attention heads, autoencoder latents) that contribute to the behavior, showing automatically generated explanations of what causes those components to activate most strongly, and tracing connections between components to help discover circuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
]]&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openai-transformer-debugger</link>
      <guid>https://www.lqdev.me/responses/openai-transformer-debugger</guid>
      <pubDate>2024-03-17 21:05 -05:00</pubDate>
      <category>openai</category>
      <category>ai</category>
      <category>transformer</category>
      <category>debugger</category>
      <category>tools</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>